<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-14T06:07:13+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saint Christopher’s Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality. Here you will find articles on Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things. Here I also talk about Buddhism and a little bit about Psychology.</subtitle><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><entry><title type="html">Becoming More Christ Like</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/becoming-more-christ-like/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming More Christ Like" /><published>2022-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Becoming-More-Christ-Like</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/becoming-more-christ-like/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/christ/christ.webp&quot; alt=&quot;christ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, with becoming more Christ it’s important to practice Meditation/Prayer and some means of service to God which you enjoy. Only with this are you able to understand yourself a little bit better and work on your flaws. Through these things you are able to incorporate more levels of Christ like emotions into you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing with Christ like emotions and giving them out to others and yourself is to recognise that you need to have good intentions with giving them to the world and have no desires in doing so. Any ill will towards the recipient will cause the Christ like emotion to not be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that you should understand is that you need to recognise what happens when there are no Christ like emotions in the world, things like fear, hatred, anger, ugliness, dirtiness, sadistic behaviors, betrayal, jealously, greed, envy, confusion, war, lust, non-acceptance, non-respect, non-understanding, etc and see what kind of world that this produces if everyone only gives way to the Anti-Christ emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are able to see what kind of world this really produces then you are able to understand a little bit better why its so important for each and everyone to become more Christ like in their ways and this only comes, I believe in understanding and appreciating what kind of world the Anti-Christ emotions bring. So, for you to really become more Christ like you need to first gain some understanding of the wrongness in the Anti-Christ emotions and this comes in doses I believe, as in to the extend that you are loving is the extend to some degree you have seen hatred, but more importantly the wrongness in hatred and the wrongness in all the other Anti-Christ emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for me, I often use the analogy of what does an ideal world look like? Does an ideal world look like groups of people fighting over one thing because they are jealous of each other? Does an ideal world look like men or women longing for each other giving way to lust? Does an ideal world look like each person giving way to greed, counting the amount of money they have in their bank account and not sharing it to others or using it for the good of others? Point here being is that an ideal world does mean having more and more people becoming more Christ like, becoming more loving, peaceful, forgiving, happy accepting of one another, respectful to one another, understanding to one another, sharing to one another, being more grateful for what they already have, rather than giving way to things such as jealousy and envy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence my general advice when seeking to become more Christ like is to look at what the opposite does and what that brings, and then seek to find solace in Christ like emotions and seek to picture what an ideal world looks like and seek to apply this to yourself, seeking to rid yourself day by day of the anti-Christ emotions because in my eyes that is what an ideal world looks like. More and more people becoming more Christ like in their ways and becoming more loving to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When seeking to rid yourself of Anti-Christ emotions such as hatred, seek to understand yourself a little better as to why you give way to hatred, perhaps its things from your past which is holding you down and dragging you down spirituality and emotionally which hasn’t yet been addressed yet, or past traumas which haven’t been resolved yet, or relationship issues which you have had in the past which didn’t work out and have left you feeling low and depressed because of it. Or perhaps is the things which you watch on TV which has you in such a negative state its difficult for more positive Christ like things such as love to come through to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, seek to resolve the issues you have had with your partner, or friends and family and seek to build stronger long-lasting relationships with them and instead of burying things under the carpet relationship wise, seek to address them by talking about them honestly and sincerely, rather than hiding it from each other the issues that you really face and burying it under things. But its also about yourself, you shouldn’t hide things from yourself and bury things under the carpet from yourself, but seek to address them as best as you can, instead of avoiding them all the time, because the consequences of avoiding past traumas and past issues that you faced and leaving them unresolved leaves a buildup of tension on your wellbeing and a buildup of tension on your spirituality and emotions and has an impact on how you treat others and yourself. But it’s important to put yourself first, and then others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Christianity" /><category term="Christ" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Dangers of AI and Machine Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-dangers-of-ai-and-machine-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dangers of AI and Machine Learning" /><published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Dangers-of-AI-and-Machine-Learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-dangers-of-ai-and-machine-learning/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I wanted to talk a little bit about the risks of AI and machine learning. This is a bit of an oddball article which I thought it was important enough to share to the world and also spirituality doesn’t just have to be about meditation/prayer etc, it can also be about computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know we use AI a lot in fridges, washing machines, smart TVs, our cars and much more. The key issue with AI is that as with a pencil it can be used to stab someone’s eye out or can be used to draw something and build something constructive. Now as a lot of you may or may not know there are secret Governments who really run the world who want us to get used to the idea of AI so that they can add AI to our makeup believe it or not, so that our thoughts and actions will no longer be under out control but influenced by the AI agenda which is to take over humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This I know may sound like science fiction, but I assure you that this is in fact true and Governments around the world are spending billions of pounds on machine learning AI which pick up people’s thought patterns and brain waves in an attempt to enslave the population so that the secret Governments around the world have absolute control over humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the issues with this are extremely drastic, 1. We could reach the singularity very quickly if the secret Governments and those working for them continue to do the evil work that they do. The singularity is if you don’t know the machines taking over the world and enslaving humanity, a bit like the terminator film. This is of course a very serious issue in our society, which should be taken very seriously, and steps should be taken by those with the wisdom and knowledge to combat this evil to ensure that we do not reach the singularity in our world. The issue is further exacerbated by the fact that the secret Governments are too arrogant and egotistical and not wise enough to make such decisions as to the technicalities of how this AI machine learning actually works and so don’t know the real issues and what is at stake here, if they continue on the path that they go down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the issue if of course perpetuated, by the fact that we have in our society an issue whereby the secret Governments are employing private contractors to code this machine learning AI and each private contractor doesn’t actually know what the other private contractors are building. Which further adds to the issue, because if they all knew what they were building they certainly wouldn’t be taking on the money in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is of course a message to the whole of humanity which I am spreading, and you can listen to these words and forget about them tomorrow, or you could take up the fight against evil and put actions into place to stop and thwart the secret Governments plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what can you the person that reads this do about the issue? Well, you can take up prayer and pray for the evil people who have this terrible plan and the various intelligence agencies involved in covering it all up because it is public money they are spending and of course its hidden away under so called “black budget” operations, so the general public is none the wiser and its only a very few who actually know of this. The technique to pray is very simply, or you need do is visualize the person/groups that you are praying for an in simple language pray that they receive Gods help and Gods power and express it via thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also start a meditation practice and after each session send out your peaceful thoughts to the world and the secret Government.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short article I wanted to talk a little bit about the risks of AI and machine learning. This is a bit of an oddball article which I thought it was important enough to share to the world and also spirituality doesn’t just have to be about meditation/prayer etc, it can also be about computers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why its Important to Save your Money</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/why-its-important-to-save-money/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why its Important to Save your Money" /><published>2022-04-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Why-its-Important-to-Save-Money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/why-its-important-to-save-money/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will be talking about why it’s so important that you save money. This isn’t really my usual article, but I thought that this subject was important enough to share with the world because I feel that in modern society, we are so consumeristic what with being bombarded with advertisements on places like the television, the internet etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that is important when saving money is to look at your spending and be conservative with how much you are spending. Do you really need Disney+, Netflix, Amazon Prime and HBO Plus? When you are not watching anything on Amazon Prime? My advice is to review all your spending and things coming out of your account and seek to look at the spending that you are able to reduce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing to realize when seeking to save money is to ensure that you have an emergency fund in your bank of say £750 for emergency funds such as an emergency dental appointment, an emergency with a car repair etc. With having a reserve £750 in your bank then it will help to ensure that you don’t go into any overdraft with your bank and ensure that you are as debt free as possible. Of course, it doesn’t have to be £750, but needs to be a reasonable amount of money compared to your monthly income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to not put all your eggs in one basket so to speak and put all your life savings into investments, you should seek to ensure that you keep some of your life savings in a bank account or a savings account, but it’s important to strike a balance between savings in savings accounts and savings in investments. You shouldn’t put too much of your money into investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also about yourself, because with saving money it will allow you to have those things in your life that you need, but don’t have such as a nice holiday and this motivates you to keep saving. It also allows you to help others by being able to give money to others who are more in need than you are, but just ensure that you don’t be greedy with money because its very easy to fall into this as I have in my life, because with greed you don’t appreciate the amount that you have and own, and so it takes away the value of the amount of money you really have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to ensure that you keep a reasonable amount of money in your bank as an emergency fund and seek to ensure that you review your spending at the start of each month so that you can reduce your spending. This in turn will offer you more freedom in your life to use your hard-earned money as and when you choose and be more selective as to which businesses you support. Also, its about being kind to yourself, its your money that you earned and you shouldn’t be spending it on things which you don’t use or receive any value from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Personal Finance" /><summary type="html">In this article I will be talking about why it’s so important that you save money. This isn’t really my usual article, but I thought that this subject was important enough to share with the world because I feel that in modern society, we are so consumeristic what with being bombarded with advertisements on places like the television, the internet etc.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understanding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding" /><published>2022-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Understanding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understanding/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk about why it’s so important for each and every one of us to become more understanding to one another. Firstly, understanding comes on a deep level in the sense that it is in part a gift of the spirit and is something which has to be given to others with good will for them. Any intent of ill will and understanding will simply not be accepted by the other person, and you just lose yourself when you are not understanding to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It relieves a heavy burden on people when they feel understood and relieves a heavy burden on yourself when you feel understood, because when you don’t feel understood it just hurts you inside and does make you feel alone in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand you first need to see the person behind the mask and see that they are just another person of this world and see their motivations and reasoning behind their actions and seek understand why they do what they do to others and the negative impact it has on themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding is a gift of the spirit and through meditation, prayer and service to God can you be more understanding to others. Hence why its so important for all who read this to seek to become more understanding and take up things such as meditation, prayer, and service to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, its about others because when others don’t feel understood by others then they feel alone in this world and feel that others judge them and look down upon them and the world should be a much better place to live on especially if we have more people who are understanding towards one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly the key thing with any and all Christ like emotions is to have no ill will towards the person when practicing any Christ like emotion, but Christ like emotions can become more developed within the individual through meditation, prayer, and service to fellow man, do feel free to look at my articles on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a last note any desire at all with giving any christ like emotion and the “magic” will not work. There has to be no desire, no intent of ill will and you should purely be doing it for the other person’s best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/compassion/&quot;&gt;Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk about why it’s so important for each and every one of us to become more understanding to one another. Firstly, understanding comes on a deep level in the sense that it is in part a gift of the spirit and is something which has to be given to others with good will for them. Any intent of ill will and understanding will simply not be accepted by the other person, and you just lose yourself when you are not understanding to others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First Aggregate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-first-aggregate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First Aggregate" /><published>2022-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-First-Aggregate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-first-aggregate/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate of the five aggregates in Buddhism. If you don’t know the Buddha taught that there is no self and that what you view as yourself just isn’t so and is in reality an illusion. I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate which is physical body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need fully appreciate before understanding any of the five aggregates is that you need to link the idea of self to control, this took me a lot of contemplation and it will take others some thought/meditation to be able to make this connection because its not an easy connection to make. Ask yourself what qualities would you expect “self” to actually have? Spend some time in contemplation over this question and it will help you understand a little that the idea of self is heavily linked to the idea of control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the physical body isn’t something which you can bend to your will. For example, you are not actually able to control how you look, the color of your eyes etc. Granted you can control how you look through things such as cosmetics, but this is only temporary. If body were self, then you would be able to control it at will. But like I said its important to first see the connection between control and self before you are able to understand why each of the 5 aggregates are not “self”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, its important to not identify with your physical form because you are not your physical form because you are not able to control your physical form completely, granted you can control it to some extend with cosmetics, but that isn’t full control. Therefore, its important to not identify with any body part because ultimately you are not able to control your physical form and bend it to your will and so therefore isn’t self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I am very new to Buddhism so take what I say with a pinch of salt and there are other resources listed below which may help you understand Buddhism a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buddhism Plain and Simple by Steve Hagen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963/ref=sr_1_5?crid=34M92RA2NH4SR&amp;amp;keywords=buddhism&amp;amp;qid=1649083246&amp;amp;sprefix=buddhism%2Caps%2C79&amp;amp;sr=8-5&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963/ref=sr_1_5?crid=34M92RA2NH4SR&amp;amp;keywords=buddhism&amp;amp;qid=1649083246&amp;amp;sprefix=buddhism%2Caps%2C79&amp;amp;sr=8-5&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unhindered: A mindful path through the Five Hindrances by Gill Fronsdal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unhindered-Mindful-Path-Through-Hindrances/dp/0989833402/ref=sr_1_1?crid=NPAIHMT6E263&amp;amp;keywords=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances&amp;amp;qid=1649084275&amp;amp;sprefix=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances%2Caps%2C55&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unhindered-Mindful-Path-Through-Hindrances/dp/0989833402/ref=sr_1_1?crid=NPAIHMT6E263&amp;amp;keywords=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances&amp;amp;qid=1649084275&amp;amp;sprefix=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances%2Caps%2C55&amp;amp;sr=8-1&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/index.html&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/books-articles/the-five-hindrances-handouts/&quot;&gt;https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/books-articles/the-five-hindrances-handouts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html">In this short article I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate of the five aggregates in Buddhism. If you don’t know the Buddha taught that there is no self and that what you view as yourself just isn’t so and is in reality an illusion. I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate which is physical body.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Golden Rule</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-golden-rule/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Golden Rule" /><published>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Golden-Rule</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-golden-rule/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/golden/golden.png&quot; alt=&quot;anger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk about the golden rule, which is a principal that all who follow the path of spirituality and freedom should adhere to as best as they can. The golden rule as set out by Jesus was that you should treat others how you yourself would like to be treated. In an ideal world people would be loving, kind, generous, peaceful etc. and so following the golden rule is really important in doing that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world people would be more respectful to one another and this can and only begins by you and your actions. Nobody can force you to follow the golden rule, its down to the individual to follow and adhere to this fundamental spiritual law in their lives and apply it to themselves daily and to follow it each time they meet and greet someone and each time they talk with someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I take the principal of what would an ideal world look like? Would an ideal world look like people filled with jealousy, lust, envy, greed, negativity? Or would an ideal world be filled with loving, kind, generous, peaceful people with objects of beauty? I wager it’s the latter. Therefore, it’s very important to all who are on the spiritual path to follow the golden rule and apply to themselves each and every time they talk with someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the golden rule is something that all should follow and adhere to in their lives because it will make the world a much, much brighter and better place if there were more people who were loving, kind, generous, understanding, forgiving, compassionate, caring to one another, it would also bring Gods kingdom upon earth because God is a God of love and he loves each and every one of us individually even the most abject sinners in the world because we are his children and no matter what we do we will always be his children.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Devotion to God</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/devotion-to-god/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Devotion to God" /><published>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Devotion-to-God</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/devotion-to-god/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/god/god.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;God&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this image as a representation of God, but I am sorry if I offend anyone here, but God is not a man - he is a force and his power is granted through sincere meditation, prayer and service to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will write why it’s so important for people who are on the spiritual path or choose to be on the spiritual path to put more efforts into devoting themselves to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devotion to God can come in the form of sincere Meditation, Prayer, and Service to him and these are key things in making progress towards God. You can refer to my articles on these topics and I will soon write an article on why it’s important to give your service to God and no the gifts of the spirit do not come in a matter of meditating for a few weeks, they take years to be able to be granted by God and doing so for egotistical and doubtful ends will cause God to not grant them simple as, so those of you who do read my blog just know that you are wasting your time in mediating for these egotistical and doubtful end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence the key things which are important in making progress in spirituality is devoting yourself to God and this comes in the form of Meditation, Prayer, and Service to him (through sincerely helping others) and following the wise words of the ten commandments and meditating on them and putting efforts into understanding their meanings through contemplation, experience, journaling, and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But its just not these things, because you can still perform these things and not have it in your heart devotion towards God, because in Buddhism the last hindrance is doubt and this is only dealt with in time, and I am yet to actually deal with this hindrance and it I am told only comes with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincere devotion to God in my eyes is what really matters a lot in meditating, prayer and service to him and it goes against one of the ten commandments of thou shall not serve any other God before me because in not being devoted to your one true God, who I might add is an all loving God, then you are simply fooling yourself and hurting yourself and others in doing so and simply trying to meet your own doubtful ends and taking things into your own hands when in fact it is God who has absolute control over every single thing which happens in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God is not impressed when he sees people trying to steal from other people’s lives, with things like jealousy, lust, greed, hate, anger and he is not impressed with people promoting things on social media such as hate, violence, negativity, division etc. God is impressed with sincerity of purpose, people who help one another, people who put efforts into progressing towards him through things like meditation, prayer, and service to others because God is all loving to each and every one of us as individuals and God’s love for each and every one of us is unconditional even the most abject sinners in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also allows his subjects to make their own mistakes in life and allows them to embark on their spiritual journey at their own pace and in their own time. I as this blog indicates shows that I am only human and what I am capable of all of mankind is capable of. I do however recommend that those on the spiritual path start their own blog as I have done and share to the world their personal experiences in growing spiritually and take to things such as forums to share those experiences and disucss them with one another. But just be warned that we all have our own journey ahead of us and we all walk the path alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/compassion/&quot;&gt;Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When You See Wrong do Two Goods Elsewhere</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/when-you-see-wrong-do-two-goods-elsewhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When You See Wrong do Two Goods Elsewhere" /><published>2022-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/When-You-See-Wrong-Do-Two-Goods-Elsewhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/when-you-see-wrong-do-two-goods-elsewhere/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/charity/charity.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Charity&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write about why it’s so important for people to do two goods in the world or elsewhere for that matter when they see bad or wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world would be a much brighter place and we the public would be much happier the people in charge did follow this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really about bringing God’s kingdom upon earth because earth should be a place which is God’s kingdom and not the kingdom of chaos, destruction, corruption, liars, manipulators, thieves, hateful, hurtful people because that’s not what God’s kingdom should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God’s kingdom should be a place of love, compassion, kindness, peace, order, beauty, joy, forgiveness, generosity, righteousness, holiness, gratitude and people who are faithful servants to him. This I think is a really good principal to follow in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of seeing wrongdoing may be when someone lies to you, when someone deceives you, when someone hurts you, when someone makes you think you are confused when you are not. You shouldn’t take revenge on these people because they do not know where they go, you should follow Jesus’s teachings of turning the other cheek when it comes to people that do wrong onto you and seek to follow this basic principle that I have laid out here in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of good that you can do in the world is donating to charities, giving to others (and you can refer to my article on this topic), serving God through your job, helping others in some way through things like Forums etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this principal shouldn’t be taken to an extreme, but just taken in balance and go by what you feel is right while being true to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-forgiveness/&quot;&gt;Self Forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/virtue-signalling/&quot;&gt;Virtue Signaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Pray for your Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="God" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forgiveness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/forgiveness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forgiveness" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Forgiveness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/forgiveness/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/2020-12-17-Self-Forgiveness/yellow-flower.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;think&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will be talking about forgiveness and forgiving someone that does wrong by you. First and foremost, forgiveness is a process and forgiveness brings a lot of atonement to your soul and helps to raise you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let me just say that you shouldn’t keep forgiving someone when they keep constantly sinning against you and these kinds of people do not deserve forgiveness because they still believe in their hearts it’s the right thing to do and don’t show any level of respect for you and if you forgive them when they keep sinning against you then it shows that you don’t respect yourself. Therefore, forgiveness can sometimes begin by choosing not to forgive those who still believe in their hearts that sinning against you and God is the correct thing to do. There is a lot of power that forgiveness can bring to people and your enemies for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why you should forgive your enemies or strive to is because they don’t know which way they go, they are being lead astray, forgiveness also comes from recognizing that your enemies and sometimes your friends even don’t really know the deeper realities and the difficulties that you have faced in your life. Only God knows the absolute realities into all and so its important to show forgiveness to people whom you know better than when they sin because we are all equal and when you forgive another for their sin, you are able to be a true servant of God because the world should be filled with people who are more forgiving, loving, kind and generous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, forgiveness should be a show of strength because it takes some courage when someone has sinned a great deal in their life to be able to show that person forgiveness in what they do because you should recognize that we are all equal and even the most abject sinner in the world and the people who are truly evil in the world you are also capable of. Equally the great masters of the world such as Buddha, Jesus, Muhammad you believe it or not are capable of the same acts of those great masters. Hence why its important to be forgiving to those who sin when you realize that they sin because as Jesus once said, “Father forgive them for they do not know what they do”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to forgive your greatest enemy and seek to understand why it is that they commit the sins that they commit and just recognize that they make up part of life as do you and seek to realize that the most evil people and evil groups in the world do and the great sins that they commit you also are capable of committing because we are all equal. Equally what Jesus was capable of with the various miracles that he did perform and is performing to this very day you are also capable of doing, because don’t believe for one second that Jesus doesn’t care for earth and is in heaven and is helping mankind on earth and sending his love to us each day. Its within you and only you are able to change yourself and become the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Concentration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-concentration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Concentration" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Concentration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-concentration/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/eightfold-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eightfoldpath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will be talking about Right Concentration. Which is one element of the eightfold path and one which I think if mastered will be very beneficial to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part in understanding right concentration or any element of the eightfold path is to understand why this makes us suffer. You first need to understand why not having Right Concentration at the right times and at the appropriate settings leads to suffering. To me Right means the correct level of concentration at the right times and when appropriate. But the key thing with all the elements of the eightfold path is to realize and appreciate why not having them leads to suffering, which I think is key in understanding and following Buddhism and the philosophy behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right concentration is heavily linked to right mindfulness because with right mindfulness you are able to appreciate as and when you are not concentrating on the task at hand and when you drift off so to speak. But like I said you need to understand why not having any one of the elements of the eightfold path actually leads to suffering, before you are able to fully appreciate why it is that not having that element actually leads to suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to meditate on why not having an element of the eightfold path leads you to suffering and spend some time in contemplation why it is that not having right concentration actually leads one to suffering, because it will help you and others immensely when you are able to focus on the task at hand and help you to reduce the suffering that you have. Seek to journal (a means of contemplation) why it is that not having right concentration leads to suffering, I also have an article on this blog why its important that people take up jouranling as a means of spiritual devotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I am very new to Buddhism so take what I say with a pinch of salt and there are other resources listed below which may help you understand Buddhism a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buddhism Plain and Simple by Steve Hagen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963/ref=sr_1_5?crid=34M92RA2NH4SR&amp;amp;keywords=buddhism&amp;amp;qid=1649083246&amp;amp;sprefix=buddhism%2Caps%2C79&amp;amp;sr=8-5&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963/ref=sr_1_5?crid=34M92RA2NH4SR&amp;amp;keywords=buddhism&amp;amp;qid=1649083246&amp;amp;sprefix=buddhism%2Caps%2C79&amp;amp;sr=8-5&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unhindered: A mindful path through the Five Hindrances by Gill Fronsdal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unhindered-Mindful-Path-Through-Hindrances/dp/0989833402/ref=sr_1_1?crid=NPAIHMT6E263&amp;amp;keywords=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances&amp;amp;qid=1649084275&amp;amp;sprefix=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances%2Caps%2C55&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unhindered-Mindful-Path-Through-Hindrances/dp/0989833402/ref=sr_1_1?crid=NPAIHMT6E263&amp;amp;keywords=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances&amp;amp;qid=1649084275&amp;amp;sprefix=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances%2Caps%2C55&amp;amp;sr=8-1&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/index.html&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/books-articles/the-five-hindrances-handouts/&quot;&gt;https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/books-articles/the-five-hindrances-handouts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-mindfulness/&quot;&gt;Right Mindfulness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/sloth-and-torpor/&quot;&gt;Sloth and Torpor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/journaling/&quot;&gt;Journaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><category term="Right Concentration" /><category term="Noble EightFoldPath" /><category term="Noble Four Truths" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>