<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-27T08:39:14+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saint Christopher’s Blog</title><subtitle>Articles on Spirituality, Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things.</subtitle><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><entry><title type="html">Control Dramas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/control-dramas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Control Dramas" /><published>2022-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Control-Dramas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/control-dramas/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/control.png&quot; alt=&quot;Control&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I wanted to discuss a little about this book that I read while I was in University called Celestine Prophecy which was in my article I had on my blog “Books that Changed my Life”. I read it first in 2019 and its been over 3 years since I have read that book. But I wanted to highlight something in the book which I see a lot of truth in, which is the four control dramas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four control dramas are according to the book: Intimidator, Interrogator, aloof and poor me, in that order. Now they rank from aggressive to most aggressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intimidator steals people’s energy by as the name suggests intimidating people, and attempting to gain control over them through fear, interrogator which is the most popular one which I fall victim to by others (because I believe that with me the poor me is the one which is prominent with me), aloof is generally always vague and takes energy because others always need to ask for ore clarity on things and then poor me always try to make others feel guilty by pretending to have no control (generally poor me is caused when you can’t control suffering somehow or feel that you can’t control suffering or that you feel that your needs can’t be met)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution for them is to bring awareness of them because as the book points out they exist to covertly manipulate people to steal their energy more or less. This works for both if you use any of them and if anyone is using them against you. To bring them to awareness in conversation takes some courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I wanted to share how I generally always fall into poor me, its because I feel that I wasn’t about to control my own suffering having self-mutilated myself because of an unhealed trauma in my life which I still am not able to fully recount. But the point is that the self-mutilation I felt wasn’t in my control and this is why I am in so much grief, or that I felt that it wasn’t in my control. But I should look at what came from it, I have become a lot holier in my ways because of this experience and I do pray for less suffering in the world and pray for peace, but I strongly advise all to never self-mutilate. Its very much against my beliefs and I will never do it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this article is moreso about how I always fall into the poor me control drama and give into interrogators all the time, but this blog is moreso meant to be a writing place for my personal growth in spirituality and I hope that others can learn from it and grow from it also. The reason I always give way to interrogators is because of some kind of mind control I was subject to when I was young, and the reason I give way to poor me is because I feel my needs are not being meant and feel that I have little control over my needs being met, but this just isn’t the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do apologize to all who read this article for not sharing this truth to you, because I felt that I was saving myself suffering in not sharing it, but really it was just unkind. But I am moreso writing this article for myself because that is what true spirituality is about and others either read it or they don’t and learn from it or don’t. Its up to the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend to all that you give the book a read because it is a good book on spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Becoming Myself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/becoming-myself/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming Myself" /><published>2022-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Becoming-Myself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/becoming-myself/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Becoming-myself/swan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Compassion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this short piece to say here that I realized why I was so “Lost at sea” for so long. Its not because I was lost, its because I found a truth and, in a sense, I denied it and buried it for so long that I forgot the truth and just learned to continue to bury it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is personal to me and there is no use in trying to describe it here. But I am in grief because of this realization that I buried this truth and spent so, so very long trying to be someone else and trying to always be someone else, denying this basic truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It saddens me to see myself in grief and I’m sure it does others, but I held on for something for so long, buried it and buried a basic truth that I simply forgot this basic truth and just learned to bury the truth under more things and I in a sense learned to always change who I was, never quite accepting who I was at any given instance and always thinking that others didn’t accept me for who I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am in grief upon discovering this and realizing this truth of a sorts, which is related to when I was a teenager and went through a spiritual awakening at the time…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess its because I wanted something else and wanted something more… But now I am in grief because of being so long denying a basic truth. But things are changing for the better with me in beginning to accept once again this basic truth and realizing all this depth to me and becoming more of who I really am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am in grief with close to 4 years of always changing who I was, but the thing is; I will always be myself and nothing will ever change who I truly am as a person. I can pretend to be someone else and, in a sense, lie to myself, but I will always be who I truly am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now I am going through an identity crisis with who I am, but I guess that is something for me to work through while in hospital. Needless to say, I am the same person of who I am, just a slightly more developed and wiser person with all the attempts at changing who I was because of others…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I need learn forgive myself now and learn to accept who I really am as a person. Which is something for me to work through…  and allow myself to grieve.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Real Spirituality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/real-spirtuality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Real Spirituality" /><published>2022-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Real-Spirtuality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/real-spirtuality/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I wanted to spend some time discussing what so called real spirituality is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To first understand what real spirituality is, you first need to understand that we all go on our own journeys. Each journey is different and each journey all has the same end. But the journey is unique to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real spirituality isn’t about others, as selfish as this may sound it is about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means is that its about working on yourself and becoming the bestest version of yourself and it doesn’t mean that you ignore others, far from it, because when you work on yourself, you thereby set an example, but also in working on yourself it allows you to help others that much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also just want to say that fake spirituality need be defined here and I do have an article on this which may clarify this point. But essentially fake spirituality is whereby you are just not being true to yourself and are just a phonie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for their to be fake spirituality, you first need to see what real spirituality looks like and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to work on yourself and when you are ready you help others whom you are able to help. My mantra generally these days is I intend to help others by helping myself and this helps me when I am feeling down, but the no.1 person you should be trying to impress with anything is yourself… Not your friends, your neighbours or your family, but yourself, although it isn’t wrong to want to impress others….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am able to I will post this article as I wrote it on my phone 15/07/22 and will get around to posting it, but due to unforeseen circumstances I am in hospital and so not able to post it right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in conclusion, seek to better yourself, but don’t push yourself to the limit, we all have our own limits, even me. Learn to take spirituality in strides and just be patient. I learned that persistence is key to growth. I respect the man who is spends 10 minutes learning a skill a day for a year than the man who spends 3 months learning that skill, because it shows his determination to succeed - of course this is generic numbers, but I’m sure you get the idea…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore seek to meditate and pray as consistently in your own time as you can and seek to take breaks, as this is really my own downfall and my own curiosity does off time get in my own way a lot of the time… But seek to take breaks as and when you are able to and don’t be mean on yourself if after several years you still haven’t achieved what you set out to achieve - The value is in the journey, not in the end result…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note I’ve been doing some art and this has been helping me and colouring in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to mention that I saught depth to myself, which I do not recommend anyone do because it just leads to a mess with things in your life and I’m learning to lessen the depth to me, but I recognize it will be a struggle for a short period, and I will become better…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this article I wanted to spend some time discussing what so called real spirituality is.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prayer for Peace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/prayer-for-peace/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prayer for Peace" /><published>2022-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Prayer-For-Peace</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/prayer-for-peace/">&lt;p&gt;Prayer for Peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will discuss a little why its so important to pray for peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace is a concept that not many people quite appreciate enough, we nowadays have a lot of military factions always striving for war, but not many people appreciate what they have including myself. I personally have never been victim to war in my lifetime and is something I am very much grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also feel like, not enough people quite appreciate peace enough. Or concepts such as love for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know many people that may read this article don’t normally pray, but I think it is important to all that practice or want to practice spirituality to take up things such as prayer and meditation and have it be taking up as part of daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I advise all who read this message to only take up prayer and meditation if it is what you want to do. Don’t do so because I write it in this article, do so because you want to and want to make a difference in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Prayer for Peace.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Doing Things For Yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/doing-things-for-yourself/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doing Things For Yourself" /><published>2022-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-06-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Doing-Things-For-Yourself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/doing-things-for-yourself/">&lt;p&gt;Doing Things for yourself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about doing things for yourself and how having your best interests at heart is the most important thing that you can do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been a little down in myself because I have realized that I’ve been doing things far, far too much for the good of others at my own expense and this has been the way I have been for the past few years now and is one of the reasons I have had a rough life these past few years in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I realize now that true spirituality is about yourself. Its not about others, its not about your friends/family and your acquaintances, its about yourself. I realized that I took up meditation/prayer because I followed a certain group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My honest advice to all is to put yourself first and just be yourself, I have struggled because I have felt that others have had something more than me these past few years. This doesn’t mean that you go about doing bad deeds onto others, quite the opposite, it means that you have your best interests at heart and always put yourself first no matter what, which means doing good deeds onto others, for the rewards that you shall receive in heaven are big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gained a lot from meditation/prayer, but as in one of my articles I mentioned that its important to take breaks in spirituality as and when you feel the need to. Right now, I feel I have spent the past 4 years, mostly doing daily meditation and this is enough for anyone. So, I guess what I am trying to say is I am long overdue a long break from spirituality, which means no longer spending time in prayer/meditation and working on my flaws and personality flaws etc. Therefore, I need to rely on others more especially when taking a break from spirituality and this is something I have struggled with in the past, but something that I will learn to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Doing Things for yourself</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Change Your Inner World First</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/change-your-inner-world-first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Change Your Inner World First" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Change-Your-Inner-World-First</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/change-your-inner-world-first/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk about how you should seek to pray for your inner world and seek to change your inner world before you attempt to pray for others outside your inner world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all live in our own worlds. No person’s world is the same as another person’s, but I believe that its very important for those on the spiritual path towards God to seek to change the things in their inner world which is causing them harm before attempting to change other people’s worlds who are not in your world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic example of this is that you should seek to pray for those close to you who are causing you harm before you seek to pray for those outside your inner world who are causing others harm. In a sense this is very much the analogy of when you are on a plane and before takeoff the flight attendant says in an event of an emergency for you to put your gasmask on before you put on the gasmask of those near you. The reason for this is that you should ensure that you are in a good place and are actually fit enough to help others, before you seek to help others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very much why its important to pray for your inner world who are causing you harm in your inner world, before seeking to help those who are outside your inner world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, its also important to pray for yourself for your own benefit before seeking to pray for those in your inner world causing you harm, because again if you have a lot of issues and wounds from the past which are weighing you down mentally, emotionally, and spiritually, then you are not able to pray for others with the intention of helping them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as Jesus once said in his sermon on the mount; “Judge not, that you be not judged. 2 For with the judgment you pronounce you will be judged, and with the measure you use it will be measured to you. 3 Why do you see the speck that is in your brother’s eye, but do not notice the log that is in your own eye? 4 Or how can you say to your brother, ‘Let me take the speck out of your eye,’ when there is the log in your own eye? 5 You hypocrite, first take the log out of your own eye, and then you will see clearly to take the speck out of your brother’s eye.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What he was saying here is that you shouldn’t judge or condemn others because in doing so you in a sense set a metric that others will judge you by the same measure that you use to judge that them. But yet, you yourself are not perfect and so you shouldn’t judge others or pray for others until you yourself are able to “take the log out of your own eye”. In a sense we all have a log in our own eyes, some more than others. But its important to take up things like prayer and meditation and have it be established as part of daily routine because then will you be able to take the log out of your own eyes so to speak and also come into contact with God on a daily basis though meditation and prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bruderhof.com/en/topics/the-sermon-on-the-mount&quot;&gt;https://www.bruderhof.com/en/topics/the-sermon-on-the-mount&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christianbiblereference.org/jteach.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.christianbiblereference.org/jteach.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short article I will talk about how you should seek to pray for your inner world and seek to change your inner world before you attempt to pray for others outside your inner world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Serving Others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/serving-others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Serving Others" /><published>2022-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-05-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Serving-Others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/serving-others/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will be discussing why its so important for each and every individual to find some means of serving others whether that be through a job, volunteering in some way or donating to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that needs to be understood is that we all are all God pretending not to be, so when we serve others, we are really serving the God made manifest in man which is in that person and so thereby serving God. Also, in serving others we attract to us God’s angels, guides and helpers who are always looking out for people who serve others, meditate, and pray and will help us to help others and pull the strings so to speak so that we are better able to serve others and they will help us so long as we are sincere in our purpose of serving others and helping others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In serving God made manifest in man it also allows us to reduce the power of our personality, which can have many flaws and so can cause you to fumble. Therefore, the solution generally is to serve others while also when identifying a personality flaw to send out a prayer for that flaw to be rectified, so that the personality flaw is snuffed out and that you can progress that much further towards God and progress in spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also important to find work meaningful to you and spend some time considering the best way in which you can serve your fellow man. Something like the army may not be the most peaceful means of service, but if it is something which you are drawn to then you shouldn’t deny this experience for yourself because you gain experience in any work that you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I encourage all who read this article to take up some means of volunteering, this could be going to your local supermarket and donating to the food bank there, it could be donating your books/clothes to a local charity shop, it could be helping your family move their furniture around the house etc. I also strongly encourage all to help others on social media who are feeling down and lonely. There are a few subreddits which you can seek to help others in such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/mentalhealth/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/mentalhealth/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/depression/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/depression/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/SuicideWatch/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/SuicideWatch/&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which are filled with people looking for help from others who clearly don’t have it as good as the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend that you donate to a charity because if you read my article on giving to others you would know that when you give to others in some way a call is sent out to return whatever it is you gave, so when you give money away so long as you have adequate faith that God will return to you your money – he will. However, its not as simple as that because you need to get that money back somehow so it may take some time for all that money to be fully returned to you, but this doesn’t mean spend all your money on charity. It simply means that the money which you give will be returned to you eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this article I will be discussing why its so important for each and every individual to find some means of serving others whether that be through a job, volunteering in some way or donating to others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Healing Past Wounds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/healing-past-wounds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Healing Past Wounds" /><published>2022-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Healing-Past-Wounds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/healing-past-wounds/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about how you can heal from your past wounds and traumas that an incarnation on earth bears you with. The first thing you need to appreciate when seeking to heal past wounds and traumas is that you should become more like a child, which is you should seek to lessen your own ego, arrogance, pride, selfishness, and things that are likely to deter you from really healing your past wounds and traumas. I do have an article on this here on this blog if you would like to read that then do feel free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The few things that you can do and that I personally recommend to all who are really devoted to spirituality is to take up meditation, prayer and perform some kind of service to your fellow man that you find meaningful in some way. Feel free to check out my articles on these topics which you can find on this blog by using the search function or looking for the posts in the posts page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one healing power that each and everyone has at their disposal is love. Love conquers and heals all wounds from the past and is the most powerful force in the galaxy. Therefore, seek to cultivate more love into your life through things such as mediating on love and then after you meditate on love sending those loving thoughts out to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which you can do is to seek to lessen things such as toxic masculinity which I find so many men in modern times giving way to, which is unfortunate because modern times in places such as schools and work life etc do not give an accurate portrayal of what a man should and shouldn’t be and men are taught that they can’t be vulnerable and appear weak to others, which has a detrimental impact on them psychologically speaking. This also applies to toxic femininity, but its not my place to comment on this what with being a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which brings great healing to your soul and your life is to not bottle your emotions and other things up but to express your emotions openly, honestly, and sincerely to others because when you bottle things up it has detrimental impacts on your spiritual, emotional, and mental wellbeing. Therefore, if someone does wrong by you seek to address this rather than holding grudges against them and allowing yourself to feel hatred, jealousy, envy and other negative emotions towards them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, another thing that you could do is to cut out negative influences in your life – this could be negative people in your life which bring you down, this could also be social media which has a lot of negative people on their trolling others, this could also be negative family members who don’t have your best interests at heart, this could be the content that you consume such as The News which I find only serve really negative articles and don’t show much of the good done in our society and so portrays a wrapped reality whereby they only show you articles/segments that is likely to bring you into a low vibrational state of negativity and low mood. Feel free to give my articles on these a read also. Also you should seek to make up with your family members and seek to build good relationships with them because they are your family and you only have one family on this earth, so seek to forgive your family for past hurts and past wounds they may or may not have inflicted upon you and seek to resolve the issues that you have had in the past with them, rather than allowing those wounds and traumas to remain festering in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also seek therapy or counseling of some sort if your wellbeing really isn’t that great because these have helped myself and many others in their life and just having an honest, open and compassionate ear to listen to you does wonders for you mentally and emotionally. But you should appreciate that nobody is alone and that there is no shame at all for seeking therapy or counseling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which you can seek to do to heal your past wounds and past traumas is to be more compassionate towards yourself. I recommend to all that as a basic technique of self-compassion that they can do is write on paper – the many ways that they can or are mean to themselves, then on another sperate bit of paper write down the ways that you can be more caring, understanding, compassionate towards yourself. This is a simple technique but has done me any many others wonders. You can also give my articles on compassion a read – I have one on self-compassion and compassion. Also, a key thing which giving yourself compassion is to be mindful, that is learning to discern your thoughts, feelings and emotions and mental activity and recognizing the ways that you can and are mean to yourself. But you should also when you do this basic technique, I outlined here is to see yourself just as another person of this world and recognize that you make up life just as much as the next person and so you should seek to be your own best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly some of the other ways in which you can seek to heal yourself of past wounds and past traumas is to do activities which you find meaningful and heal you in some way. This could be doing art, such as painting, drawing, or coloring in. It could also be meeting with your friends and doing some activity with them such as bowling, going for a meal, going to the cinema, and watching a film. It could also be listening to or creating music, which can be really healing to a lot of people. When listening to music I cannot recommend music which is loving in nature because that positive love energy will affect you and bring healing to yourself in your life. Some other things that you could do which are just some suggestions are read a book, watch a movie, watch fun YouTube videos, talk to your friends and family about how you really feel inside instead of burying how you actually feel inside yourself. Point being is that you should seek to do some kind of activity that you enjoy doing and that brings great healing to yourself and your past wounds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spirituality" /><summary type="html">In this article I will talk a little bit about how you can heal from your past wounds and traumas that an incarnation on earth bears you with. The first thing you need to appreciate when seeking to heal past wounds and traumas is that you should become more like a child, which is you should seek to lessen your own ego, arrogance, pride, selfishness, and things that are likely to deter you from really healing your past wounds and traumas. I do have an article on this here on this blog if you would like to read that then do feel free.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linking With the God Spirit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linking-with-the-god-spirit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linking With the God Spirit" /><published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Linking-With-The-God-Spirit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linking-with-the-god-spirit/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about linking with the I AM as Jesus described it or the God spirit within us all. Now this God spirit can be linked with by anyone – but generally most people in the world have what is known as the ID which is the person that looks back at us in the mirror – the ID and is a fairly basic part of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for those who with spirituality developed are able to make a connection to their God spirit and the information coming from them would be very wise indeed and they would be complete in that the information coming from their mind is information which the God spirit is sending through to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way that I was able to link with my God spirit at a young age (late teenage years) was by being a lot more present and I was as I described being self-aware of being self-aware of being self-aware infinity and it felt really amazing – I was a lot more happier than I had been in my life and was receiving cosmic wisdom and still am to this very day, one basic example was that I realized that “happiness comes from within”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can link with the God spirit by living more in the present moment, which is a valid way to do so, but you can also link to it through years of meditation/prayer/service to others. I guess the thing that really made me realize why living in the now was so important was because I realized at the time through all my philosophical thinking that you are not able to control your actions/thoughts in the past, or the future. You are only able to control your thoughts/actions right here in the now moment or the present moment as I referred to it as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my ability to enter the present moment has been severely cut off due to a severe trauma that I had gone through in my life, and so thereby my ability to make a link with my God spirit has been weakened. But to some degree this has made me the person that I am to this very day, and I do have split personality disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my advice to all who read this article, is to practice meditation, prayer and service to others and then and only then are you able to link with your God spirit and the information coming through to you would be wise and you would be a lot more spiritual and be able to one day perform similar if not the same miracles as people such as Jesus and other various people who have existed across time, and you will be blessed for eternity in performing miracles for the good of others and proving to others that Gods power which is indeed infinite is real and is a reality. I also just want to add that the idea that Jesus has to be involved with miracles is a fabrication - Jesus was a special person, but that is only because he spend many years in heaven receiving training so that when he came to earth he was ready to help mankind in their long journey, so when people say that Jesus needs to be involved when a miracle is performed - its a lie because Jesus is human and what one human is capable of - all are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this article I will talk a little bit about linking with the I AM as Jesus described it or the God spirit within us all. Now this God spirit can be linked with by anyone – but generally most people in the world have what is known as the ID which is the person that looks back at us in the mirror – the ID and is a fairly basic part of us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ten Commandments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-ten-commandments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ten Commandments" /><published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Ten-Commandments</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-ten-commandments/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/ten/ten.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ten&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this short piece on the ten commandments, which if adhered to and really understood are enough to carry you into the arms of God. If you don’t know the ten commandments are “you shall have no other Gods before me”, “you shall not make for yourself an idol”, “you shall not take the name of God in vain”, “Remember the sabbath day to keep it holy”, “honor your father and mother”, “you shall not kill”, “you shall not commit adultery”, “you shall not steal”, “you shall not lie”, “you shall not covet” (yearn to possess something).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that needs to be understood with the ten commandments I believe are that people often take the ten commandments literally, for example thou shall not steal, often people interpret it as meaning you shouldn’t take others personal items for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, when adhering to the ten commandments, seek to really meditate and spend some time understanding each of them and their implications and how to apply them into your life. I also recommend to all that they recite the 10 commandments by hand and do lines with them and put efforts to contemplate in which ways they break the 10 commandments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I don’t want to give too many of my own interpretations regarding the ten commandments because it takes away from your own interpretations and really my points are just suggestions in how you may interpret the ten commandments. With each of the ten commandments really try to understand each of them and look for the implications in them, seek to meditate and start a journal to help to understand yourself better and understand how it is you break some of the 10 commandments. We are all far from perfect and as such it is bound that in our lives, we break the ten commandments somehow because if we were able to apply each of the ten commandments to our lives, we would be at Gods side already. But we are all far from perfect on earth and even the great masters such as Buddha, Jesus, Moses etc were not perfect. We each have a long journey ahead of us and its important to keep up our strength in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1 01/07/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend to all that you spend time in meditation and contemplation on how you break any of the 10 commandments, because we all sin because none of us are perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also strongly recommend that you recite by hand the ten commandments and do lines on the ten commandments and focus on how you break them in your life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher&apos;s Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>