<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-11T04:37:40+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saint Christopher’s Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality. Here you will find articles on Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things. Here I also talk about Buddhism and a little bit about Psychology.</subtitle><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><entry><title type="html">Being Authentic and True to Yourself</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Being Authentic and True to Yourself" /><published>2022-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Being-Authentic-and-True-to-Yourself</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk a little about why it’s so important to be authentic and true to yourself and do what is right in your heart and not the hearts of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you don’t do right in terms of what is right in your heart you lose yourself and who you truly are and give way to others reasoning which may be faulty because others have their own lives and their own flaws, and you should appreciate that sometimes you know more than others and so should make your own judgements on when and when you don’t know better than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also about being clean because when you listen to others reasoning and their stupidity and foolishness it has an impact on yourself because you go with things that you don’t agree with and so you just become unclean and lose yourself and what you truly stand for in life, which is in a way a form of lying because you lie to yourself and lie to others in terms of who you truly are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I guess the key thing with this, is to see the other person as just another person of this world and see that they themselves are far from perfect and so you shouldn’t judge others mistakes and judge people for their flaws and ‘foolishness’ because as Jesus once said “Father forgive them, they know not what they do” because in a way it plays into realities, and nobody can possibly know the deeper realities to their own reality and so they don’t realize the consequences of their actions, hence why Jesus was a master of this world, he understood this key principal. Whether we like it or not, we all sin because we are all not perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also about fooling others, because people know, but more importantly God knows if you are not being authentic to who you really are. Yet people fool themselves on who they really are, which is quite sad, but is the way of the world and we shouldn’t judge those whom fool themselves in this way because as I understand nobody on earth is actually perfect, so we all have our own sins that we commit, but because we don’t realize the sins we commit we should be more forgiving to others when we see that they commit sin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, its about filling your house so to speak things which are apart of you and not filling your house with junk from others and taking on other people’s problems which then has an impact on you in terms of you then become influenced by them and take on their flaws and negative traits because you are not being true to yourself. Hence why its so important for each and every person to strive be as true to themselves as they can possibly be and not do things because I write about it on this blog, but do things which are true in their hearts regardless of what others say or do and also its important so as I have put an ‘act’ on for so long because you lie to yourself and it is a form of sin, this is why its so important to be forgiving to others and yourself especially because everyone is far from perfect and everyone no mattar who they are have their own flaws and negative traits that they have. Equally we shouldn’t judge those who are not authentic to themselves and be forgiving to those who are not authentic and as I said once in a note “Leave others to their own foolishness and don’t try to help those who don’t want help and don’t try to take on other people’s problems, you have your own problems to be dealing with”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, we should be more trustful of ourselves and who we really are and not listen to the advice of others when we feel we know better than others, but equally we should listen to others whom we feel know better than we do, because as I said we are all far from perfect and so we shouldn’t judge the actions of others and should strive to be more forgiving of the sins of others because they don’t know the deeper realities of the sins that they commit, so its up to the individual to understand as and when others are sinning. We should also strive to be more respectful of others even if they sin against us because they are apart of life and we are far from perfect and because all is one to not be respectful to everything is not in line with reality, but the key thing is to be respectful towards yourself and your own feelings on mattars.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk a little about why it’s so important to be authentic and true to yourself and do what is right in your heart and not the hearts of others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Third Noble Truth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-third-noble-truth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Third Noble Truth" /><published>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Third-Noble-Truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-third-noble-truth/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/Statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Truths&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk about the third noble truth that the Buddha described. To recap the first noble truth is that life is inherently dukka and you can read my article about this &lt;a href=&quot;/the-first-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;  and then the second noble truth is that dukka has a cause and that cause arises from within us through what he described as wanting/thirst/trying/desire and you can give my article on this second noble truth &lt;a href=&quot;/the-second-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third noble truth simply states that which is subject to arising is also subject to ceasing. That ending of dukka, the ending of confusion, sorry and loss is nirvana. The Buddha described nirvana as unborn, ungrown and unconditioned. The Buddha argued in the second noble truth that this dukka arises from within us and so therefore we are the cause of dukka because we don’t understand the way of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I equate in my mind the third noble truth to what goes up must inevitably come down, it’s just a question of when it comes down, similar how in life you find people taking it out on others – their own suffering and it’s understandable because they don’t see the truth in the way of the world and you can’t blame them because its not their fault why they don’t see the way of the world. Eventually though all people who take it out on others their own suffering will incur a cost in the afterlife or karma as Buddhism describes it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Buddha also sees that our actions, our speech, and our thoughts are geared towards bringing about some kind of control. Then, when these efforts inevitably fail, we suffer. The Buddha doesn’t ask us to give up control. Instead, it acknowledges that we never had it in the first place. I know this is quite deep and it took me a long time to really fully grasp this understanding, because in my life I have attempted to exert control over others because I thought they were the cause of my suffering, when in fact it was myself who was causing myself my own suffering – which is quite a sad truth for me to actually realize because I have taken it out on others my own suffering and not been as compassionate to myself as I should be because I feel the need to be punished all the time because I feel the need to be punished and so this has hurt my friendships a lot and people whom are close to me because I just don’t want to hurt them and so have learned somewhat to avoid people and put a shield around myself because I think that others are the cause of my own suffering when in fact it is myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So more on the third noble truth, it essentially says to let go of attachment and desire because any desire and attachment to anything will inevitably cause dukka. This is quite a difficult thing for many to do because like I said they just want control mainly as an attempt to end their own suffering and so can make others suffer as I have done as a result of an attempt to end their own suffering. Therefore, its beholden upon each individual who understand the four noble truths to be more forgiving, loving, compassionate and understanding to those who don’t yet understand the nature of reality and the way of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this isn’t to say that you shouldn’t love others, your family, your spouse etc. because you should, because you can love others and love your spouse without being attached to them which took me some contemplation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend some time contemplating in meditation these truths and some time testing their validity by putting them to the test in your life, because the Buddha and others Buddha’s after him have extremely wise teachings and we would all do very well putting efforts to understand these noble truths that the Buddha has blessed us with in the world because like I said they are extremely wise and so if you want to end your own suffering then spend more time contemplating on these truths and meditating on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also be putting out my understanding of the eightfold path and each of them in separate articles on this blog so be sure to stay tuned for those articles because the Buddha argued that the eightfold path is actually the way out of suffering, which I tend to agree with, but don’t fully accept yet because I am still fairly new to Buddhism and have been putting a lot of effort to really understand the Buddha’s teachings and apply them to my own life because it is very wise teachings from a master of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you shouldn’t be deterred by the perception that you have of Buddhism and that modern society has given us, because Buddhism isn’t simply being a monk and living like a monk your whole life – its more so a way of living. There are lots of people who have lived and been good Buddhists and still managed to live ordinary lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small list of interesting people who are Buddhists is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dhammawiki.com/index.php/List_of_Celebrity_Buddhists&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; to name a few&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Bowie&lt;br /&gt;
Jackie Chan&lt;br /&gt;
Jack Dorsey&lt;br /&gt;
Bill Clinton&lt;br /&gt;
Mark Zuckerberg&lt;br /&gt;
Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rickhanson.net/third-noble-truth-noble-truth-end-suffering/&quot;&gt;https://www.rickhanson.net/third-noble-truth-noble-truth-end-suffering/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buddhanet.net/4noble16.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.buddhanet.net/4noble16.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BNmmWY9PAKQ&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BNmmWY9PAKQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://buddhistpeacefellowship.org/the-third-noble-truth-a-glimpse-of-hope/&quot;&gt;http://buddhistpeacefellowship.org/the-third-noble-truth-a-glimpse-of-hope/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Noble_Truths&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_Noble_Truths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca3/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca3/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yogiapproved.com/third-noble-truth-buddhism/&quot;&gt;https://www.yogiapproved.com/third-noble-truth-buddhism/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/rahulawhatthebuddha/the-third-noble-truth&quot;&gt;https://sites.google.com/site/rahulawhatthebuddha/the-third-noble-truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://buddhistpeacefellowship.org/the-four-noble-truths-in-our-world-truth-3-the-cessation-of-the-suffering-of-caste/&quot;&gt;https://buddhistpeacefellowship.org/the-four-noble-truths-in-our-world-truth-3-the-cessation-of-the-suffering-of-caste/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Four-Noble-Truths&quot;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Four-Noble-Truths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buddhistdoor.net/features/three-awakenings-and-four-noble-truths/&quot;&gt;https://www.buddhistdoor.net/features/three-awakenings-and-four-noble-truths/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unhcr.org/50be10cb9.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unhcr.org/50be10cb9.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebuddhistsociety.org/page/fundamental-teachings&quot;&gt;https://www.thebuddhistsociety.org/page/fundamental-teachings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The True Aliens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-true-aliens/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The True Aliens" /><published>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-True-Aliens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-true-aliens/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will give my rough understanding of the alien topic. Which has nowadays become virtually a household topic. Most of the information I have received here has been from The Great White Brotherhood’s book “Aliens the Strange Truth” and you can find a link to that book &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreatwhitebrotherhood.org/books/aliens-the-strange-truth/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the true aliens are very similar to humans but are entirely inter-dimensional that is they live in between dimensions and can enter our realities if they do so choose and as with humans you have good ones and bad ones. But they are actually brought about from people’s unused personality bundles so if you have a human who is full of joy and happy and positive then you will most likely produce an alien of similar traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aliens have of course their own agendas with things, and some have similar if not the same agendas as us humans and so we are able to work alongside the aliens to have a positive effect on humanity and the world if we do so choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you also have the grey aliens who are actually demonic in nature and work with intelligence agencies to produce a disastrous effect on the world. Of course, it is their choice if they want to work alongside actual demons and invite them into their reality, but that is their choice. Which I of course disagree with because to work alongside demons is terribly foolish, I guess it’s a question of what those humans that work alongside them really want, but its sad because they don’t know what they really want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, the true aliens which are humanity’s unused personality bundles serve life and are very advanced compared to us humans and so we would do well as a species to listen to them and their advice for humanity because they know much more than we currently do in our current stage of advancement. But of course, that isn’t to say that the aliens are here to take us over. The good aliens are here to help us. I leave humanity to judge the intentions of aliens because as I said some are good and some are bad, and some work with other species going back thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there were to be aliens come to our planet in an ideal world we would treat them with respect and love (even the bad true aliens) because aliens are as much apart of life as we are and we have the right to life as they do, but that isn’t to say that we should judge the actions of aliens because they work on much higher levels of reality and we would be wise as a species to not condemn their actions out of hand because they know a lot more than we do about many things, the good aliens work alongside The Great White Brotherhood in serving man also because they have the same objectives which is to help people and assist man incarnate and discarnate and we as a species could never do with enough help in promoting things like peace, love etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this article I will give my rough understanding of the alien topic. Which has nowadays become virtually a household topic. Most of the information I have received here has been from The Great White Brotherhood’s book “Aliens the Strange Truth” and you can find a link to that book Here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding your Ideal Partner</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/finding-your-ideal-partner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding your Ideal Partner" /><published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Finding-your-Ideal-Partner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/finding-your-ideal-partner/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Ideal-partner/partner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Partner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little about finding your ideal partner. Now I feel that many people unfortunately don’t actually know how to find their ideal partner, which I think is unfortunate because I would like to see a world where everyone meets their ideal partner in life, because the world would be a lot more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the trick with finding your ideal partner is dead simple. All you need to do is sit somewhere quietly and say a short prayer to God telling him that you are ready to receive your ideal partner in life and thank him for sending you your ideal partner. Now of course it may take a number of weeks/months/years for you to finally meet in person, but you will have your guides/Gods angels helping to pull the strings so to speak so that you two are able to meet in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you meet your ideal partner, I am told that it is like an explosion when you finally meet for the first time. However, both you and your ideal partner sometimes need to change before you meet in order for you to be a couple and for you to have a loving, long lasting successful relationship with each other. An example of something that may need to change is your understanding of the opposite gender (or same gender if you are homosexual). Especially I find with men in our society we have a lot of toxic masculinity which are behaviors which you believe make you a man – but don’t, because as I found out you define who a man should be – which thus makes a man a man. Equally a woman defines what a woman should be – which makes a woman a woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, don’t beat yourself up too much if you haven’t had much experience with the opposite gender even if you are at an old age in life. There is always room for growth no matter how much you think you know. But seek to say this short prayer if you are still without your ideal partner and don’t think that you are silly for saying this prayer if you don’t prayer often. But seek to be the best version of yourself and being so full of sexual frustration isn’t in my opinion being the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a nice video that more or less says the same thing from Bob Sanders who works with The Great White Brotherhood, link to the video is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TzONRXw_x5s&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.truity.com/test/which-personality-type-your-love-match&quot;&gt;https://www.truity.com/test/which-personality-type-your-love-match&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.howstuffworks.com/quiz/whos-your-ideal-partner&quot;&gt;https://play.howstuffworks.com/quiz/whos-your-ideal-partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://brightside.me/inspiration-relationships/scientists-reveal-how-to-choose-the-perfect-partner-before-you-turn-35-737760/&quot;&gt;https://brightside.me/inspiration-relationships/scientists-reveal-how-to-choose-the-perfect-partner-before-you-turn-35-737760/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marriage.com/advice/relationship/characteristics-of-a-good-partner/&quot;&gt;https://www.marriage.com/advice/relationship/characteristics-of-a-good-partner/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lifehack.org/articles/communication/25-qualities-the-person-you-should-marry.html&quot;&gt;https://www.lifehack.org/articles/communication/25-qualities-the-person-you-should-marry.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-qualities-are-you-looking-for-in-an-ideal-partner&quot;&gt;https://www.quora.com/What-qualities-are-you-looking-for-in-an-ideal-partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.imagorelationshipswork.com/qualities-to-look-for-in-a-partner&quot;&gt;https://blog.imagorelationshipswork.com/qualities-to-look-for-in-a-partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://technology.inquirer.net/101840/got-specifics-for-your-ideal-partner-research-says-most-are-looking-for-the-same-qualities&quot;&gt;https://technology.inquirer.net/101840/got-specifics-for-your-ideal-partner-research-says-most-are-looking-for-the-same-qualities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://liveboldandbloom.com/12/relationships/qualities-good-woman&quot;&gt;https://liveboldandbloom.com/12/relationships/qualities-good-woman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3dservicad.com/three-qualities-of-the-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;https://www.3dservicad.com/three-qualities-of-the-ideal-partner/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bonobology.com/must-have-relationship-qualities/&quot;&gt;https://www.bonobology.com/must-have-relationship-qualities/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikihow.com/Find-Your-Ideal-Partner&quot;&gt;https://www.wikihow.com/Find-Your-Ideal-Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinybuddha.com/blog/key-finding-ideal-partner-life/&quot;&gt;https://tinybuddha.com/blog/key-finding-ideal-partner-life/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/better/health/how-use-love-list-find-your-ideal-romantic-partner-ncna847641&quot;&gt;https://www.nbcnews.com/better/health/how-use-love-list-find-your-ideal-romantic-partner-ncna847641&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/the-art-closeness/201710/the-surprising-key-finding-the-perfect-partner&quot;&gt;https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/the-art-closeness/201710/the-surprising-key-finding-the-perfect-partner&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Found at Sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/found-at-sea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Found at Sea" /><published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Found-at-Sea</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/found-at-sea/">&lt;p&gt;This short poem is just a follow up from lost at sea made 19/01/22. I guess the fact that I recognized that there was a problem was really significant in bringing me to the light so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the thing that really did it was prayer. Prayer is what really brought me to the light, so if you feel lost as I did, then please do take to prayer because it will help you alot, feel free to give my article on prayer a read which gives you the technique that I generally use &lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found at Sea&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I return from being lost at sea for oh so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look back and realize that my own ignorance, arrogance, and reluctance was preventing me from seeing the light of the lighthouse that was always there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now that I look back in sorrow at all the suffering that I put myself through in rowing endlessly attempting to find land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a sobering thought to think that the reason I caused myself so much suffering to myself is because I was so deluded that I thought that suffering was the answer to solve all my problems. It was not.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">This short poem is just a follow up from lost at sea made 19/01/22. I guess the fact that I recognized that there was a problem was really significant in bringing me to the light so to speak.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lost at Sea</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lost-at-sea-poem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lost at Sea" /><published>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Lost-at-Sea-Poem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lost-at-sea-poem/">&lt;p&gt;I thought I would share here this poem I wrote in December 2021 to share here that in life it hasn’t always been easy sailing so to speak. I felt I owe it to myself to share this short poem because people oft get the wrong idea about me that I have had an easy life through life and that because of my upbringing I have had a perfect life. Which therefore gives them the right to speak down to me thinkign that I haven’t gone through similar difficulties as they have. This simply isn’t true - you can have the most perfect upbringing in life, but still feel completely lost. This poem is of course a metaphor for life where I was in such a deep state of sloth and torpor and would just “goto sleep” as I described it at time. I will also post my very short poem on being found at sea - which I think is quite cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what the poem really kinda illistrates is that there is a purpose to life and that sometimes your perceptions of life, your way of looking at things and your way of living can have a major impact on your wellbeing and mental health. What this poem really is about is not giving up because all too often I find that people give up easily on things and that if people put more efforts into changing their beliefs and their perceptions that they can change their reality and who they want to be in life. But only you can choose who you want to be in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I begin the poem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowing and rowing endlessly at sea looking for land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will I ever find land?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long have I been rowing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Endlessly it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I see others rowing in their boats looking for land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are as lost as me, some act like they are not lost and that seems to fool some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is lost at sea rowing endlessly looking for land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will they ever find land?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long have these others been rowing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more than others it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I hallucinate and think I have found land after all my searching and all the vast efforts I have put into rowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joy I feel in thinking I have found land doesn’t last very long as I get closer and closer and realize it was just a hallucination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have those from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the stars give me warning signs that there are pirates or sharks further ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is dying any much worse than rowing endlessly lost at sea in the hopes that I will one day find land?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I oft envy the stars with their vantage point; they seem to know so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do they have sympathy for me being lost at sea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are they the reason I’m lost at sea in a boat rowing endlessly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are special boats that pick-up people that for whatever reason stop rowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that special boat they tell that person why it’s so important to keep rowing endlessly at sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know who the crazy one is to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I dream of being older and being even more lost at sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will there ever be a point in my life when I am not lost at sea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I see couples share their boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the result is the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Endless rowing lost at sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s better that they are lost at sea with each other, at least they can provide each other comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes there are items in the sea that I pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They give me entertainment for some time, but I know deep down that the entertainment they give me is only due to how benign rowing lost at sea is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I ask myself is there any point in continuing? Afterall, I have been rowing endlessly at sea my whole life and yet I still hold on to some hope that maybe one day I will be able to find land and live there instead of rowing endlessly at sea. Maybe I’m deluded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should ignore the warnings from the stars and let the pirates and sharks have me, at least then maybe it will stop me from rowing endlessly lost at sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who put this ocean here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why was I given a boat and paddle to row?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why could I have not started at land to begin with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that one day I can find land.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="life" /><summary type="html">I thought I would share here this poem I wrote in December 2021 to share here that in life it hasn’t always been easy sailing so to speak. I felt I owe it to myself to share this short poem because people oft get the wrong idea about me that I have had an easy life through life and that because of my upbringing I have had a perfect life. Which therefore gives them the right to speak down to me thinkign that I haven’t gone through similar difficulties as they have. This simply isn’t true - you can have the most perfect upbringing in life, but still feel completely lost. This poem is of course a metaphor for life where I was in such a deep state of sloth and torpor and would just “goto sleep” as I described it at time. I will also post my very short poem on being found at sea - which I think is quite cool.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Second Noble Truth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-second-noble-truth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Second Noble Truth" /><published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Second-Noble-Truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-second-noble-truth/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/Statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Truths&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little about my understanding of the second noble truth in Buddhism. The second noble truth is that dukka has a cause and that cause is a thirst, craving, wanting or as I put it desire. Essentially what this means it that dukka inevitably has a cause which the Buddha saw as wanting/thirst/trying to get the object of desire into our hands. This wanting/thirst/trying/desire arises from within us (which I agree with).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wanting comes in three different forms. The first is sensual desire. We want comfort, physical sensations – nice food, a healthy body. We also want good intellectual stimulation, good conversation, a balanced and emotional life, enjoyable art and entertainment, we want to listen to good music, we want massages, we want to see nice photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second form of craving is for existence itself. We don’t want to die and what we envision death to be or I have envisioned death to be is nothingness (and has caused me to be in a total state of sloth and torpor) We would much rather live and persistent and live until 1000 years old. I guess its more so the unknowable and uncertainty of what happens when our physical body ceases to function. But something which has helped me is to realize that we are not our physical bodies. The brain and heart are just computers in a way because they keep the body alive. We are not our physical bodies so we should not identify with our physical body, which is something that I have suffered with tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third and last form of craving/want/thirst/desire is that for non-existence. That is we don’t want to be unhappy, we don’t want to be miserable etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what the second noble truth really is about is realizing that dukka has a cause and that cause is thirst/desire/wanting/craving and this arises only from within us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rickhanson.net/second-noble-truth-noble-truth-cause-suffering/&quot;&gt;https://www.rickhanson.net/second-noble-truth-noble-truth-cause-suffering/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buddhanet.net/e-learning/buddhism/bs-s04.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.buddhanet.net/e-learning/buddhism/bs-s04.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://secularbuddhistnetwork.org/reflections-on-the-second-noble-truth-its-more-than-craving/&quot;&gt;https://secularbuddhistnetwork.org/reflections-on-the-second-noble-truth-its-more-than-craving/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.learnreligions.com/the-second-noble-truth-450092&quot;&gt;https://www.learnreligions.com/the-second-noble-truth-450092&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca2/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca2/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.londonbuddhistvihara.org/teachings/the-first-and-second-noble-truths/&quot;&gt;https://www.londonbuddhistvihara.org/teachings/the-first-and-second-noble-truths/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1YPDFcOr2t0&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1YPDFcOr2t0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://mindfulspot.com/second-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;https://mindfulspot.com/second-noble-truth/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yogiapproved.com/second-noble-truth-causes-of-suffering/&quot;&gt;https://www.yogiapproved.com/second-noble-truth-causes-of-suffering/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/the-second-noble-truth&quot;&gt;https://www.psychologytoday.com/gb/blog/the-second-noble-truth&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Doing The Most Loving Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/doing-the-most-loving-thing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doing The Most Loving Thing" /><published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Doing-The-Most-Loving-Thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/doing-the-most-loving-thing/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little about love and doing the most loving thing. I will just say now that love is the strongest force in the universe and love is what gives us strength in this world and also should be the force that guides us in terms of we should always strive to take the actions that will bring the most love to the world, not just for yourself but for all of life, because you are not the only person living on the planet and should be respectful not just to yourself, but to all of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also add here that similar to what Jesus once said with when having to one of two actions, where both is an evil in a sense – do the action that is the lesser of two evils. Well, I put here today that when you are faced with one of two choices, you should take the choice that will bring the most love not just to yourself but to others as well. Or as I describe it doing the most loving thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, love should be the guiding force in the world and we should all strive to be more loving towards others, especially ourselves and follow Jesus’s teaching of “loving thy neighbor as ourselves”, because with this simply principal if everyone applied it to their lives then the world would be a much more beautiful place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly you shouldn’t just love your neighbors you should love your enemies also because if you only love your friends and ‘neighbors’ then where is the room to loving those who do you harm? Also something that I am trying to understand more is that you don’t beat evil by being evil yourself – or fighting fire with fire just simply doesn’t work, and I am yet to fully understand that. The only thing that beats evil is the power of God, which comes through things like love, peace, happiness, joy or praying for others evil and meditating on things like love and peace etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap up, seek to be more loving to one another and seek to when faced with one or more decisions in life – seek to take the decision which will bring not just the most love to yourself, but bring the most love to others as well. Also when you see evil seek to pray for that person’s evil and just send out your love to that person as best as you can – feel free to give my articles on &lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Praying For Your Enemies&lt;/a&gt; a read which will give you some good guidance on how to pray and meditate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Jesus" /><category term="God" /><category term="Christianity" /><category term="Love" /><category term="Love thy neighbour" /><category term="Prayer" /><category term="Meditationg" /><category term="Enemies" /><category term="Evil" /><summary type="html">In this short article I will talk a little about love and doing the most loving thing. I will just say now that love is the strongest force in the universe and love is what gives us strength in this world and also should be the force that guides us in terms of we should always strive to take the actions that will bring the most love to the world, not just for yourself but for all of life, because you are not the only person living on the planet and should be respectful not just to yourself, but to all of life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Speech</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-speech/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Speech" /><published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Speech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-speech/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/eightfold-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eightfoldpath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk about right speech which is one of the eightfold paths. Right speech encompasses anything you say to others and yourself, even with talking in your mind you should practice right speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key thing in right speech is to not tell lies to anybody, but you don’t need to tell everyone your whole life, but just have speech which is consistent with the truth as you know it to be, and which is relevant to the discussion at hand. The reason this causes suffering is because you need to constantly keep track of what you have told people all the time in order to be organized with yourself, and so if you are always lying then it will cause much suffering to yourself in keeping track of what you have and haven’t told others because it causes you suffering in the sense that you just are not organized and it can be a bit much on yourself keeping track on who you have told what to whom. It also hinders your soul because when you don’t tell people the truth as you know it to be then it brings death to the soul, but also it hurts others which brings death to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of right speech is talking at the correct time when it is your time to speak during conversations - which is something that I cannot really read, I guess for me it’s due to confidence in a way and feeling like I am a bad person in doing this, which is just silly really, but also I speak out of turn a lot because my own personality and ego gets in the way and also my anxiety can also take control over me. It’s also about having relevant conversations to the correct people at the right time and realizing when the correct time for discussion on xyz is. For example, you shouldn’t disturb someone who is sleeping to talk about moving from your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right speech is also about avoiding idle talk, gossip and speaking ill of others, because essentially it causes others suffering if they find out about you talking ill about them, but it causes yourself suffering in the sense that its low vibrational level talk which hinders your soul (for me at least) and is mostly just piety to talk about these kinds of things, because its zero sum – in the sense that you don’t really get much and the other party doesn’t really get much from it either – except fulfilling their own egos. Its also about showing others respect for all their idiosyncrasy, faults and characters by avoiding talking ill of them and avoiding lying to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A further aspect of Right Speech is knowing when to be silent during conversation – even if someone asks you a question directly to you because it adds to the conversation even not answering someone’s question. But of course, this isn’t an excuse to not talk to people during conversation but is another aspect of right speech which I thought I would mention here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right speech is also about using the correct use of your language (whichever language that you speak in) and ensuring that you can present yourself in a way that you would like to be presented to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also about not hurting others through your words - which I think is quite important because it brings death to the soul, but also hurts the other person. There is a time and place for every conversation and some things are better left unsaid sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly the final aspect of right speech is having healthy, good, meaningful conversations to others about things which are of importance to either them or yourself and also having the appropriate body language – tone of voice – energy level during conversation. This causes suffering to yourself because you should come across in conversation in saying what you mean and tone of voice, body language and energy level is what matters if you don’t then it undermines yourself and brings death to the soul because you are not able to come across and present to the world what you mean – which causes suffering and causes others to misconstrue. In other words, say what you mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me its also about control – because I feel that by not being 100% truthful it will free me from suffering because I feel that others cause me suffering in how they judge me (or how I perceive they will judge me), but really, I cause myself suffering by not adhering to the eightfold path as best as I can. Which also plays into this fault I have that you need to fight fire with fire. Its just difficult for me to really accept this, I guess. I also need to understand more why there is nothing is permanent, and everything is in constant change. But then again what’s the worst judgement someone can really make about me – and who are they to make that judgement upon me? The only judgement I should give is to myself and I should judge myself fairly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, right speech is not lying to others, having good conversations with people using the correct body language and tone of voice, speaking to others at the correct times in conversations. But its also about ensuring that you avoid from idle talk, gossip and speaking ill of others (even in your own mind and in a way plays a lot into judging others which is something that everyone should strive to do because it causes others suffering how others are judged – which isn’t good). Its also about saying what you mean and believing in what you say because its important to do that to free yourself from suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1: 08/03/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right Speech is also about having conversations when appropriate and meaning in what you say i.e saying something and then having an ulterior motive because this brings suffuring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tricycle.org/trikedaily/family-dharma-right-speech-reconsidered/&quot;&gt;https://tricycle.org/trikedaily/family-dharma-right-speech-reconsidered/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.learnreligions.com/right-speech-450072&quot;&gt;https://www.learnreligions.com/right-speech-450072&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca4/samma-vaca/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca4/samma-vaca/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://zenstudiespodcast.com/right-speech/&quot;&gt;https://zenstudiespodcast.com/right-speech/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buddhistdoor.net/features/right-speech-is-responsible-speech/&quot;&gt;https://www.buddhistdoor.net/features/right-speech-is-responsible-speech/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sryahwapublications.com/journal-of-religion-and-theology/pdf/v3-i3/4.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.sryahwapublications.com/journal-of-religion-and-theology/pdf/v3-i3/4.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.dickinson.edu/buddhistethics/files/2017/09/King-Right-Speech-final-1.pdf&quot;&gt;https://blogs.dickinson.edu/buddhistethics/files/2017/09/King-Right-Speech-final-1.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=19VdkH0DqRU&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=19VdkH0DqRU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unhcr.org/50be10cb9.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.unhcr.org/50be10cb9.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buddhism&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buddhism&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><category term="Right Speech" /><category term="Noble EightFoldPath" /><category term="Noble Four Truths" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First Noble Truth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-first-noble-truth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First Noble Truth" /><published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-First-Noble-Truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-first-noble-truth/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/Statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Truths&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first noble truth is that the existence is inevitably dukka or usually this is translated as suffering but that doesn’t encompass the entire meaning of this word. It means unsatisfactory, I think what the Buddha really meant by this word is that because everything is temporary, we are not able to satisfy anything into a permanent state and because of this we suffer and that it is unavoidable due to there being existence – this is just one aspect of dukka that the Buddha meant and I think one of the more important aspects of dukka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first kind of dukka is pain, both physical and mental pain – whether we like it or not, pain is an unavoidable part of our lives. Many cases to avoid pain actually increases it as with the case of a toothache that is put of for a few months and then when going to the dentist you experience more pain from having to have the tooth removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second form of dukka is change we suffer because we think that our unhappiness, doubts, worries and negative emotions are permanent states and define who we are. But we should always appreciate this basic notion that nothing is permanent – everything is in everlasting change because anything that is made up of something (and everything is made up of parts) it is subject to change because those parts are inevitably broken down or built up into other things which make up a whole. This is because in existence everything is made from parts. Even the most basic thing an atom goes into making something and so when atoms make up wood – can you really call all those atoms wood? Or can you call wood just a bunch of atoms? Labels for different interdependent parts seems to define existence in a way. I guess the point I’m making is that because things are made from interdependent parts, they will always be subject to change because they are either broken down or reused and turned into something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is thus what defines existence, the fact that all things are essentially just made up of other smaller things and due to this its law that because everything is made up of interdependent parts they will either decay and be broken down or they will be put to use and turned into something else (as is the case with atoms) and so nothing is complete in of itself because nothing can be unconditioned in terms of being free from the parts that make it and being free of being able to be built into something. Therefore because of this basic principle everything that will ever exist and can possibly exist is bound by the law of change. Or as the Buddha put it everything is impermanent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third and final form of dukka is one which requires serious contemplation and that is that if your existence if in being, then you must inevitably pass out of existence. This is something which I still don’t fully actually understand to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always put my words to the test and see the truth for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rickhanson.net/four-noble-truths-noble-truth-suffering/&quot;&gt;https://www.rickhanson.net/four-noble-truths-noble-truth-suffering/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Four-Noble-Truths&quot;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Four-Noble-Truths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buddhanet.net/4noble4.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.buddhanet.net/4noble4.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediation1st.co.uk/?blog=blogs/archive/2014/11/05/the.first.noble.truth.aspx&quot;&gt;https://www.mediation1st.co.uk/?blog=blogs/archive/2014/11/05/the.first.noble.truth.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pbs.org/edens/thailand/buddhism.htm&quot;&gt;https://www.pbs.org/edens/thailand/buddhism.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G54Ap3NiS_o&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G54Ap3NiS_o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2XdhxTXuxRY&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2XdhxTXuxRY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca1/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/dhamma/sacca/sacca1/index.html&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>