<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-02T03:46:08+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chris’ Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality. Here you will find articles on Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things. Here I also talk about Buddhism and a little bit about Psychology.</subtitle><author><name>Chris</name></author><entry><title type="html">Doing The Most Loving Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/doing-the-most-loving-thing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Doing The Most Loving Thing" /><published>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Doing-The-Most-Loving-Thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/doing-the-most-loving-thing/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little about love and doing the most loving thing. I will just say now that love is the strongest force in the universe and love is what gives us strength in this world and also should be the force that guides us in terms of we should always strive to take the actions that will bring the most love to the world, not just for yourself but for all of life, because you are not the only person living on the planet and should be respectful not just to yourself, but to all of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also add here that similar to what Jesus once said with when having to one of two actions, where both is an evil in a sense – do the action that is the lesser of two evils. Well, I put here today that when you are faced with one of two choices, you should take the choice that will bring the most love not just to yourself but to others as well. Or as I describe it doing the most loving thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, love should be the guiding force in the world and we should all strive to be more loving towards others, especially ourselves and follow Jesus’s teaching of “loving thy neighbor as ourselves”, because with this simply principal if everyone applied it to their lives then the world would be a much more beautiful place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly you shouldn’t just love your neighbors you should love your enemies also because if you only love your friends and ‘neighbors’ then where is the room to loving those who do you harm? Also something that I am trying to understand more is that you don’t beat evil by being evil yourself – or fighting fire with fire just simply doesn’t work, and I am yet to fully understand that. The only thing that beats evil is the power of God, which comes through things like love, peace, happiness, joy or praying for others evil and meditating on things like love and peace etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap up, seek to be more loving to one another and seek to when faced with one or more decisions in life – seek to take the decision which will bring not just the most love to yourself, but bring the most love to others as well. Also when you see evil seek to pray for that person’s evil and just send out your love to that person as best as you can – feel free to give my article on &lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Praying For Your Enemies&lt;/a&gt; a read which will give you some good guidance on how to pray and meditate.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Jesus" /><category term="God" /><category term="Christianity" /><category term="Love" /><category term="Love thy neighbour" /><category term="Prayer" /><category term="Meditationg" /><category term="Enemies" /><category term="Evil" /><summary type="html">In this short article I will talk a little about love and doing the most loving thing. I will just say now that love is the strongest force in the universe and love is what gives us strength in this world and also should be the force that guides us in terms of we should always strive to take the actions that will bring the most love to the world, not just for yourself but for all of life, because you are not the only person living on the planet and should be respectful not just to yourself, but to all of life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crisis in Ukraine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crisis-in-ukraine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crisis in Ukraine" /><published>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Crisis-in-Ukraine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crisis-in-ukraine/">&lt;p&gt;Hello all, it saddens me to see war in Ukraine. I don’t know much about Ukraine and the politics involved in that area, but I know that all war isn’t good. I don’t actually watch the news, but I have heard from the forums and friends/family that I visit that the situation is dire in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did see Russian forces from YouTube enter Ukraine and heard that the people were confusing the Russians by mixing the street signs. My thoughts are with those who are affected by this terrible crisis in Ukraine, and I wish all from Ukraine who read this message safety and good health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I have decided to take a stand against this, and I will be praying for Ukraine that the war be stopped, and the suffering and chaos be put to an end there because I stand for peace and love and not war and chaos as should we all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, I encourage all who read this short article to take up prayer and also meditation and after each meditation session to send out your loving/peaceful thoughts out to Ukraine. Of course, those who are able to – perhaps you could further support Ukraine by funding noble causes which help the people of Ukraine in some way and engaging in debates and lobbying our Government to take action against this crisis in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course the issue of Ukraine all comes down to politics in some way or another. So seek to pray that these politicians that we have in power are brought to the light so to speak because whether we like it or not our polticitians and world leaders are corrupt and not good people. The best thing that we can do as people is pray for these people that currently hold positions of power in the world. Politics is a subject I tend to avoid because it devides people alot, but we as people should recongize that the leaders we currently have don’t have our best interests at heard, therefore we should use the power of prayer to reduce the suffering that these people that we currently in power cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is on each and everyone of us and our responsibility as people to pray for these people in power because like I said they don’t have our best interests at heart. But we as people should be consistent with prayer and setup a regular practice of prayer as our daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to give my article on prayer a read, linked &lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;, which also gives the prayer which I have made, which may be of use to you who read this message and also give my article on meditation a read, linked &lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;, on the technique which I have used for over 3 and a half years now which has helped me significantly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Current Affairs" /><summary type="html">Hello all, it saddens me to see war in Ukraine. I don’t know much about Ukraine and the politics involved in that area, but I know that all war isn’t good. I don’t actually watch the news, but I have heard from the forums and friends/family that I visit that the situation is dire in Ukraine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fake Spirituality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fake-spirituality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fake Spirituality" /><published>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Fake-Spirituality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fake-spirituality/">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to talk a little about ‘fake spirituality’ which is something I have been a victim of for various points in my life. I define fake spirituality is spirituality which is just fake and not true to yourself. As the Buddha once said, “see the truth in my words for yourself”. So essentially what it can mean is that you don’t see the truth for yourself, but act like you see the truth. Also, a side note I see the truth in various things – but fail to accept it. Which is something that I don’t fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point I wanted to add is that people identify with being ‘spiritual’… what does that even mean? There is nothing wrong with that, but I think it hinders your ability to make actual spiritual progress because with identifying as being spiritual it could encourage you to share this with others and so ‘virtue signal’ – which isn’t right because the spiritual path should be trod in secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which I think is important to ensuring that you don’t practice ‘fake spirituality’ is to become more like a child, feel free to read my article on this &lt;a href=&quot;/becoming-a-child/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; another thing which I think is important to not practicing ‘fake spirituality’ is to offer your service to the world through a job which doesn’t harm others (i.e gun seller in America) but also to meditate/pray and also to not lie to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key aspect of it is also to take the saw dust out of your own eyes before you go around helping others in their ways, feel free to give my article on this &lt;a href=&quot;/taking-the-saw-dust-out-of-your-own-eyes/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;, because you should help yourself before you go around helping others. Everyone is far from perfect and so everyone should work on themselves because everyone has flaws in some way – this could be personality flaws, bad habits, flaws picked up from others in their lives etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly just do things which are true to yourself and don’t feel the need to follow the crowd at all. Especially if you feel that the crowd is wrong in what they do. Do things true to yourself, and not others. Only you can decide what it means to be [your name]. Nobody can decide that for you. Only you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I wanted to talk a little about ‘fake spirituality’ which is something I have been a victim of for various points in my life. I define fake spirituality is spirituality which is just fake and not true to yourself. As the Buddha once said, “see the truth in my words for yourself”. So essentially what it can mean is that you don’t see the truth for yourself, but act like you see the truth. Also, a side note I see the truth in various things – but fail to accept it. Which is something that I don’t fully understand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Remove Bad Spirits - Possession</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/possession/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Remove Bad Spirits - Possession" /><published>2022-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Possession</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/possession/">&lt;p&gt;I don’t take credit for the techniques outlined here - they come from The Great White Brotherhood. Link to original article is &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreatwhitebrotherhood.org/lessons/possession/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; link to their website is &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreatwhitebrotherhood.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to put here a technique that you can do to get rid of any bad spirit that may be attached to you. It will also protect you.. It is simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sit on your own in a room with the door and window closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell God that you are going to pray to get rid of a bad spirit and ask Him to send His angels and your guides to stand guard over you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then imagine that you are sitting under a shower of water that is pouring over your head, over your body and down into the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be spiritual “water” but try really to feel it as if you were under a real shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sit under this shower of spiritual water for a couple of minutes and visualize all negative entities being washed away from you and down into the ground just as if you were dirty and were washing the dirt from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine this spiritual water not only washing your body but washing you inside also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of minutes, let the spiritual water stop, thank God for the fact that all bad spirits have now gone, thank God for the protection that he sent you and just carry on with your day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may do this for three days consecutively, if you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any bad spirit will now be gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, how to protect your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buy a small bag of rock salt – real salt not this man made stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put it outside your house where the sun shines. Leave it there for three days so that the daylight fills the salt with positive energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, ask God to bless the salt – just ask God as if you were talking to a friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, go round your house/apartment and, everywhere where there is an opening – doors, windows, fireplaces, toilets, wash basins, taps (faucets), say a little prayer to God thanking Him for His protection and sprinkle a little of the salt in the sign of a cross over those openings. You can also sprinkle a little salt in a line across the threshold of the doors and windows. Go round your entire place doing that. Then, when you have finished, thank God for his protection and you are finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a garden (yard) you can also go round the limit of your area sprinkling a little salt and thanking God for His protection. Once again, when you are finished, thank God for his protection and you are finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No demon can now enter your house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you lie down to sleep, say a short prayer to God thanking Him for sending His angels to look after you when you sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will draw angels to you who will remain in the astral realms protecting you as you sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then imagine that you are like an embryo chick. Imagine a white eggshell completely surrounding you as you sleep with you safe in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This eggshell will be real in the etheric realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you have angels protecting you in the astral realms and you are protected from the etheric realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing can harm you and nothing can enter your space. Also, you can not leave that space as the eggshell is keeping you safe inside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, sleep peacefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you wake up in the morning, thank God for sending His angels to keep you safe all night, imagine the eggshell dissolving and just carry on with your day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, do not go to bed having taken drugs or strong drink.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I don’t take credit for the techniques outlined here - they come from The Great White Brotherhood. Link to original article is here link to their website is here</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prayer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/prayer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prayer" /><published>2022-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Prayer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/prayer/">&lt;p&gt;Praying is one of the things that I think a lot of people can benefit from. The secret with prayer is to have the genuine intention of helping the person/thing you are praying and doing it for them and not for yourself. To progress towards God, it’s important to serve your fellow man, meditate and pray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When praying for others, you draw towards you Gods’ helpers/guides/angels etc. who will help you with your needs and help you to progress towards God. So, helping others through service and prayer is almost definitely in everyone’s best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technique that I use to pray nowadays is to sit and visualize the person/thing that is causing harm to the world and send out a prayer that this person/thing is helped by God but doing so in a manner without any ill intent towards the person/thing you are praying for but doing so in the genuine intention that this person is helped by God for his benefit and not your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another technique which has helped me along my journey, and I think which will help others is to use Jesus’s prayer which is a really good prayer called the “Lords prayer” which you can find a copy of it somewhere on the internet, but it goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our Father who art in heaven,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hallowed by thy name,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thy Kingdom come,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thy will be done,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On earth as it is in heaven,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give us this day our daily bread,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And forgive us our sins as we forgive those who sin against us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead us not into temptation,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But deliver us from evil,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Power and the Glory is yours, now and forever and ever,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amen”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, I say this prayer a few times (but leave the amen until the end) and say it with conviction and trueness in your heart. Over time you will be able to take up regular prayer and draw towards you Gods angels/guides who will work alongside you to help for your benefit and the benefit of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to also give my article a read which is similar to this one &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovehumanity.gitlab.io/spiritual/Pray-For-Your-Enemies/&quot;&gt;Pray for your Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1: 02/03/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made my own prayer if anyone is interested in my prayer feel fre to use it as a template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Said with conviction and sincerity and a belief in the power of God and with an understanding and trueness in the meanings of the words. Be sincere and actually act like you art thanking God directly when saying this prayer for the ‘magic’ to work. Generally I repeat this prayer for half an hour and it will and has done wonders for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our Father who art in heaven,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hallowed be your name,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Thank you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the blessings that you send to us on earth,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For helping those in need,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping us away from evil and corruption,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For helping those who are seduced by evil and corruption,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading us not into temptation,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But leading us to become more Christ like,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing peace, love, harmony and order to the world,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giving us the strength, dignity, fortitude, bravery and courage to fulfill your will for each of us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping us to serve you and only you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping those will ill will in their hearts to change for the benefit of life,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helping those who don’t yet believe in your power,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And giving us freedom and leading us to you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amen”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Jesus" /><category term="God" /><category term="Christianity" /><summary type="html">Praying is one of the things that I think a lot of people can benefit from. The secret with prayer is to have the genuine intention of helping the person/thing you are praying and doing it for them and not for yourself. To progress towards God, it’s important to serve your fellow man, meditate and pray.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Intention</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-intention/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Intention" /><published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Intention</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-intention/">&lt;p&gt;Now I believe that right intention is one of the more important parts of the eightfold path because if you don’t have right intention then all else fails in terms of freeing yourself from suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right intention begins by becoming more mindful of your intentions and so I believe that right mindfulness is linked heavily to right intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me I oft take my own interpretation in Buddhism which is why I enjoy it so much because it’s very flexible and I don’t think it’s a religion but more of a way of living. To me right intention is about bringing others up/helping people in some way because I recognize that all is one and so to hurt/harm anything is harming yourself. It’s also about not letting yourself down and doing things which are in your best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also about meaning because meaning comes from helping others and serving others and not just thinking for yourself as I myself have found out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me I have been very selfish with regard to things and avoided others a lot and it has made me very alone in life which has contributed heavily to my own downfall in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seek to practice right intention in your life because life should be about helping others to the best of your ability and for me God sees everyone’s struggles and understands how difficult it can be for people, but my advice would be to persevere and see it through and just have faith in God that he will get you through rough times because faifth is what gives us strength.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right intention is also about not giving way to thoughts of ill will or harming others (which for me has been a hindrance in my life and is one of the five hindrances) because your own thoughts are very important in defining who you are and what your actions are. Therefore, if you know that you give way to unwholesome thoughts seek refuge in prayer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, don’t just read these words blindly and practice here what I have said today because you are able to change yourself through these very wise words and thereby change the world for the betterment of mankind and when you help others and work for others then by the law of mutual attraction which I have an article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovehumanity.gitlab.io/spiritual/The-Law-of-Mutual-Attraction/&quot;&gt;The Law Mutual Attraction&lt;/a&gt; you will attract towards you people/guides/angels who will work with you to help you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html">Now I believe that right intention is one of the more important parts of the eightfold path because if you don’t have right intention then all else fails in terms of freeing yourself from suffering.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sloth and Torpor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sloth-and-torpor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sloth and Torpor" /><published>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Sloth-and-Torpor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sloth-and-torpor/">&lt;p&gt;Sloth and Torpor is described as an unwholesome state whereby the mind is dulled, and it leads one into a thick and irritable depression. It is one of the 5 hindrances in Buddhism and is I think quite a significant hindrance for following the path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have suffered tremendously from Sloth and Torpor and yet I still amaze myself at the accomplishments in life that I have still been able to make, even with being under Sloth and Torpor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the reason why I have suffered and given way to Sloth and Torpor is due to me having an attachment to incarnation because we progress a lot quicker while incarnate and I just really want to progress towards God and as this blog proves (to myself) I have made considerable progress towards God. I guess my attachment towards progress towards God has caused me tremendous amounts of suffering in my life and its something I need to work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional approach to dealing with Sloth and Torpor is to contemplate death more and spend time understanding death because Buddhism sees that Sloth and Torpor is mostly caused by your relationship with death and attachment to death. The sad thing is – is that there is a heaven and life goes on and everyone has their own journey in life they go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you just give up on things and don’t enjoy life as much as you would like to because you are so focussed on death that you miss the present moment and don’t live your life how you would like to and just don’t actually live life and it caused me more suffering than anyone could ever know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realize that like if I were to die it would free me and I would become the person I was always destined to be. But that isn’t to say I actually want to die because it doesn’t achieve anything. I guess it really plays into this notion of what I think death actually is. I just envision it as nothingness which is a strong delusion and a delusion, I have been under for too long now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I haven’t entirely been truthful towards myself because there is something which has caused this state of Sloth and Torpor which I don’t actually recall, which is really unfortunate for me because I find myself in a state of Sloth and Torpor and it is related to this traumatic event in my life which was so traumatic, I don’t actually recall it and I am seeking help with this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html">Sloth and Torpor is described as an unwholesome state whereby the mind is dulled, and it leads one into a thick and irritable depression. It is one of the 5 hindrances in Buddhism and is I think quite a significant hindrance for following the path.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meditation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/meditation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meditation" /><published>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Meditation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/meditation/">&lt;p&gt;Meditation, prayer and service to man is of vital importance in making real progress towards God. I will talk a little about meditation and give you my basic technique which I have used for a few years now, which I have got from the Great White Brotherhood. If you would like to know why meditation is so important feel free to read The Great White Brotherhood’s article on the subject, in short you become a more devleoped human being - you develop your auras and allow your chakras to open up more and allow energy to pass more freely into them, you are also able to develop the gifts of the spirit over many years. The gifts of the spirit are telepathy, telekenesis, clairvoyance, clairsentience and teleportation. But you shouldn’t meditate with the goal of devloping the gifts - meditate with the intent on meditating and over time the gifts will appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly when you start meditating its best to choose a quiet place where you can not be disturbed by others and where there is little outside noise and distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly you should say a short prayer thanking God for his protection and thanking Angels and your guides for watching over you as you meditate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly you should visualise yourself using your hands placing a cacoon over yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you do these things then you should sit quietly ideally in a chair or a place of your choosing and then try to clear yourself of your thoughts as best as you can for about 15 minutes. Consistency is key with anything in life as with meditation, so you shouldn’t over exert yourself and spend longer in meditation than you need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you have finished 15 minutes of meditation, then you should send this energy which you have received from God out to the world - just imagine yourself sending out this energy is all you need do. Then thank Gods angels and your guides for watching over you and then imagine yourself lowering this cacoon that you had placed over you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aim to make meditation apart of your daily routine and you can meditate for longer and as frequnetly as you wish, but aim to be consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QRSlzULFWpM&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is the video from Bob Sanders who works with The Great White Brotherhood and &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreatwhitebrotherhood.org/lessons/meditation/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is an article on their website on how to meditate&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Meditation, prayer and service to man is of vital importance in making real progress towards God. I will talk a little about meditation and give you my basic technique which I have used for a few years now, which I have got from the Great White Brotherhood. If you would like to know why meditation is so important feel free to read The Great White Brotherhood’s article on the subject, in short you become a more devleoped human being - you develop your auras and allow your chakras to open up more and allow energy to pass more freely into them, you are also able to develop the gifts of the spirit over many years. The gifts of the spirit are telepathy, telekenesis, clairvoyance, clairsentience and teleportation. But you shouldn’t meditate with the goal of devloping the gifts - meditate with the intent on meditating and over time the gifts will appear.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking a Break From Spirituality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/taking-a-break-from-spirituality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking a Break From Spirituality" /><published>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Taking-A-Break-From-Spirituality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/taking-a-break-from-spirituality/">&lt;p&gt;I will outline why its so important to take a break from spirutality, especially in times when you feel you have had enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spirutal journey should be trod carefully and in good time. Most of the time people who are on their spiritual journey feel that they are doing God a disservice when they take a break from spirutality and spirutal work. But they should recognize that it is of their own choosing and God has patience with all his subjects because all roads lead to rome (so to speak). So don’t feel that you are doing God an injustice when you take a break from spirutality because the path should be trod as and when one chooses, but also in good time, so don’t feel the need to constantly push yourself to practice spirituality and let Gods angels guide you to be able to take a break from spirutality in a way that isn’t detrimental to your wellbeing, your mental health and your physical health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also when you take a break from spirutality you shouldn’t feel guilty about doing so and you should let your guides and your angels know of your decision to take a break from spirutality and it is of course your right to do so and you shouldn’t feel that you are letting God down in doing so because God gives all his subjects the right to tread the path as and when they choose, but also lets his subjects choose themselves as and when they should take a break from spirutality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I will outline why its so important to take a break from spirutality, especially in times when you feel you have had enough.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Law of Mutual Attraction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-law-of-mutual-attraction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Law of Mutual Attraction" /><published>2022-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Law-of-Mutual-Attraction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-law-of-mutual-attraction/">&lt;p&gt;The Law of Mutual Attraction is a univerisal law which quite simply means that like attracts like. A basic example is your own thoughts that you put out to the world you receive in return, so if you are having lots of negative thoughts, then the world will respond to that by attracting you to people of a similar nature in terms of people whom think like you, whereas if you are more positive, then the world will seem like a much brighter and better place. I feel we need more people in the world who are more optimistic about their circumstances and people whom are positive in nature and have good attitudes towards things because what you put out to the world - you receive in return. Feel free to also give my article on why giving to others is of vital importance &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovehumanity.gitlab.io/spiritual/Giving-To-Others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays the Law of Mutual Attraction is well known from places like YouTube Twitter etc, but that doesn’t take away the truth from this universal law. So the world will pick up on your own thoughts and send you back what you put in so to speak. But this law doesn’t just apply for your thoughts - it applies to everything in your life the people that you see in your life are a result of this universal Law of Mutual Attraction, when you change yourself you will be drawn to people who are similar to you in terms of the changes that you’ve made to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way its similar to karma - what goes around comes around. What you put out to the world is what you receive in return. I used to sulk all the time, because of something personal then the world will send me things to sulk about. But its not the way to go about getting what you want in life ever. People should strive to be loving to one another, strive to be happy and let go of the past, which I feel is a source of a lot of hurt for most people.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">The Law of Mutual Attraction is a univerisal law which quite simply means that like attracts like. A basic example is your own thoughts that you put out to the world you receive in return, so if you are having lots of negative thoughts, then the world will respond to that by attracting you to people of a similar nature in terms of people whom think like you, whereas if you are more positive, then the world will seem like a much brighter and better place. I feel we need more people in the world who are more optimistic about their circumstances and people whom are positive in nature and have good attitudes towards things because what you put out to the world - you receive in return. Feel free to also give my article on why giving to others is of vital importance Giving To Others</summary></entry></feed>