<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-16T08:37:12+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saint Christopher’s Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality. Here you will find articles on Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things. Here I also talk about Buddhism and a little bit about Psychology.</subtitle><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><entry><title type="html">Stop Using Social Media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stop-using-social-media/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop Using Social Media" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Stop-Using-Social-Media</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stop-using-social-media/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/social/social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Social media&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will be talking about why you should limit the time that you spend on social media platforms. Now in general most people need to admit to themselves that social media doesn’t really bring much benefit to them in their lives. Social media companies have designed algorithms which have been optimized to make the general public stay on social media for as long as possible to maximize their revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media in general also promotes a lot of negativity to the world and you have a lot of people doing terrible things on social media such as scamming, extortion, grooming, trolling, promoting hate, promoting racism, promoting gambling and all sorts of really negative things which contribute nothing but harm to our society and to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media also has a major impact on people’s mental health and makes people suffer because on Instagram and Snapchat when you always see your friends doing activities with others you feel lacking inside because you yourself are at home watching them enjoying life, so it promotes things like jealousy, hatred and negativity and doesn’t really promote any Christ like things such as peace, love and happiness, which is a shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the general public should limit the time they spend on social media platforms and ideally seek to remove it all together because it doesn’t help humanity and people’s own mental health which I think should be taken a lot more seriously in our society because social media in general actually promote mental illness by way of their algorithms which doesn’t benefit anyone long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, social media companies don’t have humanities best interests at heart because they censor certain opinions and ideas which hinder democracy and Governments around the world are complacent in that and its only until we as individuals start to stop using social media or at the very least limit the time in which we spend on these platforms because like I said it promotes things such as jealously and hurts our mental health. We should take to things such as meditation, prayer and service to God because it will lessen the power that evil has in the world and the evil that these social media companies bring to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, social media companies affect societies mental health, hurt our democracy, and do a lot of harm to the world and its only until we as individuals stop giving way to the temptation to constantly look at our phones every 5 minutes to look at Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, YouTube etc that we can begin to lessen the impact of the harm that these social media companies bring to the world. We as individuals should and need to take to things like meditation, prayer, and genuine service to God because it will bring a lot of benefit to the world and will further the power of God on earth. But if you feel that this is too much for you, then at the very least limit the time that you spend on social media, which will help your own mental health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-forgiveness/&quot;&gt;Self Forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/virtue-signalling/&quot;&gt;Virtue Signaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Pray for your Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop Watching the News</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stop-watching-the-news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop Watching the News" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Stop-Watching-the-News</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stop-watching-the-news/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/news/news.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;News&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news is something which I think only brainwashes the general public and is propaganda. Try finding an old news article and you will be hard find to find an article from three months ago on their own website and this really is how the news thrives by constantly filling the general public with absolute nonsense in what’s really happening in the world right now, because how reliable really are a bunch of overpaid journalists who don’t really care for the general public and who brainwash the public with false doctrines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my view we the people should take a stand in the content that we consume and consume only content which is beneficial for us which certainly isn’t the news which promotes these corrupt and backstabbing leaders we have in power who certainly do not know better than the general public and who don’t really care for each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content which I deem credible and worthy of consumption are independent sources from people with little financial interest who follow God and Christ. The news stations that we have in the world are certainly not following God and certainly not following Christ. Content that is reliable and credible books and articles/research papers on your field or independent blogs from genuine down to earth kinds of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news are corrupt organizations who lead the public astray and brainwash the general public into fear and fear then controls them. Of course, the news follows a formula of control as do the world leaders the formula is Problem, reaction, solution. They create a problem to sell us things which hinder out development as individuals for their own selfish reasons, which is an abomination to the concept of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We the people have put up for long enough with this brainwashing, and only until we as individuals begin to stop watching the news and start taking to things like prayer (praying for our leaders especially) and meditation and service to God will we be able to put a stop to this absolute madness that the news television promotes, and our leaders promote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, we the people need to understand that watching the news only bring our own downfall and the downfall of the world because the news doesn’t have our best interests at heart and they don’t portray the world as clearly as they should and we get filtered news and filtered by people who don’t care for us or our wellbeing, but only care about serving their masters who have their own doubtful ends. Therefore, avoiding the news is in my view everyone’s best interests because bad news sells, and it just promotes negativity which reduces the power of God in the world which is the power of love. It also affects your own mental health and we the people should be doing more to stop the news organizations and politicians from getting away with their crimes against the general public.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Concentration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-concentration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Concentration" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Concentration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-concentration/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/eightfold-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eightfoldpath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will be talking about Right Concentration. Which is one element of the eightfold path and one which I think if mastered will be very beneficial to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part in understanding right concentration or any element of the eightfold path is to understand why this makes us suffer. You first need to understand why not having Right Concentration at the right times and at the appropriate settings leads to suffering. To me Right means the correct level of concentration at the right times and when appropriate. But the key thing with all the elements of the eightfold path is to realize and appreciate why not having them leads to suffering, which I think is key in understanding and following Buddhism and the philosophy behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right concentration is heavily linked to right mindfulness because with right mindfulness you are able to appreciate as and when you are not concentrating on the task at hand and when you drift off so to speak. But like I said you need to understand why not having any one of the elements of the eightfold path actually leads to suffering, before you are able to fully appreciate why it is that not having that element actually leads to suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to meditate on why not having an element of the eightfold path leads you to suffering and spend some time in contemplation why it is that not having right concentration actually leads one to suffering, because it will help you and others immensely when you are able to focus on the task at hand and help you to reduce the suffering that you have. Seek to journal (a means of contemplation) why it is that not having right concentration leads to suffering, I also have an article on this blog why its important that people take up jouranling as a means of spiritual devotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-mindfulness/&quot;&gt;Right Mindfulness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-intention/&quot;&gt;Right Intention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-speech/&quot;&gt;Right Speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/sloth-and-torpor/&quot;&gt;Sloth and Torpor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-first-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The First Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-second-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The Second Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-third-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The Third Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/journaling/&quot;&gt;Journaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><category term="Right Concentration" /><category term="Noble EightFoldPath" /><category term="Noble Four Truths" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Veganism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/veganism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Veganism" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Veganism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/veganism/">&lt;p&gt;First, I encourage all those on the spiritual path to become vegetarian/vegan and see it as an act of obedience towards God. The reason why you should consider diet as important is because what you put inside your body has an effect on your wellbeing. When you eat only junk food and takeaways then it causes upset in your stomach and you become unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also just say that I have been vegetarian since mid 2018 and have been a vegan since 2020 March so I have good experience with being both and generally I would recommend being a vegetarian before going into veganism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But vegetarianism and veganism is showing respect for life because you show respect for the animals that are being slaughtered before their time to die and against their own wishes. It also goes against thou shall not kill which is one of the ten commandments because you kill the animals by eating them and you are the reason that they died before their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I agree that plants are also living, but plants have less sentience than an animal, so in a sense it’s the lesser of two evils that you eat plants than eat animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the DNA of an animal is very similar to that of humans and so it can be considered a form of cannibalism to eat animals because they are so similar to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also goes against thou shall not steal because animals should be free to live their lives as they chose in peace and harmony, instead we have a situation in the world where animals are bred in captivity, with no amount of love or affection and then they are slaughtered for the general public to enjoy as a meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you shouldn’t if you yourself vegetarian/vegan look down upon those who eat meat, but accept that they still believe in their hearts that it’s the right thing to do and so accept these people as you should all life and not condemn them or judge them but show respect for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the digestive tract of carnivores is short and so the food can be digested quickly, whilst the digestive tract for humans is long and so humans were never meant to be carnivorous, and meat contains toxins which actually harm the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, humanity will do well to become vegetarian/vegan because it will reduce the suffering that these poor vulnerable, defenceless creatures of God have had to put up with for so long. But you should only become vegetarian/vegan if you yourself believe in your heart that it is the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Vegan" /><summary type="html">First, I encourage all those on the spiritual path to become vegetarian/vegan and see it as an act of obedience towards God. The reason why you should consider diet as important is because what you put inside your body has an effect on your wellbeing. When you eat only junk food and takeaways then it causes upset in your stomach and you become unhealthy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Others Think of You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-others-think-of-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Others Think of You" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/What-Others-Think-of-You</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-others-think-of-you/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/think/think.png&quot; alt=&quot;think&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little about what other people think of you. This is something which I have struggled with a lot in my life and something I am sure that other people have struggled with a lot of their life. What other people think of you is always something subject to change and not everyone will have the same opinion on you, especially on places like social media where I have advertised this blog and where toxic people and behaviors thrive (generally I tend to ignore these people but try to see where they are coming from and leave them to their toxic behaviors because their behaviors don’t achieve anything and only cause upset to themsevles and the rest of the world through their negativity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now not following the crowd so to speak is something which so many people don’t do and it’s a real shame because people should be true to themselves and not just do things because of others, in the sense that their actions shouldn’t be defined by the opinions, judgements and beliefs of others or their perceived opinions, judgements and beliefs. Granted everyone should live by some sort of consensus, but in a sense, this takes away from people’s ability to truly be themselves, because you are just following the crowd and the crowd could and has been in the past very wrong in their own ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you should respect people’s own opinions and negative feedback, or opinions should be seen as feedback because in society you should present in a way appropriate for the situation and for the time and place. Which is important because you should respect others and this in of itself is a form of respect. So conformity to society is important, but its choosing when to be yourself and when not to be yourself that is important. But its also about respect for yourself and respect for others, because respect for yourself and respect for others should be equal and so you shouldn’t try to make others conform to your perceptions, beliefs or opinions in one single day because it takes for others to accept your different opinions, ideas, perceptions and beliefs, because in short when you are so different from the crowd it just doesn’t achieve anything and can make things worse for yourself in expressing your so different ideas, beliefs and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m really trying to say here is that you should choose wisely as and when to fight your battles and when to be true to yourself and when to express opinions, ideas and beliefs which are far out there so to speak because you shouldn’t undermine what other people think, but respect what others think and currently believe even if you know what they currently think and believe to be wrong and not based on reality. This is something which I have struggled with because to see so many people give way to deluded ways of thinking and deluded beliefs in things just hurts me a little inside because they are under illusion and it’s a real shame to see much of our society under an illusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence why it’s so important for humanity to be true to themselves at the right time and in the right circumstance because consideration should be taken into how the general public may react/respond/what they may think of you personally when you express beliefs, opinions, ideas, perceptions which are not in the general consensus because as I have found out to my own detriment you can’t show spirituality to the world when they are not ready for it especially the general public, but during times when people give me stick for my ads I run I just try to understand that they are still in an illusion so to speak and just are not ready for the light and so I seek to understand that it threatens their confirmed reality which they are subject to and then I seek to forgive them for they no not what harm it does to themselves (in terms of hindering their own growth and spiritual development) and forgive them for the fact that they have harmed others development in encouraging people to think like them and then forgive them for the offense that they may have caused me or intended to cause me had I not been what others may describe as an enlightened being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what this article is really about is that you can’t please everyone and you should pick and choose as and when it is appropriate to be yourself because you may or may not harm people in being the true you in the sense that it threatens others conformed beliefs and perceptions on things that they have so long held and so only brings harm to them and harm to yourself for the backlash that they give way to by denying the validity of you and that is certainly not what I stand for. I stand for love, peace, order and harmony between mankind and life in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the key think for most people because generally I tend to find that most will conform their behaviors, perceptions, beliefs and ideas on what others do is the courage to be yourself and the courage to be disliked, while choosing your battles so to speak on when the right time and when the wrong time to be yourself is, because being yourself at the wrong time can and does have a detrimental impact on the world and being yourself at the right times should have a long lasting and positive impact on you and the rest of the world. Granted how are you supposed to know when the right and wrong times are to be yourself, but I guess you should go off on others feedback is really the key thing and you can only base this on your own judgements in things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I do believe that being true to yourself is very important and being true should mean having your own beliefs, ideas, perceptions, and thoughts on topics and not just having these because of the crowd so to speak. Equally you should be mindful of the feedback that you receive when being true to yourself and when not being true to yourself but seek to work for the benefit of mankind and the benefit of yourself – but have these two things be of equal importance to you in your life. You should respect people’s opinions and beliefs even if you know them to be wrong because nobody on earth is perfect, but really pick your battles as and when to be true to yourself but work for the betterment of others in your choice of when to be true to yourself and when not to be true to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: This article was inspired by a user on Reddit by the name of /u/VentusTrash who spoke ill of my ad on Reddit, but please show him kindness and love for what he said because he inspired me to write this short article which I know will help others along their journey through life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="true to yourself" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good vs Evil</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/good-vs-evil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good vs Evil" /><published>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Good-vs-Evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/good-vs-evil/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/2020-12-20-Good-Vs-Evil/gve1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;gve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: That this article was changed on 14/03/22 to be much more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people will generally say that one person’s good is different to another person’s good - that good and evil are subjective. However, this isn’t accurate. Good are things that are constructive; things that build things. While evil are things that are destructive, things that unbuild things. Evil isn’t confined to just destroying others, it can be destructive behaviours to yourself, for example eating unhealthily. Equally constructive things are not limited to things you do for others, it’s also things you do for yourself, for example doing the work you need to do, so that you stop yourself from having to stress about it, eating healthier things such as fruit and vegetables (because when you eat healthy you feel better within your soul)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people because they don’t know what good and evil are, have negative, destructive habits and behaviours without any knowledge. You either work for the forces of chaos, or you work for the forces of construction. There is no in-between. As much as you can fool yourself into thinking that there is an in-between, there isn’t. Most people are asleep to this truth, and because of this by default they work for the forces of chaos without any realisation. Equally we shouldn’t look down upon those who are seduced by evil because they have a place in life as much as the people that work for good and people that choose evil have their own right to choose as do people that work for construction in this world, hence why its important that both groups order and chaos, don’t put any efforts to change either side because its disrespectful and shows that you don’t accept that they make up a part of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ask people what they want the world to be in the future, I most often get answers that amount to a world where there is world peace. With the idea being that it is in other people’s control if the world will be peaceful in the future. Failing to realise that each person is a part of the world. As Gandhi once said, “Be the change you wish to see in the world”. If you are a peaceful, loving person then this encourages others to be more peaceful and loving, if you are unkind, arrogant, and selfish then this encourages others to be unkind, arrogant and selfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I will say that in the world as of right now there is a heavy sway for people to work for the forces of evil through their jobs, their family environment, their social positions and evil is a part of life and we as a species should accept that people have a right to choose evil over good and we shouldn’t judge those who do and have chosen evil over good. But we should be true to ourselves, regardlness of if we are drawn to construction or deconstruction (good or evil) and like I said we shouldn’t try too hard to change people who work for the forces of construction or deconstruction, but should only try to help them if they see that the path they are on isn’t who they really are. But my advice would be to be more accepting that there are good and bad people in the world and that people, even good people like myself do bad things from time to time and we shouldn’t condem those actions out of hand, but seek to understand and forgive those who do commit sins to us and put efforts to turning the other cheek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, its ok to work for a boss who is evil and you shouldn’t think yourself better than him/her for not being evil like him/her and for not committing the same level of sins as them. But seek to be true to yourself would be my honest advice here in this article, but recognize that there are people who are very evil in the world and seek to recognize that there are people that are very good in the world. In life we have extremes on both ends. But just accept that this is apart of life and you will become a lot happier inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the forces of good and evil are very real in this world that we live in, but just seek to be true to yourself regardless of if you do what could be construed as evil because like I said in my article that I wrote on evil - its a very seductive power and you need to be in my view an advanced being to be able to resist the power of evil, but you need to understand why its wrong and that only comes through experience and isn’t something that you can do in a single day. Also don’t not make the mistake of underestimating how much you understand yourself. Don’t be arrogant. Analyse your motives behind your actions and behaviours and do this regularly. Seek to better understand yourself. If you don’t put the time and effort into understanding yourself no one will, but be true to yourself regardless of what others tell you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Note: That this article was changed on 14/03/22 to be much more accurate. Most people will generally say that one person’s good is different to another person’s good - that good and evil are subjective. However, this isn’t accurate. Good are things that are constructive; things that build things. While evil are things that are destructive, things that unbuild things. Evil isn’t confined to just destroying others, it can be destructive behaviours to yourself, for example eating unhealthily. Equally constructive things are not limited to things you do for others, it’s also things you do for yourself, for example doing the work you need to do, so that you stop yourself from having to stress about it, eating healthier things such as fruit and vegetables (because when you eat healthy you feel better within your soul) Most people because they don’t know what good and evil are, have negative, destructive habits and behaviours without any knowledge. You either work for the forces of chaos, or you work for the forces of construction. There is no in-between. As much as you can fool yourself into thinking that there is an in-between, there isn’t. Most people are asleep to this truth, and because of this by default they work for the forces of chaos without any realisation. Equally we shouldn’t look down upon those who are seduced by evil because they have a place in life as much as the people that work for good and people that choose evil have their own right to choose as do people that work for construction in this world, hence why its important that both groups order and chaos, don’t put any efforts to change either side because its disrespectful and shows that you don’t accept that they make up a part of life. When I ask people what they want the world to be in the future, I most often get answers that amount to a world where there is world peace. With the idea being that it is in other people’s control if the world will be peaceful in the future. Failing to realise that each person is a part of the world. As Gandhi once said, “Be the change you wish to see in the world”. If you are a peaceful, loving person then this encourages others to be more peaceful and loving, if you are unkind, arrogant, and selfish then this encourages others to be unkind, arrogant and selfish. However, I will say that in the world as of right now there is a heavy sway for people to work for the forces of evil through their jobs, their family environment, their social positions and evil is a part of life and we as a species should accept that people have a right to choose evil over good and we shouldn’t judge those who do and have chosen evil over good. But we should be true to ourselves, regardlness of if we are drawn to construction or deconstruction (good or evil) and like I said we shouldn’t try too hard to change people who work for the forces of construction or deconstruction, but should only try to help them if they see that the path they are on isn’t who they really are. But my advice would be to be more accepting that there are good and bad people in the world and that people, even good people like myself do bad things from time to time and we shouldn’t condem those actions out of hand, but seek to understand and forgive those who do commit sins to us and put efforts to turning the other cheek. Also, its ok to work for a boss who is evil and you shouldn’t think yourself better than him/her for not being evil like him/her and for not committing the same level of sins as them. But seek to be true to yourself would be my honest advice here in this article, but recognize that there are people who are very evil in the world and seek to recognize that there are people that are very good in the world. In life we have extremes on both ends. But just accept that this is apart of life and you will become a lot happier inside. In conclusion, the forces of good and evil are very real in this world that we live in, but just seek to be true to yourself regardless of if you do what could be construed as evil because like I said in my article that I wrote on evil - its a very seductive power and you need to be in my view an advanced being to be able to resist the power of evil, but you need to understand why its wrong and that only comes through experience and isn’t something that you can do in a single day. Also don’t not make the mistake of underestimating how much you understand yourself. Don’t be arrogant. Analyse your motives behind your actions and behaviours and do this regularly. Seek to better understand yourself. If you don’t put the time and effort into understanding yourself no one will, but be true to yourself regardless of what others tell you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Selfishness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/selfishness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Selfishness" /><published>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Selfishness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/selfishness/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/selfishness/coward.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Selfishness&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will write a little on selfishness, this is something which I have given away to so much in my life and I thought that hiding my own selfishness and disguising it under the guide of selfless acts was the correct thing to do – it was not. Sincerity of purpose is what in my eyes counts the most in this world, but also being true to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I’ve been selfish because I can be cowardly at times and I’m not afraid to admit it, because I lack courage and have lacked courage my entire life, but this is something which I am working on as I write this article. Its also because I am just scared, afraid of what others may or may not think of me – or part of me is. But oft times I put on a face, a face that I am strong when really I just hide the fact that I mask inside the fact that I’m just lonely and lack friendship in my life, because I’ve been an introvert a lot of my life, that’s not to say that I’ve lacked friends completely – I just haven’t had close friends, friends I can really trust and rely upon and who I am loyal to and friends who are loyal to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as a result of me being a coward I hide the way of the world from myself, and the way of the world could always be improved no matter how good things appear to look. I also choose to hide things from myself because there has been a lack of courage my entire life, but like I said I am working on this and it’s a positive that I am recognizing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I also don’t fully appreciate that choosing to not be scared/frightened at the appropriate times is extremely selfish because these granted negative emotions are there for a reason and they help us in life, because I delude myself in the sense that because I repress these negative emotions I don’t see the way of the world clearly, in the sense that there are very bad people in the world because I am a coward or part of me is and its both foolish to not respect the fact that there are very bad people in the world and its extremely selfish on the rest of the world do not respect that simple fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that my own pride, arrogance, and ignorance gets in the way a lot in regard to giving way to selfishness – as it does to many others in the world. But the only thing that can reduce things like pride, arrogance and ignorance is things like meditation, prayer, devotion to God, service to God etc. I guess I really need to reduce my own pride which has cost me and others a lot, but I intend to put right all those wrongs that I have caused to the world and especially to myself, by my own actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sad part about it is – is that I don’t actually quite realize most of my life when selfishness was playing a role but chose to hide it from myself a lot of the time because I didn’t want others to see me as a coward/frightened/scared, because I cared too much about what others think of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I should accept that these emotions are a normal part of life and are there to protect us in our lives which are a positive thing. But equally you should take the approach of 50/50. In the sense that you should hold a balance between both negative emotions and positive emotions and not take things to extremes which is something that I have done, which just wasn’t fair on myself or the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted this is still a work in progress for me in terms of reducing my own selfishness.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why You Should Read</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-read/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why You Should Read" /><published>2022-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Why-You-Should-Read</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-read/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/reading/reading.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reading&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will be talking about reading and why its so important for all to read this article to take up reading and have it be a part of your daily routine. Now reading doesn’t necessarily need to just be books that your read – it can also be reading about research papers in your relevant field, it can be reading articles, it can be reading blogs as you are doing right now – it isn’t only books that I encourage you to read, its any content that will bring value to you in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so inspired by the film Good Will Hunting and in the film the main character Will who was played by Matt Damon reads a considerable amount of books in his free time and there was one scene in particular which really did inspire me and that was when he was in the therapists room and he saw all the books on the shelves and he said that he read all the books on the shelves as if it was nothing to him. This amazed me and really encouraged me and inspired me to take up reading and have that be apart of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons why you should take up reading is because it allows you to become a more knowledgeable and sophisticated person and allows you to develop your vocabulary and allows you to know more about the world (especially if you are reading good books). But you should only read because you want to read – don’t read just because I say it here in this article, read because you want to read and only read the content that you feel drawn to and content that you are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading also in my view allows you to become a lot better and a lot more developed person because it allows you to have a much clearer picture on the world, especially if you are reading the correct content – I can not emphasis this enough, because why should you read a book from someone who has 1 year experience in x subject when you can read a book written by someone who has 30 years of experience and has worked at multiple different companies? Point being is you should be selective of the content that you consume and only consume content which is of high value from people who know what they are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another short point I just wanted to add here is that I believe that you shouldn’t read the news too often because the news has just become so heavily politicized especially with the virus always on the news and being spoken about. It just isn’t healthy for your mental health to constantly be watching the news every single day because bad news sells a lot more than good news and also how much value does the news really bring you in your life? Can you recall 5 articles that you read over the past month? I wager that most will say that they are not able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, only take up reading because you want to take up reading and become the best version of yourself and only consume content which you feel drawn to and content which is of high value objectively speaking from people who are good writers/experts in their fields etc, because it will allow you to in one book read from an expert and this is of more value in my eyes than reading 100 books from people with very little experience in a subject. You also shouldn’t read content just because they are the most popular – granted most popular does mean something, but you should read content which you believe will add value to you in your life and content which is of high quality. But its also about the fact that you shouldn’t just read what everyone else is reading because how unique are you really if you just read everyone else’s thing which they are reading?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Lifestyle" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Controlling Others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/controlling-others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Controlling Others" /><published>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Controlling-Others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/controlling-others/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/anger/anger1.png&quot; alt=&quot;anger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk about controlling others and this is something I see a lot of people get away with and people often have their own foolish justifications for this kind of behaviour where they are so controlling of other people. But generally, when we meet such people, we should aim to be forgiving of them for they no not what they do to others and themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, controlling others comes under the jurisdiction of evil weather the people that try to control others realize this or not. This is because to make someone conform to your beliefs or ways of thinking hinders the freedom of others and so it restricts things like soul growth and progress towards God and progress in spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, control over others bring about people’s suffering because you can’t control the actions of others truly because we all have free will. Granted the people that seek to control others think they are doing a good thing and getting away with what they do and seek to hide what they do when they control others because these kinds of people just want order, but in trying to control others and their ideas and beliefs and actions they just get disorder because the person being controlled doesn’t agree with these things because they don’t agree with it in their heart and so in subtle ways so things which undermine that control and I don’t think that people that try to control others through fear, anger, resentment, jealousy, envy etc realize that we all have free will weather they like it or not. Its also about how people have very subtle ways of seeking to control others which they themselves are not actually aware of – hence why it’s so important to be forgiving of these kinds of people, but generally these kinds of people will seek control over others because of how they falsely believe that others are the cause of their own suffering – when in fact this is not true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, it should be under the authority to those who are controlled or think they are being controlled unjustly to pray for those that seek to control them and make them conform to their own delusions, beliefs, ideas and make them take actions in things out of conformity because it is evil to seek to control others in this fashion. Also, you should assess why it is you conform to their control and perhaps take up journaling and write about why it is you think you conform to others control, is it out of compliance etc? Feel Free to read my article on this &lt;a href=&quot;/journaling/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; But those who do this shouldn’t be frowned upon and should be shown love, sympathy, compassion, understanding etc. Feel free to refer to my article on prayer. It also the duty of those who think they are being controlled to not allow themselves to be controlled because to allow yourself to be controlled by others in a way detrimental to you goes against thou shall not kill and thou shall not lie because you kill who you are and you lie about who you are to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also if you feel you are controlling others and suffer from this form of evil seek to take up prayer and pray to God or whoever you believe in and pray that you reduce this evil and this form of control that you seek to bring about in the world because it will reduce your own suffering immensely and make you much happier when you just let go of things and let go of your attachment to control others. Also I feel that meditation helps considerably in not being controlled by others because you just go deeper within and notice things alot more that are holding you back in terms of your own growth. I linked my article on this &lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, it’s in everyone’s best interests to avoid trying to control others because it will only bring about your own suffering because as I said we all have free will weather those with I’ll intent realize this or not. If you think you are being controlled by others seek to pray for them and you can find my article on prayer &lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; and those who think they are controlling others seek to pray that you reduce your evil ways because it will only bring about your own suffering trying to control others when you realize that things like fear, anger, jealousy, gluttony will only control people so much and people will disagree with you at times and so you can’t always get your way of control weather you like it or not and so will inevitably suffer from attempting to control others. Of course, we shouldn’t judge those who do seek to control others because they are lost in their ways of trying to control others when they are not able to because of free will, granted they may get some weak form of control, but they can never control others fully and so will inevitably cause them suffering and its up to those who seek to control others to change for their own benefit. Nobody can take that leap of faith so to speak for them, they have to do it themselves but praying for them will almost certainly help them to change for their own benefit and the world’s benefit. Feel free to give my article on Being Authentic and True to yourself &lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; which may help you if you think you are being controlled by others in ways detrimental to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/self-acceptance/&quot;&gt;Self-Acceptance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-compassion/&quot;&gt;Self Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-image/&quot;&gt;Self Image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-forgiveness/&quot;&gt;Self Forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/compassion/&quot;&gt;Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/sloth-and-torpor/&quot;&gt;Sloth and Torpor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/suffering-and-the-four-noble-truths/&quot;&gt;Suffuring and the Four Noble Truths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/black-and-white-thinking/&quot;&gt;Black and White Thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/know-your-limits/&quot;&gt;Know your Limits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/judgement/&quot;&gt;Judgement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Mindfulness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-mindfulness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Mindfulness" /><published>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Mindfulness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-mindfulness/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/eightfold-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eightfoldpath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about Right Mindfulness which is something which really does bring you out of suffering and is something which would say I have mastered. Right mindfulness should first come in recognizing that you are not your mind, which so many people in our society seem to believe that they are their minds, this is just untrue. We also have a society in which the monkey minds as Buddhists put it so eloquently in that our minds are on autopilot and often people don’t have much control over their minds because there are so many people who don’t bother to take up things like meditation which help them to come out of their monkey mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key aspect of mastering right mindfulness is you need to meditate because its only after much meditation that you are able to stop allowing your mind to run rampant or lessen the impact of the monkey mind. Feel free to give my article on meditation on the way in which I have been meditating for about 4 years now which you can find on this blog. It took me a long time of meditation to actually achieve right mindfulness, so please don’t be deterred if you are not able to achieve right mindfulness in a few weeks of meditation – it takes a long time in meditation to recognize why listening to our minds all the time cause suffering and a long time in meditation to be able to not allow your monkey mind to dominate your life as I have seen so many people have in their lives – which is unfortunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my general advice would be to spend more time contemplating on the noble four truths because the noble four truths are indeed the means out of suffering and everyone would do well in recognizing the great wisdoms that the Buddha has sent to us on earth. Which is a big promise that you can end your suffering, but it is true and has proven very true in my life. But of course, I am still learning and have a long way to go as do we all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right mindfulness also goes hand in hand with right concentration because you are able to concentrate that much better when you are able to be mindful and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I believe that right mindfulness is a very important part of the eightfold path and everyone that reads this should seek to meditate and contemplate a lot more on the noble four truths because they are indeed universal wisdoms that the Buddha has blessed us with on this earth and we would do well to adhere to his teachings because his teachings were a great blessing to us on this earth. I will soon be writing an article on misconceptions that people have on Buddhism to clear up some things which I feel we as a society has greatly misunderstood Buddhism and I feel that is partly due to how its taught in schools and how the media portrays it and how there is great emphasis on monks and the clothing used and how they shave their hair etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-intention/&quot;&gt;Right Intention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-speech/&quot;&gt;Right Speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/sloth-and-torpor/&quot;&gt;Sloth and Torpor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-first-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The First Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-second-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The Second Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-third-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The Third Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-concentration/&quot;&gt;Right Concentration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><category term="Right Mindfulness" /><category term="God" /><category term="Eightfoldpath" /><category term="Suffering" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>