<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-01-19T07:18:41+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chris’ Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality and other various stuff</subtitle><author><name>Chris</name></author><entry><title type="html">Patronizing Others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Patronizing-Others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Patronizing Others" /><published>2022-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Patronizing-Others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Patronizing-Others/">&lt;p&gt;Patronizing Others&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that one thing that has caused me suffering and many others suffering is patronization which is whereby you think that you are better than others and so in very subtle ways have behaviors which condescend them in someway. But its also about thinking that you can get the better of others in someway and you think that you are more intelligent than others which is quite arrogant because we are all equal and to patronize another isn’t in line with reality because you are not better or lesser than anyone or anything else. Everyone and everything is equal in the eyes of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To patronize is also to kill another’s confidence in themselves which goes against one of the ten commandments thou shall not kill. But I realized that I also patronize myself in a way which isn’t good for me to do that because we and everything is equal, but I just struggle to accept that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also find its important to call out patronization if and when someone does it to you because it affects your self-esteem when someone patronizes you in someway and you just accept it and think that the other person is better than you in someway because when you patronize another its puts them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should learn to have the courage to stand up to people whom patronize you in someway and learn to not judge those who patronize you in someway because we are all on our separate journeys. Just as a short note you shouldn’t think that you are more spiritually advanced than someone else because they still patronize. We are all far from perfect. You should be accepting of all life as all is one and to harm another is to harm yourself. Which took me a lot longer than it should have to realize that harming yourself isn’t good because its yourself that you are doing it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to understand people a lot more and be forgiving to those who patronize you and forgiving to those who judge you. But learn to be your own person and not allow yourself to patronize another and not allow yourself to be patronized by others, but stand up for yourself and what you believe. Not what others want you to believe. Become more mindful of your intentions and recognize more when you patronize others. Its in very subtle ways that people patronize you and you patronize others. But learn to be more understanding and forgiving of when people do this kind of thing because they don’t recognize the oneness of all of life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Patronizing Others</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rushing Spirituality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Rushing-Spirituality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rushing Spirituality" /><published>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Rushing-Spirituality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Rushing-Spirituality/">&lt;p&gt;Rushing Spirituality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that one thing that is holding me back a lot now that I am starting to see some results with my spiritual advances I feel the need to rush spirituality for more gains because I have been in the dark for so long now and given way to a lot of negative thoughts and been quite depressed and just felt so lost. But now that I am starting to see some results with spirituality I am willing to learn lot about myself a lot more because I can see that there are indeed significant gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one thing that I learned during my rush for spirituality is that it can damage yourself significantly if you are not careful, and so my advice would be to practice spirituality in your own time and at your own pace. Some people progress faster than others, while others progress slowly. But you shouldn’t judge how fast/slow someone progresses in their spirituality because its not a contest or a race, I guess one of the reasons I feel the need to rush in spirituality is because of fear of suffering and I realize that this is in part due to me not realizing the nature of suffering and that following the Buddha’s noble eightfold path is indeed the way out of suffering, because the Buddha is one of the great masters of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also the fact that I suffer from mental health difficulties is in part one of the reasons why I rush, because I worry too much about how others judge me, in part because I don’t accept that I have mental health difficulties because I’m too egotistical, arrogant, prideful to accept that I do have mental health difficulties. I feel like ego does get in the way sometimes, but I don’t often recognize it. Ego also affects my ability to trust other people, because I can be antisocial when I choose to be which does make me quite lonely and I feel a lot of people suffer from this similar thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I realize also is it should be about the journey that is of importance. I know its a little cliche, but that is true. But I don’t quite see that, or accept it as truth hence why I’ve been rushing spirituality out of fear of losing out on something (suffering).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, go at your own pace in spirituality and only practice spirituality if you do want to develop. You don’t have to practice spirituality if you don’t choose to and also its important to take breaks with spirituality when you feel the need to. But the gains that can be made are big.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Rushing Spirituality</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self-Worth</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Self-Worth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Worth" /><published>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Self-Worth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Self-Worth/">&lt;p&gt;Self-Worth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-Worth is something I have struggled with my entire life, I guess its like somewhat due to my personality flaws and how due to these flaws others don’t accept me as much because I kind of like think its right to put myself down in some way because of lack of acceptance of who I really am. Which I think equates to holiness in someway, but I realize its incredibly stupid and unfair on others and the rest of the world but its also important in the fact that you put yourself down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But its also like am I enough? When will I be enough? What makes someone enough? I guess its in part due to my lack of acceptance of myself, I guess in part due to my personality flaws which essentially mean that the people whom I interact with don’t respect me as much as I would like them to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own sense of humor gets in the way a lot of the time in my advancements towards God. But I’m quite arrogant and ignorant of that fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But its also I realized that I think others are better than me, or that they have more to offer than I do. But most don’t. I guess its in part due to self-confidence and confidence in yourself because I guess its something that I lack and need to work upon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which I guess plays into this flaw that is quite serious whereby I think sensitivity or being sensitive equates in someway to holiness in someway. But it definitely doesn’t because you essentially just become a slave to other people and are not fulfilling your own wants and needs. But I realize that you should seek to be true to yourself and not be a slave to others expectations of you. Its also about sticking to your guns in the face of adversary and your enemy and taking a stand against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I realized that I trust God, more than I trust myself. But the trust between yourself and God should be equal because all is one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also because I think it makes you humble in not recognizing your own achievements and accomplishments, but it isn’t – you just become devoid of the reality of your own worth to the world. Which is unfair towards yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also unfair to not accept your own talents and powers and skill and think that its selfish to give way to your own skills and talents, when it simply isn’t because it undermines your own self-worth and makes you think that you are powerless in the face of opposition, when you are not. Then it just makes you hate and despise yourself when you just take so much stuff from others and don’t stand up for yourself when you are perfectly capable of taking a stand and giving into your own skills and talents. Its also unfair on others and the world when you don’t give into your natural talents and gifts and it makes you look a fool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also hurts your self-esteem when you have such low self-worth. Having low self-worth also makes you doubt yourself, which then causes you to have low self-confidence and then it affects how others perceive you because when you are constantly doubting your decisions it just makes you appear weak when you are not. Having doubts also affects you ability to have beliefs about things based on reality. Due to stigma around mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess ultimately the reason I have given into so much self-doubt is mainly due to evil because evil makes you doubt yourself a lot and the solution to doubting yourself is to not care what others think of you and making someone doubt themselves goes against the 10 commandments of thou shall not kill because you are killing their confidence and ability to believe in themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Self-Worth</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Evil</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Evil/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Evil" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Evil</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Evil/">&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I will say here that evil is a very seductive power. You need to be an advanced being I believe to not be seduced by evil. But what most people who give way to this evil don’t actually realize is that evil is controlling their actions significantly more than they are controlling their own actions. I will also say that evil generally has this very red kind of energy that consumes the person and clouds their ability to see reality clearly because they are so consumed by this evil which in turn makes them very ignorant, arrogant, and selfish towards the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to say that nothing good can be achieved by giving way to evil. The only thing that evil brings is suffering to yourself and suffering to others through destruction. I also want to add that being so evil it removes any amount of sincerity that you may have had, evil also I feel brings out the more negative aspects which make us human for example arrogance, ignorance, neglect etc. I find that I can be very ignorant when I chose to be, which is quite selfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, when you give way to evil so much you thereby block more of the positive aspects to yourself such as the ability to feel more positive things, such as joy, happiness, love, sincerity because evil has so much power over you. You become someone you were never supposed to be. What is worse is that most evil people don’t recognize that evil has so much power over them which is limiting the power of God and limiting their positive emotions, they wrongly believe that they have control over evil and that evil gives them power. The power of God is a lot more powerful than the power of evil, but you need to open yourself up more to the power of God by reducing the very things that evil seeks to promote like pride, arrogance, ignorance, selfishness etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power of evil also attempts to undermine things that you think about yourself. Such as your own worth to the world, it seeks to put you in a corner and casts judgements upon you on the kind of person that you should be, it seeks to turn you into a fool, it seeks to make you doubt yourself, it seeks to make you experience mental suffering, emotional suffering, physical suffering. But what is worse is that those who use evil, will become so seduced by its power that the evil will actually turn on them and destroy them and their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also just wanted to add quickly is that when you are so influenced by evil you may notice what is known as throught block, which is where the power of evil actually is so powerful it prevents the thought coming through to your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, you should seek to pray to God each day that he keeps you from evil. Only the power of God keeps the power of evil away, nothing else can prevent the power of evil. If you yourself are able to see that you are being influenced by evil in someway pray to God that you reduce the power that evil has over, you and pray that you reduce the temptation it has over you. If you recognize that others are being influenced to do evil, seek to pray for them so that you can increase the power of God in the world and help to reduce the evil in the world and the suffering that’s in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updated 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that evil basically makes you doubt yourself a lot and destroys your mind and self-esteem. But evil makes you think that this is who you are. But you identify with whatever you choose to identify with, also people that are so consumed by evil don’t actually see that evil is harming themselves because all is one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When consumed by evil is makes it difficult for you to judge things for yourself and makes you doubt your own sanity, it also clouds your ability to receive more positive thoughts and more positive things, constructive things, and makes you identify with those evil thoughts and makes you think that the evil thoughts are your thoughts and the thoughts that you should have. Then it becomes difficult for you to judge if your thoughts are evil or good because evil has a form of power, but that power is nothing compared to the power of God. Therefore if you suspect that you are under the powers of evil you should seek to pray to God that he rids you of this evil - granted it is difficult to do this esepcially if you are so consumed by evil as I was. But the act of prayer in itself shows that you want to be rid of evil. But you need to mean it in your heart that you want to convert to the side of good and are willing to put efforts into yourself that you will change for the benefit of yourself and your fellow man because there is no fooling God, the rewards are very high for doing Gods work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True evil, true evil utlimately leads to mutilation of the self (in my case it was the holy spirit that was being mutilated, not my physical body), which is not good and I’m ashamed that I did such things to myself. Mainly because I didn’t see myself as myself which is an unusual sentence, but I had complete faifth in God that he was able to heal me if I do such things - which I now realize is not an excuse to do such things and is unfair on those working on healing me because I don’t want to see it and the damage done, but they are the ones that have to see it and are kind enough to heal such things, but its just ultimately unfair on them, but more importantly unfair on yourself. But its not just yourself whom you let down when you give way to evil and mutilation, but its also the people who care about you, which is unfair on them and unfair on yourself in letting them down. Another small point is that if you feel attracted to evil you shouldn’t devoid yourself of those experiences because you should only relinquish evil to the extent that you see the wrongness in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly when you are evil you essentially allign your actions with sin and will just do anything and everything to sin, which is not good because you are harming yourself when you hurt others because all is one. When relinquishing evil seek to be more mindful of when you are sinning and seek to be more mindful of your intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you know I feel that ultimately a lot of the issues that I have stem from my relationship with myself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">First and foremost, I will say here that evil is a very seductive power. You need to be an advanced being I believe to not be seduced by evil. But what most people who give way to this evil don’t actually realize is that evil is controlling their actions significantly more than they are controlling their own actions. I will also say that evil generally has this very red kind of energy that consumes the person and clouds their ability to see reality clearly because they are so consumed by this evil which in turn makes them very ignorant, arrogant, and selfish towards the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Impressing Others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Impressing-Others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impressing Others" /><published>2022-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Impressing-Others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Impressing-Others/">&lt;p&gt;Impressing Others&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk a little about my experiences with impressing others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that one thing that holds me back a lot in my progress towards God is impressing others, which is a little different to virtue signaling in my eyes. When you feel you need to impress others you just become a slave to other people’s opinions of you and don’t become who you want to be. I realized also that I somewhat don’t respect my own spiritual advances and so somewhat impress others with my decisions I take. But I wouldn’t say I outright try to use my advanced level of spirituality to impress others that much, but its just sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that to be your own person in life you need to let go of the fear of disappointing others and also you let go of the fear that others may suffer at your expense, but you should focus on the greater good in that regard, but this shouldn’t be used as an excuse to make others suffer at your expense. This worry of disappointing others in some regard has made me look a real fool to be honest and for some reason I equated it with godliness the act of impressing others and not disappointing others. But it just meant that people tried to use me for their own ends and I wasn’t standing up for myself, but also letting myself down, because in impressing others and trying not to let others down I just became someone that wasn’t who I truly was and wasn’t what I actually stand for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that you shouldn’t put efforts into impressing people who you don’t respect and people who don’t respect you and also that you shouldn’t care of the opinions of people whom you don’t respect. You should only care about impressing people whom you respect, because those are the people you should really care about impressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also feel like I just want to be praised which is why I want and care about other people’s opinions because I don’t accept myself as I am and feel that having others praise me will allow me to accept myself more, which is just not true. I should learn to accept myself as I really am and stop being so miserable and depressed all the time. The ironic thing is I don’t accept that I myself care about impressing others, so therefore I just hide it from myself the fact that I care about other people’s impressions of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will end by saying that the only person that you should be putting efforts to impress is yourself and God.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Impressing Others</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtue Signaling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Virtue-Signaling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtue Signaling" /><published>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Virtue-Signaling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Virtue-Signaling/">&lt;p&gt;I thought I would write a short peice on virtue signaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I think have been causing me to not do as well as I could be doing is due to virtue signaling. I tend to think that God is watching and so will do things that I think that God would want me to do and not things that I think are right in my heart. So I would essentially do things in attempts to impress God, which is very wrong to do because I am not being very real and authentic with myself. I guess its foolish to do such things because God doesn’t need his subjects to do any such virtue signaling to him or to anyone else for that matter. But God wants all his subjects to be very real with themselves. In terms of doing what they think is right/wrong. But the worst part about it all is that I was very unaware of when I was virtue signaling, I wasn’t very mindful of my own thoughts and actions and mindful of my own intentions, but I guess that the main reason that I did virtue signaling is because I was being boastful towards myself and kinda just hurting myself because I knew that virtue signaling brought dirtiness/death towards the soul because impressing others and God via virtue signaling is wrong and that you don’t even realize when you are virtue signaling and you then allign your actions with what will bring death to the soul, which is not fair or kind on yourself. The reason that I did this is because I knew that it was dirty to do something like this and brought death to the soul, because I didn’t see myself as an individual of the earth. I didn’t see that like I myself was a person to other people and ignored the positive effects that I have had on the world, which is a means of putting myself down. I had no respect for myself because I kept putting myself down because I wrongly believed that it was the right thing to do, I mainly did it out of worry of being hurt and going through more suffering in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose that the greatest irony about this article is the fact that I still give way to virtue signaling towards God, which is very wrong, but its a flaw that I would like to work on and hopefully remove fully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related to this is I feel like the relationship with myself could be a lot better. I feel that everyone should seek to develop a kind and loving relationship with themselves and who they truely are and also be true to themselves, and not do things to impress others but just be themselves, I guesss like related to that is that you shouldn’t seek to give into others expectations of you and not give into who others want you to be in life and not conform to what others want you to believe. But you should hold true to your own morals and beliefs and not worry about the damage that it may cause to others and the world. I also realized that its actually really evil to put someone down especially yourself and others around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also felt that other people were better than me in some way and didn’t see them as people, but didn’t see myself as my own person standing on my own two feet and taking action in terms of what I truely believe is right and wrong. But you know one thing I really have learned on my journey which I think is really important is to believe in yourself and your own abilities, but also to believe in others. 
God would also like all his subjects to have absolute faifth in him and God would reward those of whom are faifthful to him and punish those who are harming Gods kingdom by hurting themselves and others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I thought I would write a short peice on virtue signaling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking the Saw Dust out of Your own Eyes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Taking-The-Saw-Dust-Out-Of-Your-Own-Eyes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking the Saw Dust out of Your own Eyes" /><published>2022-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Taking-The-Saw-Dust-Out-Of-Your-Own-Eyes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Taking-The-Saw-Dust-Out-Of-Your-Own-Eyes/">&lt;p&gt;I realized that I haven’t been very truthful and honest and sincere towards myself and one of the reasons was because of ignorance, but also arrogance - I feel like the arrogance that I have towards myself and not practicing right intention which is 1 of the eight foldpaths were betraying me and letting me down so much in my life and I feel like I should learn to practice the eightfold path a lot more as I feel like it will bring a lot of peace and harmony to me in my life right now and feel like I should learn to tap into my feelings a lot more in terms of how I really feel deep down and learn that feelings are good things to have and are not in any way a weakness and that you shouldn’t repress your feelings because of others and what they believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been betraying myself and what I truely stand for. I’ve just been acting like a fool the entire time and I should learn to forgive myself for all that I’ve put myself through and learn to practice right intention and to practice mindfullness and to not give into arrogance or pride, but to show myself some respect and dignity for who I am truely. But I just wanted to make this quick blog about how important it is to before you go around putting efforts into helping other people, you first put efforts into helping yourself. As the very wise and great master Jesus put it once “You should take the sawdust out of your eyes”. Or as I like to put it you should put your gasmask on before you put the gasmask onto others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus also understood that you shouldn’t like go around teaching others things that they don’t wish to understand or as he put it do not throw your pearls before pigs, lest they trample them underfoot and turn to attack you. But this is also true of yourself, you shouldn’t put efforts to change too quickly too fast because otherwise you could damage yourself and also you should be willing to learn new things. Jesus also understood that you shouldn’t go around boating to others about your spiritual advances because you yourself are far from perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also about seeing things more clearly, because generally I find a lot of people live in their own worlds and no two people live in the same world and so everyone has their own reality to which they conform to and so sometimes people will live in alterantive realities which are delluding them from the truth and causing them considerable harm to themselves which isn’t good. I find that something I haven’t really been practicing is good intentions and I haven’t been very kind to myself because I guess in part because I was afraid of what people may think of me, which is very unkind towards myself because why should I care what others think of me, more than I care about what I think of myself, because its related to others in terms of because there are others that have opinions I care about what they think of me or may think of me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I realized that I haven’t been very truthful and honest and sincere towards myself and one of the reasons was because of ignorance, but also arrogance - I feel like the arrogance that I have towards myself and not practicing right intention which is 1 of the eight foldpaths were betraying me and letting me down so much in my life and I feel like I should learn to practice the eightfold path a lot more as I feel like it will bring a lot of peace and harmony to me in my life right now and feel like I should learn to tap into my feelings a lot more in terms of how I really feel deep down and learn that feelings are good things to have and are not in any way a weakness and that you shouldn’t repress your feelings because of others and what they believe.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Judgement</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Judgement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Judgement" /><published>2021-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Judgement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Judgement/">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make this short post today on judging others and yourself. I’ve suffered immensely because of all the judging that I have given to myself, all the times I felt like I’m unworthy or inadequate because of all the judging that I have caused myself. Its also caused me a lot of suffering thinking about how others will judge me or view me and I guess its mostly because of all the judging that I have given to myself and so I think that everyone else judges me the same way that I judge myself. But I realized that giving judgment to someone (including yourself) isn’t correct because of all this suffering that judging inflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I argue that to judge someone is actually a form of evil because of the suffering that it is likely to cause and it causes people to believe that they are constantly being judged by others which causes them a lot of suffering. In light of this, I feel its very important to put efforts to reduce the judgment you give yourself and the judgment that you give to others because of all the suffering that it is likely to cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important point that the Buddha made when he was on earth (which I got from this awesome book Why Buddhism is True by Robert Wright) was that the less you judge things – including the contents of your mind – the more clearly you’ll see them, and the less deluded you’ll be. In judging, you are essentially implying that your way of seeing things is the correct way of seeing things and is the correct reality – when that is not the case. But I think what the Buddha was saying was that the less judging you are to things, the more in line with reality you will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, judging myself or worrying how others will judge me has caused me a lot of suffering in my life and I realize now that you shouldn’t judge yourself or worry how others will judge you. Put efforts to if others judge you in some way not allow there judgment of you to cause you suffering. Let God be the judge of those that judge others. Its also important to not seek vengeance on those that caste judgment to you, but its also important to show those that have been judged by others unfairly compassion, understating etc. Then its also important to show those that have judged others forgiveness in what they do because I feel like the people that judge others a lot don’t quite realize the suffering that they are causing to others and you know the reason that people judge others is because on some level they themselves feel like they are being judged in some way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I wanted to make this short post today on judging others and yourself. I’ve suffered immensely because of all the judging that I have given to myself, all the times I felt like I’m unworthy or inadequate because of all the judging that I have caused myself. Its also caused me a lot of suffering thinking about how others will judge me or view me and I guess its mostly because of all the judging that I have given to myself and so I think that everyone else judges me the same way that I judge myself. But I realized that giving judgment to someone (including yourself) isn’t correct because of all this suffering that judging inflicts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Becoming a Child</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Becoming-a-Child/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming a Child" /><published>2021-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Becoming-a-Child</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Becoming-a-Child/">&lt;p&gt;I realized recently that perhaps one of the biggest hindrances to my growth is my own arrogance, ego, ignorance, pride and evilness (which I intend to make a separate blog post about). The answer to overcoming these issues that hinder me so much is so become like a child again as Jesus described it. What this really means is that you become more accepting of things that you may otherwise disagree with and put efforts in reducing things like your arrogance, pride, ego, ignorance etc because as a child you realize that you don’t know it all and so are more willing to accept different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I also realized is that my cup was full, in terms of all the things that I had incorporated as part of me, arrogance, pride, choosing to be ignorant etc. This meant that I wasn’t as easily willing to accept certain things; I.e things that may be beneficial for me, but would hurt my pride and so not being like a child hindered my spiritual progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I made the analogy that everyone has their own cup of water which represents all the things that make up who they are and what they incorporate into themselves. Generally most people’s cups are full and so they already have a lot of things incorporated into them, but its unfortunate that most of those things are things that hinder progress, I.e arrogance, pride, ego, ignorance, evil etc. Therefore, its important to put efforts to emptying your cup so to speak so that you can remove all these things that are hindering your progress and so that you can become more like a child again so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my personal experience, I already was aware of Jesus saying you should become like a child again to progress towards God, but never fully grasped its significance until I had first hand experience at how much my own ways were hindering my progress and realizing that the only way to overcome these things was to accept that I don’t know it all and become more like a child (or put efforts to become more like a child). In doing this it allows me to open myself more to new possibilities and empty my cup of water some more to that I can remove it of these things that were hindering my progress and add better, more holier things in my cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, its very important to become more like a child again so that you can further progress towards God and progress in spirituality. In putting efforts to become more like a child again it will allow you to empty your cup more and allow you to more easily remove things like arrogance, ignorance, pride, selfishness, evil etc. I also realized that growth in spirituality is very much just a process of becoming less ignorant of the reality of things. I also want to add here that you can put efforts to become more like a child at any age, even if you are elderly – its never too late to make progress in spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I realized recently that perhaps one of the biggest hindrances to my growth is my own arrogance, ego, ignorance, pride and evilness (which I intend to make a separate blog post about). The answer to overcoming these issues that hinder me so much is so become like a child again as Jesus described it. What this really means is that you become more accepting of things that you may otherwise disagree with and put efforts in reducing things like your arrogance, pride, ego, ignorance etc because as a child you realize that you don’t know it all and so are more willing to accept different things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journaling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/wellbeing/Journaling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journaling" /><published>2021-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/wellbeing/Journaling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/wellbeing/Journaling/">&lt;p&gt;In this very short post I will talk about the importance of journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journaling is something which I picked up about 2 years ago and has been an amazing resource for me to analyze myself daily. In my view analyzing yourself is an important aspect of following the spiritual life because it forces you to recognize more of your bad habits/behaviors that you have and so allows you to think over how you can improve yourself because without analyzing yourself daily you will not be able to identify your faults/flaws that you have and so will hinder your progress. Therefore journaling is an important thing for you help to improve yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a garden and I will often times of an evening go out and journal about my day which I find quite therapeutic to write about my day in my journal, because I think its important for each person to feel understood and journaling is a means to achieve that. It also gives some time for me to reflect on my day and explore areas in myself that need improvement and what I can do to improve myself. The main reason I didn’t start a diary/journal sooner was because I had a fear that my enemies/relatives would read it and use it to my own disadvantage, but I later realized that I should go ahead with it because there is more to be gained from it than potential disadvantage it brings me if someone reads it and to be honest I want my journals to be like a testament for my life so that I can be better understood in my actions and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally the format of how I write in my journal is the following; First make an entry with date:time then write about what I did that day/ past few days, how I feel about those things and then write about anything else that comes to my mind and then I will end the entry with a direction/goal of what I think will help me to improve and become better and where I want to be headed. Generally this format has really helped me and journaling in itself has given me a massive opportunity to really consider the direction I want to go in with various things which has benefited me massively. I feel like a lot of people are lost these days in things such as social media and they really don’t know in which direction they go – with journaling it gives an opportunity to really consider and understand yourself and figure out which direction you want to take in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have also been many great people who used journaling as well as I have some notable people that kept their own journals are; Charles Darwin, Thomas Edison, Leonardo da Vinci, Benjamin Franklin, Albert Einstein, Thomas Jefferson, Nikola Tesla, Lewis Carroll, John Adams, Emma Watson and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude this short post; you should keep a journal for its therapeutic benefit, the improvement it will bring to you spiritually through analyzing yourself, the improvement it will bring to you emotionally because it will help you to become more mindful of your feelings and thoughts that you have and so will allow you to overcome negative feelings and thoughts that you may have towards things. I have also laid out my general format for filling my journals which I hope will bring some benefit towards you in thinking about how to format your journals. Great people have also understood the importance of journaling and so I encourage all who read this to take up journaling and begin to analyze yourself daily through writing in your journal and it will allow you to improve yourself and become better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">In this very short post I will talk about the importance of journaling.</summary></entry></feed>