<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-28T08:33:01+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Light’s Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I write stuff that may interest others</subtitle><author><name>Light</name></author><entry><title type="html">Becoming a Child</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Becoming-a-Child/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming a Child" /><published>2021-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Becoming-a-Child</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Becoming-a-Child/">&lt;p&gt;I realized recently that perhaps one of the biggest hindrances to my growth is my own arrogance, ego, ignorance, pride and evilness (which I intend to make a separate blog post about). The answer to overcoming these issues that hinder me so much is so become like a child again as Jesus described it. What this really means is that you become more accepting of things that you may otherwise disagree with and put efforts in reducing things like your arrogance, pride, ego, ignorance etc because as a child you realize that you don’t know it all and so are more willing to accept different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I also realized is that my cup was full, in terms of all the things that I had incorporated as part of me, arrogance, pride, choosing to be ignorant etc. This meant that I wasn’t as easily willing to accept certain things; I.e things that may be beneficial for me, but would hurt my pride and so not being like a child hindered my spiritual progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I made the analogy that everyone has their own cup of water which represents all the things that make up who they are and what they incorporate into themselves. Generally most people’s cups are full and so they already have a lot of things incorporated into them, but its unfortunate that most of those things are things that hinder progress, I.e arrogance, pride, ego, ignorance, evil etc. Therefore, its important to put efforts to emptying your cup so to speak so that you can remove all these things that are hindering your progress and so that you can become more like a child again so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my personal experience, I already was aware of Jesus saying you should become like a child again to progress towards God, but never fully grasped its significance until I had first hand experience at how much my own ways were hindering my progress and realizing that the only way to overcome these things was to accept that I don’t know it all and become more like a child (or put efforts to become more like a child). In doing this it allows me to open myself more to new possibilities and empty my cup of water some more to that I can remove it of these things that were hindering my progress and add better, more holier things in my cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, its very important to become more like a child again so that you can further progress towards God and progress in spirituality. In putting efforts to become more like a child again it will allow you to empty your cup more and allow you to more easily remove things like arrogance, ignorance, pride, selfishness, evil etc. I also realized that growth in spirituality is very much just a process of becoming less ignorant of the reality of things. I also want to add here that you can put efforts to become more like a child at any age, even if you are elderly – its never too late to make progress in spirituality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I realized recently that perhaps one of the biggest hindrances to my growth is my own arrogance, ego, ignorance, pride and evilness (which I intend to make a separate blog post about). The answer to overcoming these issues that hinder me so much is so become like a child again as Jesus described it. What this really means is that you become more accepting of things that you may otherwise disagree with and put efforts in reducing things like your arrogance, pride, ego, ignorance etc because as a child you realize that you don’t know it all and so are more willing to accept different things.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Journaling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/wellbeing/Journaling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Journaling" /><published>2021-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/wellbeing/Journaling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/wellbeing/Journaling/">&lt;p&gt;In this very short post I will talk about the importance of journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journaling is something which I picked up about 2 years ago and has been an amazing resource for me to analyze myself daily. In my view analyzing yourself is an important aspect of following the spiritual life because it forces you to recognize more of your bad habits/behaviors that you have and so allows you to think over how you can improve yourself because without analyzing yourself daily you will not be able to identify your faults/flaws that you have and so will hinder your progress. Therefore journaling is an important thing for you help to improve yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a garden and I will often times of an evening go out and journal about my day which I find quite therapeutic to write about my day in my journal, because I think its important for each person to feel understood and journaling is a means to achieve that. It also gives some time for me to reflect on my day and explore areas in myself that need improvement and what I can do to improve myself. The main reason I didn’t start a diary/journal sooner was because I had a fear that my enemies/relatives would read it and use it to my own disadvantage, but I later realized that I should go ahead with it because there is more to be gained from it than potential disadvantage it brings me if someone reads it and to be honest I want my journals to be like a testament for my life so that I can be better understood in my actions and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally the format of how I write in my journal is the following; First make an entry with date:time then write about what I did that day/ past few days, how I feel about those things and then write about anything else that comes to my mind and then I will end the entry with a direction/goal of what I think will help me to improve and become better and where I want to be headed. Generally this format has really helped me and journaling in itself has given me a massive opportunity to really consider the direction I want to go in with various things which has benefited me massively. I feel like a lot of people are lost these days in things such as social media and they really don’t know in which direction they go – with journaling it gives an opportunity to really consider and understand yourself and figure out which direction you want to take in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have also been many great people who used journaling as well as I have some notable people that kept their own journals are; Charles Darwin, Thomas Edison, Leonardo da Vinci, Benjamin Franklin, Albert Einstein, Thomas Jefferson, Nikola Tesla, Lewis Carroll, John Adams, Emma Watson and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude this short post; you should keep a journal for its therapeutic benefit, the improvement it will bring to you spiritually through analyzing yourself, the improvement it will bring to you emotionally because it will help you to become more mindful of your feelings and thoughts that you have and so will allow you to overcome negative feelings and thoughts that you may have towards things. I have also laid out my general format for filling my journals which I hope will bring some benefit towards you in thinking about how to format your journals. Great people have also understood the importance of journaling and so I encourage all who read this to take up journaling and begin to analyze yourself daily through writing in your journal and it will allow you to improve yourself and become better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">In this very short post I will talk about the importance of journaling.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">People’s Expectations of You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/peoples-expectations-of-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="People’s Expectations of You" /><published>2021-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/peoples-expectations-of-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/peoples-expectations-of-you/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk a little about other people’s expectations of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not meeting other people’s expectations of me has caused me a lot of pain and suffering and its actually only recently I realized that its not the other person’s expectations I’m not meeting but its what I think there expectations are of me and not meeting them which causes me that pain and suffering. There is a subtle difference. I make an assumption on what others expect of me and when I feel I haven’t or don’t meet that expectation then it causes me great pain and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But  I realized that you can’t be a slave to other people’s expectations for you, because how free are    you really if you limit yourself to what other people expect of you and try to always follow other people’s expectations? People often have a view – a  label or a box to put you in so that they can better understand how to behave around you, but their view/label of you isn’t reality. You should focus on yourself and leave people to have their opinions and expectations and views of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry if you haven’t or don’t meet the expectations of others. What gives their expectations of you higher priority than your own expectations of yourself? Also just know that you will never be able to meet everyone’s expectations for you. One person may expect you to be x while other people expect you to be Y and Z, so therefore you shouldn’t aim to meet expectations of others. As in meeting other people’s expectations that they have of you shouldn’t be the end goal. In fact I argue that you shouldn’t even concern yourself with the expectations others have of you because like I said you should only care about the expectations that you have of yourself. But even then I would advise to have low expectations for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, don’t make following the expectations that others have of you be the goal because it limits the freedom you have to be the person that you want to be and not the person that others want you to be. A good analogy of this is; a tree can be perfect for the bird that uses it as a nest, or it can be perfect for the person cutting the tree down for the raw material, or it can be perfect for the apples it produces, or even perfect for the shade that it provides people, but a tree doesn’t strive to be perfect according to other people’s wants/needs – a tree strives to be perfect according to what it perceives as perfect. Applying this to expectations people have of you is that everyone will have different expectations of you, but you shouldn’t concern yourself with those expectations that they have and should strive to meet your own expectations and be perfect according to yourself and being the person that you want to be - not the person that other people want you to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will just end by saying that the only person’s expectations who you should be trying to meet are your own expectations of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk a little about other people’s expectations of you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pray for your enemies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Pray-For-Your-Enemies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pray for your enemies" /><published>2021-10-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-10-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Pray-For-Your-Enemies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Pray-For-Your-Enemies/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will look at the importance of praying for your enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me first start by saying that there are always two forces at place in life. The forces that work for good and the forces that work for bad or evil. Now the forces that work for bad or evil are the forces that we should pray for because they have succumb to evil and are actively working to bring harm and mayhem throughout the world, these are people that hold positions of power as these positions allows them to harm as many people as possible, so these evil people hold positions as bankers, politicians, religious leaders, trade unionists, business leaders, people that work in Government such as civil servants, education leaders etc. It is our job as good people to send the power of God to these people through the act of prayer. I also wanted to just note that those who are not spirtualy awake generally tend to work for the forces of evil as they are asleep in a spiritual sense. You either work for the forces of evil, or you work for the forces of good in the world. There is no in-between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technique that I use to pray for bad/evil people is to visualize the harm they are causing the world and pray to God in simple language or express the prayer via thought for them to be helped for their benefit and for the world’s benefit. There are no ill thoughts when praying for bad/evil people because to do so would act for the forces of evil. When we pray for them we do so for their benefit and for the world’s benefit. If by result of pray they lose their power and are seen for who they truely are then so be it. Short term ramifications for them may be seen as bad by them and they may despise you for some time, but it would be for their own benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to share the story of the Bible of David and Goliath and the hidden meaning behind this story because it relates to this. This interpretation is taken from the book the stairway to freedom. The story goes that two armies oppose each other on a battlefield, the Philistines are the bad guys, while the Israelites are the good guys. The Philistines have a giant on their side called Goliath who terrifies the Israelites. So the king of Israel asks a shepherd named David to help the situation. David puts a stone in his sling and throws it at Goliath, the stone finds a chink in Goliath’s Armour and kills him. The Israelites are then victorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Philistines are actually the people around us that try to destroy our happiness and peace in order to profit for themselves such as bankers, politicians, business leaders, religious leaders etc and so Goliath is the embodiment of those bad vibrations within these kinds of people. The Israelites represent all ordinary good hearted people. In the story the king od Israel is actually God. David represents you and me - just ordinary people. So David speaks to the King Saul (this means that we meditate and pray to connect with God). Through prayer and meditation we are given the arm, the power of God. The stone that David projects towards Goliath implies that we pray for our enemies and through that act we direct the mighty force for good which is God towards those who would harm reducing the evil people’s power to harm us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of David and Goliath simply means that through our connection with God, we are able to, by the act of prayer and meditation and service to our fellow man render powerless those evil people that would harm us. In doing this we work to reduce the evil in the world and help to make the world a better place, more beautiful place. It was the aim of Jesus to bring light into the world and to make the world a better place and so it should be the aim of everyone that reads this to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, its important that each and every one of us begins to pray for our world leaders, the bankers, the politicians, the business leaders, the religious leaders, trade union leaders etc. So that we can reduce their evil on the world and help to bring about a better world for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short article I will look at the importance of praying for your enemies.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Positive Thinking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/Positive-Thinking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Positive Thinking" /><published>2021-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-09-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/Positive-Thinking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/Positive-Thinking/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will look at the importance and value of positive thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positive thinking is the practice whereby you seek and actively go out of your way to see the positive in things, but more importantly is that you don’t dwell on the negative side of things and try to be as positive as you can about life in general. This is especially important when life has you down, because there is little use in being down and dwelling so much on the negatives, you should focus more on the positive aspects. Its a skill that is learned and is a skill that I have recently started to pick up, but have not yet mastered, so take what I say as just someone who is still learning how to be positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With positive thinking is pushes you to not give into negative thinking and encourages you to change your beliefs on things that cause you to be in a negative state. It also forces you have a healthier outlook on life. Being postie all the time makes you become a happier person because with looking for the positives you appreciate and accept that its not all so bad and that there are good things in life. Becoming a happier person is 100% beneficial towards you and allows you to better deal with problems, because being unhappy and negative you are more likely to struggle with problems and so give up on a problem more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being positive is closely linked to gratitude, but is different in that with gratitude you are appreciating what you already have, being positive is changing your outlook to a more positive one. You should seek to practice both being positive and gratitude. Please refer to my article on &lt;a href=&quot;/wellbeing/spiritual/Gratitude/&quot;&gt;gratitude&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life brings many challenges to everyone, some challenges are harder than others and you may make mistakes from time to time, but see them for what they are mistakes, because you can’t change your past mistakes, but you can change your outlook towards them now. Seek to change your outlook on your past mistakes and you will become a happier person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key thing with being positive is that you don’t focus so much about the negative side of things, but trying to be positive in your outlook towards things. A basic example of changing your outlook may be that you couldn’t meet with some friends on a weekend, but the positive was that it gave you more time to work on an assignment and you focus on this rather than dwelling on the fact that you were unable to meet with your friends. Another basic example is you failed in an exam, having failed it now gives you an accurate perception of your gaps in knowledge and so is a positive because it allows you to study more on those gaps in your knowledge so that you can become better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will leave on a pleasant talk by a Buddist monk who gave a talk being positive link is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=goo2IMA-nBw&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will look at the importance and value of positive thinking.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Practice Spirituality in Secret</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Practice-Spirtuality-in-secret/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Practice Spirituality in Secret" /><published>2021-09-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-09-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Practice-Spirtuality-in-secret</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Practice-Spirtuality-in-secret/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will give some reasons and justifications why those on the spiritual path should do so in secret and not announce it to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason why the path should be done so in secret is because generally people dislike someone standing in the light because they are immersed within the grand illusion of this world and so seeing someone in the light threatens the reality into which they conform to and so they will use whatever means they have at their disposal to hurt and discredit you. Therefore, the advice that is generally given to those on the path to freedom is to do so in secret in quiet and peace. Jesus said a similar thing and told people whom he brought light to to not tell anyone. For example in the sermon on the mount Jesus said “Do not give dogs what is holy, and do not throw your peals before pigs, lest they trample them underfoot and turn to attack you”. What he was suggesting was to not throw pearls of wisdom to those of whom are not ready for it because otherwise they may turn and attack you and hurt you. But for those following the path I would recommend you study what Jesus taught because he was a spiritual master and was and is on the path towards God, his sermon on the mount and the 10 commandments are a good starting point for studying Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason why the spiritual path should be trod on in secret is because the focus should be on following the spiritual path in seriousness and sincerity, not promoting and boasting to others of your achievements and doing it for the “fame” reasons, because this will deter you from actually following spiritual path. Let others have their opinions and judgments of you and carry on following the path in secret and leave them to have their judgments of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly the final reason why you should follow the spiritual path in secret is because the spiritual journey that you go in is personal to you. Everyone has a different journey that they go on, no one two people go on the same journey. What you found changed you for your benefit, may change another person and have the same impact as another person. Therefore you should follow the spiritual path as you can in peace and quiet. Jesus himself even said that you should pray in secret to God, give to charity in secret so that “fame” reasons don’t deter you from actually following the path, because some people follow the path and give to charity so that they may be seen and to have credit towards them. Don’t let this apply to you. Follow Jesus’s teachings and pray in secret and give to charity what you can afford in secret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note the general advice is to share your knowledge of the spiritual path to only those of whom are seekers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bruderhof.com/en/topics/the-sermon-on-the-mount&quot;&gt;https://www.bruderhof.com/en/topics/the-sermon-on-the-mount&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christianbiblereference.org/jteach.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.christianbiblereference.org/jteach.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thestairwaytofreedom.org/get-the-book/&quot;&gt;https://www.thestairwaytofreedom.org/get-the-book/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will give some reasons and justifications why those on the spiritual path should do so in secret and not announce it to others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Showing Respect and Love to God and his Kingdom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Showing-Respect-and-love-to-God-and-his-kingdom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Showing Respect and Love to God and his Kingdom" /><published>2021-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Showing-Respect-and-love-to-God-and-his-kingdom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Showing-Respect-and-love-to-God-and-his-kingdom/">&lt;p&gt;Showing respect and love to God and his kingdom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will outline some things which I think are quite important in showing respect and love to God and his kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I think is quite important in showing respect and love to God and his kingdom is to show kindness, understanding, forgiveness, love, compassion, and respect to all of Gods creation regardless of who or what they are. This could be paying respect to a flower by providing it water, this could be forgiving someone that did wrong by you. It could also be paying respect to the planet by recycling your bottles and tins etc. This also applies to yourself because whether you like it or not you are apart of Gods kingdom, therefore treat yourself with the same amount of love and respect as you would God. Everything and everyone have a place in Gods eyes and everything and everyone is equal according to God. Who are you to say otherwise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that is quite important to showing love and respect to God and his kingdom is to not give way to dark, evil, bad thoughts because you may hide such thoughts from your colleagues and family, but you will not be able to hide such thoughts from God. Also related to this is to not give way to unhappiness and misery because you are blessed with the life that God has given you and so should strive to be happy and cheerful as a show of thanks towards God for the life that he has given you, because he could have chosen to not create you but he did out of pure selflessness, the least you can do is to show thanks by striving to be as happy, joyful and cheerful as you can possibly be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prayer and meditation is another thing which is important for paying respect to God and his kingdom because through meditation and prayer you can begin to build a relationship with God and also lessen the effects of ego which is dispositions and thoughts related to yourself, in other words thinking for yourself and not for others. Which is important to realize that it’s not all about you – there are other people in your life that are affected by your actions. Related to this is providing some kind of service to humanity, this could be through your job, through writing blog posts to spread your knowledge to the world, this could be helping your parents with household work etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly another means of showing love and respect towards God and his kingdom is by having faith that God will regardless of the circumstance provide for you, and this is something that I have personally struggled with because its difficult having faith that God will provide when things really are bad, in that it requires a lot of faith in God to go through hardship and difficult situations. Which is why its important in my opinion to when things don’t go your way to not see it as a bad thing because ultimately you don’t know if its really a bad thing as you can’t see into the future, equally you don’t know if a good thing is a good thing because you can’t see into the future. Point being is that you shouldn’t get let down when things don’t go according to the way you would like them to, just see them as blessings in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recommend that you follow the 10 commandments as these are principals that have been understood by the wisest amongst us and should be followed. With “thou shall not kill” also seek to understand the true meaning behind it, when you put someone’s idea down are you not killing their ambitions? Are you not killing their confidence to build things from their ideas? I leave you to ponder the full meaning behind “thou shall not kill”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Showing respect and love to God and his kingdom</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Faults</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/spiritual/Faults/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faults" /><published>2021-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/spiritual/Faults</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/spiritual/Faults/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk a little bit about faults or flaws. Quite simply a fault or flaw is something that isn’t perfect or is hindering you in some way. An example of a fault could be self-sabotage, which in my opinion a lot of people have this flaw in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on your flaws is in my opinion a fundamental aspect of following the spiritual life. We all have flaws every one of us, we may have flaws which affect us to a great extend such as in my case one of my flaws was when things don’t go my way I would make myself feel unhappy as a means of detesting the fact that things hadn’t gone my way or I would think that things are a total disaster and think that they will always be a disaster and really lingering on these thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody has different flaws; no two people will have the same flaws. We have personality flaws, social flaws, flaws with our thought processes, flaws with our beliefs. In every aspect of life there are flaws. But what is important is to identify flaws as best as you can, because as the Lao Tzu says in Tao Te Ching “When you identify a fault as a fault, can you no longer be with that fault” All this is quote is saying is that you first need to be able to identify a fault before you can seek to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The means to remove a fault is fairly simple. To remove a fault you should send out a prayer to have that fault removed and then throughout your day anytime you notice that fault occurring you do your best to reject the fault, hence you need to engage in right mindfulness to be able to identify when you engage in this fault, as without mindfulness you wouldn’t be able to see when you are engaging in this fault. Over time this fault will lessen its impact on you as you constantly keep rejecting it and will gradually fade away from your makeup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I noticed is that when you remove one fault, that fault was caused by another fault, and then that fault was also caused by another fault you had and so you just have this chain of faults until you get and master the very basics. For me I was removing a lot of faults in my makeup until I got to the root causes which was having and cultivating right thought and thus rejecting negative, dark thoughts because once you master your thoughts nobody can help you as much. Another fault I had was my attitude towards things was that it would end in a disaster which wasn’t a good attitude to have so I’m slowly but surely learning to reject this attitude and cultivate a more positive attitude towards things. You also engage in right effort when seeking to remove a fault as it takes a fair amount of effort to be able to constantly reject a fault.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk a little bit about faults or flaws. Quite simply a fault or flaw is something that isn’t perfect or is hindering you in some way. An example of a fault could be self-sabotage, which in my opinion a lot of people have this flaw in some way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happiness Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/spiritual/happiness-part-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happiness Part 2" /><published>2021-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/spiritual/happiness-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/wellbeing/spiritual/happiness-part-2/">&lt;p&gt;Happiness part 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some thought provoking things about happiness that I thought others might enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External events do they contain happiness within it? Is it the travelling to the destination that is what makes us happy? Is it the enjoyment that makes us happy? If it did anyone who experienced that event would be happy, but it’s not so. Also does the happiness last. perhaps it lasts for a few days, but it isn’t true lasting happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Items do they contain happiness? Does the material it’s made from contain the emotion of happiness? Does the way it was made and constructed contain happiness? How long does happiness last when you buy an item? A few days? Therefore, to find happiness you can’t find it in items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness cannot come from things which are temporary. To find lasting happiness it comes from within yourself. Nobody can make you truly happy, no event, no amount of material possessions can make you truly happy. It comes from within yourself and from an appreciation that nothing temporary can make you happy. As the Buddha himself once put “People are like a hamster on a wheel chasing after happiness endlessly from temporary things”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become happy, you first need to really appreciate that nothing external will make you truly happy, no amount of money will make you happy, no amount of friends will make you happy, no amount of drugs or alcohol will make you happy. It comes from within yourself. Equally unhappiness is a choice. You don’t need to be unhappy, its only your reaction to external events that make you unhappy, for example you lose your job, is it the fact that you won’t have any money that makes you unhappy? Is it the fact you won’t see your work colleagues that is what makes you unhappy? Is it the fact that you think you won’t find another job that makes you unhappy? Point being is that there is a point where you make yourself unhappy as a result of something, not the event itself because the event itself doesn’t contain the emotion of unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To become happy its important also to be as positive as you can possibly be. Try to see the light in every bad situation and also don’t give way to unhappiness and misery, no matter how disastrous you think it might be. Reject thoughts of it’s a disaster and try to see the reality of the situation, it could just be a blessing in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, to sum up. Happiness and unhappiness isn’t contained in external things, there is always a point where you make yourself happy or unhappy at external things. True happiness comes from within and to be happy its important first and foremost to try to be as positive as you can be and also rejecting any emotions of unhappiness and misery or thoughts that it’s a complete disaster, which is something that I have fallen to a number of times but I’m doing my best now to here on out rejecting thoughts that it’s a complete disaster and trying to give way to happiness as best as I can.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Wellbeing" /><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Happiness part 2: Here are some thought provoking things about happiness that I thought others might enjoy. External events do they contain happiness within it? Is it the travelling to the destination that is what makes us happy? Is it the enjoyment that makes us happy? If it did anyone who experienced that event would be happy, but it’s not so. Also does the happiness last. perhaps it lasts for a few days, but it isn’t true lasting happiness. Items do they contain happiness? Does the material it’s made from contain the emotion of happiness? Does the way it was made and constructed contain happiness? How long does happiness last when you buy an item? A few days? Therefore, to find happiness you can’t find it in items. Happiness cannot come from things which are temporary. To find lasting happiness it comes from within yourself. Nobody can make you truly happy, no event, no amount of material possessions can make you truly happy. It comes from within yourself and from an appreciation that nothing temporary can make you happy. As the Buddha himself once put “People are like a hamster on a wheel chasing after happiness endlessly from temporary things”. To become happy, you first need to really appreciate that nothing external will make you truly happy, no amount of money will make you happy, no amount of friends will make you happy, no amount of drugs or alcohol will make you happy. It comes from within yourself. Equally unhappiness is a choice. You don’t need to be unhappy, its only your reaction to external events that make you unhappy, for example you lose your job, is it the fact that you won’t have any money that makes you unhappy? Is it the fact you won’t see your work colleagues that is what makes you unhappy? Is it the fact that you think you won’t find another job that makes you unhappy? Point being is that there is a point where you make yourself unhappy as a result of something, not the event itself because the event itself doesn’t contain the emotion of unhappiness. To become happy its important also to be as positive as you can possibly be. Try to see the light in every bad situation and also don’t give way to unhappiness and misery, no matter how disastrous you think it might be. Reject thoughts of it’s a disaster and try to see the reality of the situation, it could just be a blessing in disguise. So, to sum up. Happiness and unhappiness isn’t contained in external things, there is always a point where you make yourself happy or unhappy at external things. True happiness comes from within and to be happy its important first and foremost to try to be as positive as you can be and also rejecting any emotions of unhappiness and misery or thoughts that it’s a complete disaster, which is something that I have fallen to a number of times but I’m doing my best now to here on out rejecting thoughts that it’s a complete disaster and trying to give way to happiness as best as I can.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Thoughts and Happiness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/right-thoughs-and-happiness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Thoughts and Happiness" /><published>2021-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-07-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/right-thoughs-and-happiness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/right-thoughs-and-happiness/">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to make this short post about thoughts and the importance of them and the importance of not giving way to unhappiness in your life and pushing happiness as best as you can. For the past few months, I’ve been engaging in a lot of negative thought patterns about life in general. I realized that the reason I have such thoughts is because its my response to when things don’t go my way, I have these negative thoughts as a means of ‘protest’, which is extremely unhealthy. I’ve also felt so lost and one of the reasons why I think I’ve felt so lost is because I tried so hard to make myself unhappy and anytime, I would feel happy I would repress that feeling so that I could feel as unhappy and as miserable as possible. Which looking back I realized I was quite lost in doing this and if pressed to answer why I did it the closest thing I could come to is because I was angry and upset at the way I’ve been treated in life and so this was a means of protest against how I’ve been treated in life. Which is not very mature and has affected my vibration significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Buddha himself recognized the importance of thoughts saying “We are what we think. All that we are arises with our thoughts. With our thoughts we make the world”. It’s also one of the noble eightfold paths Right thought being the second part of the noble eightfold path which goes to show the significance that the Buddha put on having the right thoughts. I also like this quote “Your worst enemy can not harm you as much as your own thoughts, unguarded. But once mastered, no one can help you as much, not even your father or your mother.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it means to have right thought to me means that you reject thoughts that are in their nature negative and try to cultivate positive thoughts such as kindness to people, love for people etc. Personally, I would have a lot of thoughts which brought me unhappiness and misery. I engaged in these thoughts so much that I somewhat lost what it actually feels to be happy and when I’m ‘happy’ really, it’s just a feeling of satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for me I am going to begin rejecting negative thoughts as best as I can and also rejecting unhappiness as best as I can. I’m also going to try and be as positive as I can about things. I hope that in time with this practice I can begin to become a much happier and spiritually awake person, because being unhappy and miserable doesn’t benefit anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize I have a mountain to climb in terms of the negative, dark, dare I say evil thoughts that have been going through me and what I need to do to conquer such thoughts.  Also, the general feeling of unhappiness I’ve been pushing on to myself which has affected my vibration as have my thoughts. I feel it’s also made me weak minded or feeble in mind as I really can’t engage my mind as I used to as a result of all the unhappiness, I’ve been pushing onto myself. But as they say the journey of a thousand miles begins with one step and I like to think that this is a giant step in the correct direction to becoming an ‘ascended being’ which is something I aspire to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this has taught me whole affair I like to think has taught me a valuable lesson in the importance of not giving way to bad thoughts and also the importance of being happy and thereby rejecting unhappiness and misery, because it really has affected my motivation to do things in that because I have this general feeling of unhappiness I’m a lot less willing to do things because my view of the world has been affected negatively.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Light</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I wanted to make this short post about thoughts and the importance of them and the importance of not giving way to unhappiness in your life and pushing happiness as best as you can. For the past few months, I’ve been engaging in a lot of negative thought patterns about life in general. I realized that the reason I have such thoughts is because its my response to when things don’t go my way, I have these negative thoughts as a means of ‘protest’, which is extremely unhealthy. I’ve also felt so lost and one of the reasons why I think I’ve felt so lost is because I tried so hard to make myself unhappy and anytime, I would feel happy I would repress that feeling so that I could feel as unhappy and as miserable as possible. Which looking back I realized I was quite lost in doing this and if pressed to answer why I did it the closest thing I could come to is because I was angry and upset at the way I’ve been treated in life and so this was a means of protest against how I’ve been treated in life. Which is not very mature and has affected my vibration significantly. The Buddha himself recognized the importance of thoughts saying “We are what we think. All that we are arises with our thoughts. With our thoughts we make the world”. It’s also one of the noble eightfold paths Right thought being the second part of the noble eightfold path which goes to show the significance that the Buddha put on having the right thoughts. I also like this quote “Your worst enemy can not harm you as much as your own thoughts, unguarded. But once mastered, no one can help you as much, not even your father or your mother.” What it means to have right thought to me means that you reject thoughts that are in their nature negative and try to cultivate positive thoughts such as kindness to people, love for people etc. Personally, I would have a lot of thoughts which brought me unhappiness and misery. I engaged in these thoughts so much that I somewhat lost what it actually feels to be happy and when I’m ‘happy’ really, it’s just a feeling of satisfaction. So, for me I am going to begin rejecting negative thoughts as best as I can and also rejecting unhappiness as best as I can. I’m also going to try and be as positive as I can about things. I hope that in time with this practice I can begin to become a much happier and spiritually awake person, because being unhappy and miserable doesn’t benefit anyone. I realize I have a mountain to climb in terms of the negative, dark, dare I say evil thoughts that have been going through me and what I need to do to conquer such thoughts. Also, the general feeling of unhappiness I’ve been pushing on to myself which has affected my vibration as have my thoughts. I feel it’s also made me weak minded or feeble in mind as I really can’t engage my mind as I used to as a result of all the unhappiness, I’ve been pushing onto myself. But as they say the journey of a thousand miles begins with one step and I like to think that this is a giant step in the correct direction to becoming an ‘ascended being’ which is something I aspire to. But this has taught me whole affair I like to think has taught me a valuable lesson in the importance of not giving way to bad thoughts and also the importance of being happy and thereby rejecting unhappiness and misery, because it really has affected my motivation to do things in that because I have this general feeling of unhappiness I’m a lot less willing to do things because my view of the world has been affected negatively.</summary></entry></feed>