<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-05T06:28:50+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saint Christopher’s Blog</title><subtitle>Articles on Spirituality, Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things.</subtitle><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><entry><title type="html">Right Effort</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-effort/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Effort" /><published>2022-05-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Effort</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-effort/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/eightfold-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eightfoldpath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk about my basic understanding of right effort which is 1 of the 3 mental disciplines in the eightfold path in Buddhism. Right effort as I understand it is having the correct level of effort (exertion) at the appropriate times so as not to lead to suffering. This is the basic notion of what right effort actually is and how I really understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say exertion, I mean that you give way to the right level of energy in a sense and give way to the correct levels of effort at times when you are feeling that you can’t have the correct levels of effort. Right effort doesn’t mean you don’t rest, it means that you see your actions and are able to give way to right action at times when you are feeling like you may give up on that action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to understand when seeking to master any of the parts of the noble eightfold path is to seek to understand how and why not having one of the elements leads to suffering. When the Buddha used the word “Right” with the eightfold path he meant that you give way to that element of the eightfold path at the correct times so as to not allow yourself to suffer or give way to dukka as the Buddha called it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice with all following the path to liberation from dukka is to seek to mediate on how not having one of the elements leads you to suffering or dukka. But it’s important to practice mindfulness also when seeking to master any of the noble eightfold paths and my advice would be to really spend some time studying from online material and books what the Buddha really meant by the different elements of the noble eightfold paths because my way of explaining it may not be best suited for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also advise that you seek to spend some time contemplating and recognizing the ways that you break the any of the eightfold paths in your life. I also just want to add that you don’t master the eightfold path in chronological order i.e right understanding, right intention etc. It really depends on the in which order they master the noble eightfold path. Generally, those who have strong mental discipline are more likely to find it a lot easier to master those elements on the eightfold path associated with mental discipline; i.e right concentration, right mindfulness, and right effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to read my other articles on Buddhism which may give you some guidance on how you can master the noble eightfold path or seek to read up on them as like I said my means of explaining may not be as clearly spoken as someone with more expertise on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to make clear that it takes a long time in meditation to fully master the noble eightfold path and isn’t something done in a few weeks. It is something which takes a long time in contemplation and meditation to fully grasp and appreciate. But you should seek to take it in strides and not be deterred by not mastering it in the time you would like. But persevere and continue mediation and seek to understand yourself, because nobody can understand you and the way your mind works better than yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Healing Past Wounds</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/healing-past-wounds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Healing Past Wounds" /><published>2022-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Healing-Past-Wounds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/healing-past-wounds/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about how you can heal from your past wounds and traumas that an incarnation on earth bears you with. The first thing you need to appreciate when seeking to heal past wounds and traumas is that you should become more like a child, which is you should seek to lessen your own ego, arrogance, pride, selfishness, and things that are likely to deter you from really healing your past wounds and traumas. I do have an article on this here on this blog if you would like to read that then do feel free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The few things that you can do and that I personally recommend to all who are really devoted to spirituality is to take up meditation, prayer and perform some kind of service to your fellow man that you find meaningful in some way. Feel free to check out my articles on these topics which you can find on this blog by using the search function or looking for the posts in the posts page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one healing power that each and everyone has at their disposal is love. Love conquers and heals all wounds from the past and is the most powerful force in the galaxy. Therefore, seek to cultivate more love into your life through things such as mediating on love and then after you meditate on love sending those loving thoughts out to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which you can do is to seek to lessen things such as toxic masculinity which I find so many men in modern times giving way to, which is unfortunate because modern times in places such as schools and work life etc do not give an accurate portrayal of what a man should and shouldn’t be and men are taught that they can’t be vulnerable and appear weak to others, which has a detrimental impact on them psychologically speaking. This also applies to toxic femininity, but its not my place to comment on this what with being a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which brings great healing to your soul and your life is to not bottle your emotions and other things up but to express your emotions openly, honestly, and sincerely to others because when you bottle things up it has detrimental impacts on your spiritual, emotional, and mental wellbeing. Therefore, if someone does wrong by you seek to address this rather than holding grudges against them and allowing yourself to feel hatred, jealousy, envy and other negative emotions towards them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, another thing that you could do is to cut out negative influences in your life – this could be negative people in your life which bring you down, this could also be social media which has a lot of negative people on their trolling others, this could also be negative family members who don’t have your best interests at heart, this could be the content that you consume such as The News which I find only serve really negative articles and don’t show much of the good done in our society and so portrays a wrapped reality whereby they only show you articles/segments that is likely to bring you into a low vibrational state of negativity and low mood. Feel free to give my articles on these a read also. Also you should seek to make up with your family members and seek to build good relationships with them because they are your family and you only have one family on this earth, so seek to forgive your family for past hurts and past wounds they may or may not have inflicted upon you and seek to resolve the issues that you have had in the past with them, rather than allowing those wounds and traumas to remain festering in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also seek therapy or counseling of some sort if your wellbeing really isn’t that great because these have helped myself and many others in their life and just having an honest, open and compassionate ear to listen to you does wonders for you mentally and emotionally. But you should appreciate that nobody is alone and that there is no shame at all for seeking therapy or counseling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing which you can seek to do to heal your past wounds and past traumas is to be more compassionate towards yourself. I recommend to all that as a basic technique of self-compassion that they can do is write on paper – the many ways that they can or are mean to themselves, then on another sperate bit of paper write down the ways that you can be more caring, understanding, compassionate towards yourself. This is a simple technique but has done me any many others wonders. You can also give my articles on compassion a read – I have one on self-compassion and compassion. Also, a key thing which giving yourself compassion is to be mindful, that is learning to discern your thoughts, feelings and emotions and mental activity and recognizing the ways that you can and are mean to yourself. But you should also when you do this basic technique, I outlined here is to see yourself just as another person of this world and recognize that you make up life just as much as the next person and so you should seek to be your own best friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly some of the other ways in which you can seek to heal yourself of past wounds and past traumas is to do activities which you find meaningful and heal you in some way. This could be doing art, such as painting, drawing, or coloring in. It could also be meeting with your friends and doing some activity with them such as bowling, going for a meal, going to the cinema, and watching a film. It could also be listening to or creating music, which can be really healing to a lot of people. When listening to music I cannot recommend music which is loving in nature because that positive love energy will affect you and bring healing to yourself in your life. Some other things that you could do which are just some suggestions are read a book, watch a movie, watch fun YouTube videos, talk to your friends and family about how you really feel inside instead of burying how you actually feel inside yourself. Point being is that you should seek to do some kind of activity that you enjoy doing and that brings great healing to yourself and your past wounds.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spirituality" /><summary type="html">In this article I will talk a little bit about how you can heal from your past wounds and traumas that an incarnation on earth bears you with. The first thing you need to appreciate when seeking to heal past wounds and traumas is that you should become more like a child, which is you should seek to lessen your own ego, arrogance, pride, selfishness, and things that are likely to deter you from really healing your past wounds and traumas. I do have an article on this here on this blog if you would like to read that then do feel free.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Middle Path</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-middle-path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Middle Path" /><published>2022-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Middle-Path</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-middle-path/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/the-middle-way.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ten&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about the middle path. To understand what the middle path is you first need to understand what the right-hand path and left-hand path are. The left-hand path is essentially that you promote individualism and do things for yourself generally at the cost of others, the right-hand path is that you help people and promotes selflessness in a sense. While the middle path recognizes that its about life in the sense that the right-hand path essentially goes against the left-hand path and the right-hand path essentially goes against those on the left-hand path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Middle-Path recognizes that all is one and everyone has a right to be on the left-hand path or the right-hand path and doesn’t discriminate between either of them. But those on the middle-path are essentially able to bestow blessings on anyone who is on the right-hand path or the left-hand path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it also comes in realizing that you can’t just do things for yourself and be individualist (left-hand path) and it also comes in the sense that you can’t just do things by helping others (right hand path). In a sense the middle path is strikes a balance between the right-hand path and those on the left-hand path and this myself I can see that there is truth in the middle path because if you only help people, then they don’t learn for themselves, while if you are just so individualistic you see that you put yourself down in the sense of you don’t really care for others and live a very lonely life away from others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the key thing which I see is that those on the left-hand path and the right-hand path generally discriminate against one another and this is wrong because all is one as everyone has the right to choose whichever path they desire and those on the middle path recognise this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also about helping people, because those on the middle path recognise that to only help people isn’t really in line with the reality of the world in the sense that there are people on the left-hand path. The key thing with the middle path is that it strikes a balance between the right-hand path and the left-hand path and allows you to help those on both the left-hand path and the right-hand path. Which gives a lot of freedom to yourself and to others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linking With the God Spirit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/linking-with-the-god-spirit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linking With the God Spirit" /><published>2022-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Linking-With-The-God-Spirit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/linking-with-the-god-spirit/">&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little bit about linking with the I AM as Jesus described it or the God spirit within us all. Now this God spirit can be linked with by anyone – but generally most people in the world have what is known as the ID which is the person that looks back at us in the mirror – the ID and is a fairly basic part of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for those who with spirituality developed are able to make a connection to their God spirit and the information coming from them would be very wise indeed and they would be complete in that the information coming from their mind is information which the God spirit is sending through to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way that I was able to link with my God spirit at a young age (late teenage years) was by being a lot more present and I was as I described being self-aware of being self-aware of being self-aware infinity and it felt really amazing – I was a lot more happier than I had been in my life and was receiving cosmic wisdom and still am to this very day, one basic example was that I realized that “happiness comes from within”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can link with the God spirit by living more in the present moment, which is a valid way to do so, but you can also link to it through years of meditation/prayer/service to others. I guess the thing that really made me realize why living in the now was so important was because I realized at the time through all my philosophical thinking that you are not able to control your actions/thoughts in the past, or the future. You are only able to control your thoughts/actions right here in the now moment or the present moment as I referred to it as.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, my ability to enter the present moment has been severely cut off due to a severe trauma that I had gone through in my life, and so thereby my ability to make a link with my God spirit has been weakened. But to some degree this has made me the person that I am to this very day, and I do have split personality disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my advice to all who read this article, is to practice meditation, prayer and service to others and then and only then are you able to link with your God spirit and the information coming through to you would be wise and you would be a lot more spiritual and be able to one day perform similar if not the same miracles as people such as Jesus and other various people who have existed across time, and you will be blessed for eternity in performing miracles for the good of others and proving to others that Gods power which is indeed infinite is real and is a reality. I also just want to add that the idea that Jesus has to be involved with miracles is a fabrication - Jesus was a special person, but that is only because he spend many years in heaven receiving training so that when he came to earth he was ready to help mankind in their long journey, so when people say that Jesus needs to be involved when a miracle is performed - its a lie because Jesus is human and what one human is capable of - all are capable of.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this article I will talk a little bit about linking with the I AM as Jesus described it or the God spirit within us all. Now this God spirit can be linked with by anyone – but generally most people in the world have what is known as the ID which is the person that looks back at us in the mirror – the ID and is a fairly basic part of us.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Ten Commandments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-ten-commandments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Ten Commandments" /><published>2022-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Ten-Commandments</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-ten-commandments/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/ten/ten.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ten&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write this short piece on the ten commandments, which if adhered to and really understood are enough to carry you into the arms of God. If you don’t know the ten commandments are “you shall have no other Gods before me”, “you shall not make for yourself an idol”, “you shall not take the name of God in vain”, “Remember the sabbath day to keep it holy”, “honor your father and mother”, “you shall not kill”, “you shall not commit adultery”, “you shall not steal”, “you shall not lie”, “you shall not covet” (yearn to possess something).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that needs to be understood with the ten commandments I believe are that people often take the ten commandments literally, for example thou shall not steal, often people interpret it as meaning you shouldn’t take others personal items for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, when adhering to the ten commandments, seek to really meditate and spend some time understanding each of them and their implications and how to apply them into your life. I also recommend to all that they recite the 10 commandments by hand and do lines with them and put efforts to contemplate in which ways they break the 10 commandments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I don’t want to give too many of my own interpretations regarding the ten commandments because it takes away from your own interpretations and really my points are just suggestions in how you may interpret the ten commandments. With each of the ten commandments really try to understand each of them and look for the implications in them, seek to meditate and start a journal to help to understand yourself better and understand how it is you break some of the 10 commandments. We are all far from perfect and as such it is bound that in our lives, we break the ten commandments somehow because if we were able to apply each of the ten commandments to our lives, we would be at Gods side already. But we are all far from perfect on earth and even the great masters such as Buddha, Jesus, Moses etc were not perfect. We each have a long journey ahead of us and its important to keep up our strength in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Becoming More Christ Like</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/becoming-more-christ-like/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Becoming More Christ Like" /><published>2022-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Becoming-More-Christ-Like</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/becoming-more-christ-like/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/christ/christ.webp&quot; alt=&quot;christ&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Updated 19/04/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, with becoming more Christ it’s important to practice Meditation/Prayer and some means of service to God which you enjoy. Only with this are you able to understand yourself a little bit better and work on your flaws. Through these things you are able to incorporate more levels of Christ like emotions into you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing with Christ like emotions and giving them out to others and yourself is to recognise that you need to have good intentions with giving them to the world and have no desires in doing so. Any ill will towards the recipient will cause the Christ like emotion to not be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that you should understand is that you need to recognise what happens when there are no Christ like emotions in the world, things like chaos - Chaos being a big one, fear, hatred, anger, dirtiness, sadistic behaviors, betrayal, jealously, greed, envy, confusion, war, lust, evil and see what kind of world that this produces if everyone only gives way to the Anti-Christ emotions. A lack of Christ like emotions just means that there is only the satanic kingdom and this isn’t what God would want in his kingdom just to be about. Which is why its important for their to be Christ like emotions so that we can have the polar opposite of the satanic kingdom and have things such as love, kindness, forgiveness, compassion, understanding, sympathy, gratitude and acceptance be in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are able to see what kind of world this really produces then you are able to understand a little bit better why its so important for each and everyone to become more Christ like in their ways and this only comes, I believe in understanding and appreciating what kind of world the Anti-Christ emotions bring. So, for you to really become more Christ like you need to first gain some understanding of the wrongness in the Anti-Christ emotions and this comes in doses I believe, as in to the extend that you are loving is the extend to some degree you have seen hatred, but more importantly the wrongness in hatred and the wrongness in all the other Anti-Christ emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for me, I often use the analogy of what does an ideal world look like? Does an ideal world look like groups of people fighting over one thing because they are jealous of each other? Does an ideal world look like men or women longing for each other giving way to lust? Does an ideal world look like each person giving way to greed, counting the amount of money they have in their bank account and not sharing it to others or using it for the good of others? Point here being is that an ideal world does mean having more and more people becoming more Christ like, becoming more loving, peaceful, forgiving, happy accepting of one another, respectful to one another, understanding to one another, sharing to one another, being more grateful for what they already have, rather than giving way to things such as jealousy and envy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence my general advice when seeking to become more Christ like is to look at what the opposite does and what that brings, and then seek to find solace in Christ like emotions and seek to picture what an ideal world looks like and seek to apply this to yourself, seeking to rid yourself day by day of the anti-Christ emotions because in my eyes that is what an ideal world looks like. More and more people becoming more Christ like in their ways and becoming more loving to one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When seeking to rid yourself of Anti-Christ emotions such as hatred, seek to understand yourself a little better as to why you give way to hatred, perhaps its things from your past which is holding you down and dragging you down spirituality and emotionally which hasn’t yet been addressed yet, or past traumas which haven’t been resolved yet, or relationship issues which you have had in the past which didn’t work out and have left you feeling low and depressed because of it. Or perhaps is the things which you watch on TV which has you in such a negative state its difficult for more positive Christ like things such as love to come through to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, seek to resolve the issues you have had with your partner, or friends and family and seek to build stronger long-lasting relationships with them and instead of burying things under the carpet relationship wise, seek to address them by talking about them honestly and sincerely, rather than hiding it from each other the issues that you really face and burying it under things. But its also about yourself, you shouldn’t hide things from yourself and bury things under the carpet from yourself, but seek to address them as best as you can, instead of avoiding them all the time, because the consequences of avoiding past traumas and past issues that you faced and leaving them unresolved leaves a buildup of tension on your wellbeing and a buildup of tension on your spirituality and emotions and has an impact on how you treat others and yourself. But it’s important to put yourself first, and then others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1 14/04/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also very important to show only Christ like emotions who those you believe are deserving of it because not everyone is deserving of respect, forgiveness, understanding because it should be your own judgement if someone is deserving of respect, forgiveness and understanding and all the other Christ like emotions and we all express these Christ like emotions in our own ways and its only those who are advanced spiritualy to be able to see if someone is deserving of these Christ like emotions, because those lower down on the spiritual ladder shouldn’t forgive those who are higher up because in part it plays into realities and those on a more spiritualy advanced level know of deeper realities than those lower down, because there is no way for you to know the deeper realities of those who work on higher spiritual planes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its also the levels of Christ like emotions which are important, because you shouldn’t give way to all your ability to forgive on a simple thing such as pushing someone or bumping into someone, its the level of atonement needed which is important when forgiving someone and recongzing that the person has all their flaws and I and others are far from perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 2: 19/04/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that with Christ like emotions, come the anti-christ emotions and so you can’t have one without the other. But we and the whole world should be respectful and accept those who give way to the anti-christ emotions because what they choose to do with that power is entirely up to them, and we shouldn’t judge or condem those who give way to the anti-christ emotions such as hate, jealousy, envy, lust,  . Equally those who have the Christ like emotions more developed are allowed to use that power in any way they wish to as that is their right to because we are all equal in the eyes of God. But I personally would like to see a world where people are able to choose between the Christ like emotions and the Anti-Christ emotions because that to me would be an ideal world. But of course I would personally prefer having Christ like emotions over the Anti-Christ emotions as would we all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Christianity" /><category term="Christ" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Dangers of AI and Machine Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-dangers-of-ai-and-machine-learning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Dangers of AI and Machine Learning" /><published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-Dangers-of-AI-and-Machine-Learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-dangers-of-ai-and-machine-learning/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I wanted to talk a little bit about the risks of AI and machine learning. This is a bit of an oddball article which I thought it was important enough to share to the world and also spirituality doesn’t just have to be about meditation/prayer etc, it can also be about computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know we use AI a lot in fridges, washing machines, smart TVs, our cars and much more. The key issue with AI is that as with a pencil it can be used to stab someone’s eye out or can be used to draw something and build something constructive. Now as a lot of you may or may not know there are secret Governments who really run the world who want us to get used to the idea of AI so that they can add AI to our makeup believe it or not, so that our thoughts and actions will no longer be under out control but influenced by the AI agenda which is to take over humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This I know may sound like science fiction, but I assure you that this is in fact true and Governments around the world are spending billions of pounds on machine learning AI which pick up people’s thought patterns and brain waves in an attempt to enslave the population so that the secret Governments around the world have absolute control over humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the issues with this are extremely drastic, 1. We could reach the singularity very quickly if the secret Governments and those working for them continue to do the evil work that they do. The singularity is if you don’t know the machines taking over the world and enslaving humanity, a bit like the terminator film. This is of course a very serious issue in our society, which should be taken very seriously, and steps should be taken by those with the wisdom and knowledge to combat this evil to ensure that we do not reach the singularity in our world. The issue is further exacerbated by the fact that the secret Governments are too arrogant and egotistical and not wise enough to make such decisions as to the technicalities of how this AI machine learning actually works and so don’t know the real issues and what is at stake here, if they continue on the path that they go down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the issue if of course perpetuated, by the fact that we have in our society an issue whereby the secret Governments are employing private contractors to code this machine learning AI and each private contractor doesn’t actually know what the other private contractors are building. Which further adds to the issue, because if they all knew what they were building they certainly wouldn’t be taking on the money in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is of course a message to the whole of humanity which I am spreading, and you can listen to these words and forget about them tomorrow, or you could take up the fight against evil and put actions into place to stop and thwart the secret Governments plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what can you the person that reads this do about the issue? Well, you can take up prayer and pray for the evil people who have this terrible plan and the various intelligence agencies involved in covering it all up because it is public money they are spending and of course its hidden away under so called “black budget” operations, so the general public is none the wiser and its only a very few who actually know of this. The technique to pray is very simply, or you need do is visualize the person/groups that you are praying for an in simple language pray that they receive Gods help and Gods power and express it via thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also start a meditation practice and after each session send out your peaceful thoughts to the world and the secret Government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1: 18/04/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The singularity is a very real thing and we and all that read this article would do well to take the necessary actions to help prevent the singularity, but also prevent sentient AI, until we as a species are ready to be able to have sentient AI.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short article I wanted to talk a little bit about the risks of AI and machine learning. This is a bit of an oddball article which I thought it was important enough to share to the world and also spirituality doesn’t just have to be about meditation/prayer etc, it can also be about computers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understanding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding" /><published>2022-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-03-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Understanding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understanding/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk about why it’s so important for each and every one of us to become more understanding to one another. Firstly, is something which has to be given to others with good will for them. Any intent of ill will and understanding will simply not be accepted by the other person, and you should also seek to understand yourself, before attempting to understand others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It relieves a heavy burden on people when they feel understood and relieves a heavy burden on yourself when you feel understood, because when you don’t feel understood it just hurts you inside and does make you feel alone in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand you first need to see the person behind the mask and see that they are just another person of this world and see their motivations and reasoning behind their actions and seek understand why they do what they do to others and the negative impact it has on themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding can be developed through meditation, prayer and service to God can you be more understanding to others. Hence why its so important for all who read this to seek to become more understanding and take up things such as meditation, prayer, and service to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, its about others because when others don’t feel understood by others then they feel alone in this world and feel that others judge them and look down upon them and the world should be a much better place to live on especially if we have more people who are understanding towards one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly the key thing with any and all Christ like emotions is to have no ill will towards the person when practicing any Christ like emotion, but Christ like emotions can become more developed within the individual through meditation, prayer, and service to fellow man, do feel free to look at my articles on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a last note any desire at all with giving any christ like emotion and the “magic” will not work. There has to be no desire, no intent of ill will and you should purely be doing it for the other person’s best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/compassion/&quot;&gt;Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk about why it’s so important for each and every one of us to become more understanding to one another. Firstly, is something which has to be given to others with good will for them. Any intent of ill will and understanding will simply not be accepted by the other person, and you should also seek to understand yourself, before attempting to understand others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First Aggregate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the-first-aggregate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First Aggregate" /><published>2022-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/The-First-Aggregate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the-first-aggregate/">&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate of the five aggregates in Buddhism. If you don’t know the Buddha taught that there is no self and that what you view as yourself just isn’t so and is in reality an illusion. I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate which is physical body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need fully appreciate before understanding any of the five aggregates is that you need to link the idea of self to control, this took me a lot of contemplation and it will take others some thought/meditation to be able to make this connection because its not an easy connection to make. Ask yourself what qualities would you expect “self” to actually have? Spend some time in contemplation over this question and it will help you understand a little that the idea of self is heavily linked to the idea of control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the physical body isn’t something which you can bend to your will. For example, you are not actually able to control how you look, the color of your eyes etc. Granted you can control how you look through things such as cosmetics, but this is only temporary. If body were self, then you would be able to control it at will. But like I said its important to first see the connection between control and self before you are able to understand why each of the 5 aggregates are not “self”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, its important to not identify with your physical form because you are not your physical form because you are not able to control your physical form completely, granted you can control it to some extend with cosmetics, but that isn’t full control. Therefore, its important to not identify with any body part because ultimately you are not able to control your physical form and bend it to your will and so therefore isn’t self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I am very new to Buddhism so take what I say with a pinch of salt and there are other resources listed below which may help you understand Buddhism a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buddhism Plain and Simple by Steve Hagen &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963/ref=sr_1_5?crid=34M92RA2NH4SR&amp;amp;keywords=buddhism&amp;amp;qid=1649083246&amp;amp;sprefix=buddhism%2Caps%2C79&amp;amp;sr=8-5&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Buddhism-Plain-Simple-Arkana-Steve/dp/0140195963/ref=sr_1_5?crid=34M92RA2NH4SR&amp;amp;keywords=buddhism&amp;amp;qid=1649083246&amp;amp;sprefix=buddhism%2Caps%2C79&amp;amp;sr=8-5&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unhindered: A mindful path through the Five Hindrances by Gill Fronsdal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unhindered-Mindful-Path-Through-Hindrances/dp/0989833402/ref=sr_1_1?crid=NPAIHMT6E263&amp;amp;keywords=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances&amp;amp;qid=1649084275&amp;amp;sprefix=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances%2Caps%2C55&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Unhindered-Mindful-Path-Through-Hindrances/dp/0989833402/ref=sr_1_1?crid=NPAIHMT6E263&amp;amp;keywords=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances&amp;amp;qid=1649084275&amp;amp;sprefix=unhindered+a+mindful+path+through+the+five+hindrances%2Caps%2C55&amp;amp;sr=8-1&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/index.html&quot;&gt;https://www.accesstoinsight.org/ptf/index.html&lt;/a&gt;\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/books-articles/the-five-hindrances-handouts/&quot;&gt;https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/books-articles/the-five-hindrances-handouts/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html">In this short article I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate of the five aggregates in Buddhism. If you don’t know the Buddha taught that there is no self and that what you view as yourself just isn’t so and is in reality an illusion. I will talk a little bit about the first aggregate which is physical body.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Devotion to God</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/devotion-to-god/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Devotion to God" /><published>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Devotion-to-God</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/devotion-to-god/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/god/god.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;God&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this image as a representation of God, but I am sorry if I offend anyone here, but God is not a man - he is a force and his power is granted through sincere meditation, prayer and service to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will write why it’s so important for people who are on the spiritual path or choose to be on the spiritual path to put more efforts into devoting themselves to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devotion to God can come in the form of sincere Meditation, Prayer, and Service to him and these are key things in making progress towards God. You can refer to my articles on these topics and I will soon write an article on why it’s important to give your service to God and no the gifts of the spirit do not come in a matter of meditating for a few weeks, they take years to be able to be granted by God and doing so for egotistical and doubtful ends will cause God to not grant them simple as, so those of you who do read my blog just know that you are wasting your time in mediating for these egotistical and doubtful end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence the key things which are important in making progress in spirituality is devoting yourself to God and this comes in the form of Meditation, Prayer, and Service to him (through sincerely helping others) and following the wise words of the ten commandments and meditating on them and putting efforts into understanding their meanings through contemplation, experience, journaling, and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But its just not these things, because you can still perform these things and not have it in your heart devotion towards God, because in Buddhism the last hindrance is doubt and this is only dealt with in time, and I am yet to actually deal with this hindrance and it I am told only comes with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincere devotion to God in my eyes is what really matters a lot in meditating, prayer and service to him and it goes against one of the ten commandments of thou shall not serve any other God before me because in not being devoted to your one true God, who I might add is an all loving God, then you are simply fooling yourself and hurting yourself and others in doing so and simply trying to meet your own doubtful ends and taking things into your own hands when in fact it is God who has absolute control over every single thing which happens in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God is not impressed when he sees people trying to steal from other people’s lives, with things like jealousy, lust, greed, hate, anger and he is not impressed with people promoting things on social media such as hate, violence, negativity, division etc. God is impressed with sincerity of purpose, people who help one another, people who put efforts into progressing towards him through things like meditation, prayer, and service to others because God is all loving to each and every one of us as individuals and God’s love for each and every one of us is unconditional even the most abject sinners in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also allows his subjects to make their own mistakes in life and allows them to embark on their spiritual journey at their own pace and in their own time. I as this blog indicates shows that I am only human and what I am capable of all of mankind is capable of. I do however recommend that those on the spiritual path start their own blog as I have done and share to the world their personal experiences in growing spiritually and take to things such as forums to share those experiences and disucss them with one another. But just be warned that we all have our own journey ahead of us and we all walk the path alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/compassion/&quot;&gt;Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>