<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-15T04:53:14+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chris’ Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality and other various stuff</subtitle><author><name>Chris</name></author><entry><title type="html">Giving to Others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Giving-To-Others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Giving to Others" /><published>2022-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Giving-To-Others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Giving-To-Others/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk a little bit about why giving to others is so important in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should first start by recognizing that its not all about you and allowing things like pride and arrogance (ego) have an impact on your ability to give. I myself have allowed pride to affect me a lot and its cost me a lot in life as it has others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has the ability to give and its important that others give because as the Master Jesus once said you ‘reap what you sow’, therefore what you put out to the world you will also get in return, but only if you believe that God will return what you give and you shouldn’t worry too much about when you God will return what you give because so long as you have enough faifth that God will give what you put out – he will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic example is when you pray for others with the intent of helping them, then God will see that and will return that and help you in some way. But it all comes down to right intention (working for the good of others) in Buddhism which is something I have struggled with a lot in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also a really good video on Youtube that said that giving to others will make you a lot happier and a lot more cheerful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=78nsxRxbf4w&quot;&gt;Ted Talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is information which I got from The Great White Brotherhood’s book “Linking with the 4th dimension” Chapter 27 The Giving Plane, you can find a link to the book here &lt;a href=&quot;https://thegreatwhitebrotherhood.org/books/&quot;&gt;Linking with the 4th Dimension&lt;/a&gt; and I have found it to be true in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk a little bit about why giving to others is so important in life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking Things To Extremes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Taking-Things-To-Extremes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking Things To Extremes" /><published>2022-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Taking-Things-To-Extremes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Taking-Things-To-Extremes/">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I take things to extremes and it has caused me and others alot of suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the reason I do that is because I desire something and don’t yet fully appreciate that all desire and wants will inveitably lead to suffering and it’s as the saying goes you can lead a horse to water, but you cannot make it drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a means of repressing my trauma that I’ve gone through in my life and I will make a post describing my trauma soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wrongly have this belief that I need to please others and be a good person all the time, which is just wrong because I don’t need to be a good person if I chose not to be and this doesn’t make me s bad person, because what makes a good person? It’s relative what makes a good person and should be your own interpretation of what it means to be a good person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you shouldn’t take it in extremes because it can be too much of a good thing which is a form of evil, it’s also about desire because you desire to be a good person and this leads to suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also plays into how I can be arrogant and ignorant which isn’t good because it’s just difficult for me to listen to others because I think that all people sometimes just want me to suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is of course to strive for balance in things and never take things too personally and never take things to extremes because you can commit sins in taking things to extremes i.e thou shall not kill.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Sometimes I take things to extremes and it has caused me and others alot of suffering.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Too Much Of A Good Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Too-Much-Of-A-Good-Thing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Too Much Of A Good Thing" /><published>2022-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Too-Much-Of-A-Good-Thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Too-Much-Of-A-Good-Thing/">&lt;p&gt;Recently I realized that I was praying and asking for too much and it was being given to me, but it was a bit off because it was too much of a good thing and there is such thing as praying for too many good things because the prayers that I sent out were essentially competing with one another when they should have been working with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution I feel to not having too much of a good thing is only take that which you can handle. Don’t feel you are letting others down in rejecting their good things they sent to you because you can have too much of a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also about slowing down because with me being in dark for so so long and suddenly being in the light I realized that like I was just having so many good things as a means of compensating for being in dark for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My general advice would be to realize when you are having too much of a good thing and so slow down when you feel your having too much of a good thing and also to not be greedy in the good things that you have, but express gratitude for all the good things that are coming your way and the good things that you already have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I’ve put a lot of posts on my blog,, but the reason I put these all in a massive batch like this is due to me being in a mental hospital and having a lot lot more time to better understand myself and thereby make considerable progress towards God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it’s about taking your time and don’t feel you need to rush because of others, because when you rush the whole world rushes because you make up the world. So take your time and remember that the journey is a marathon not a sprint so enjoy each and every moment of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Recently I realized that I was praying and asking for too much and it was being given to me, but it was a bit off because it was too much of a good thing and there is such thing as praying for too many good things because the prayers that I sent out were essentially competing with one another when they should have been working with each other.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When You Can’t Do Good In Your Own Home, Do Good Elsewhere</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/When-You-Cant-Do-Good-Do-Good-Elsewhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When You Can’t Do Good In Your Own Home, Do Good Elsewhere" /><published>2022-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/When-You-Cant-Do-Good-Do-Good-Elsewhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/When-You-Cant-Do-Good-Do-Good-Elsewhere/">&lt;p&gt;In this short post I will talk a little about how when you can’t do good because of some reason like a disagreement with yourself or a flaw you have that you should do good elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I’ve suffered a lot and that suffering has really made me into the person that I am today, but I put efforts to see the good in what that suffering has brought to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that I sometimes can’t do good in the world because I can be selfish sometimes, but in such times I realized that I compensate that by doing good some place else, which isn’t a bad thing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that this is a really good prinicipal to live by that if you can’t do good in your own home, seek to do good elsewhere in the world because you are not the only person in the world and it’s important that you stay true to yourself and your own beliefs in things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I just wanted to add that you should have good intentions when following this simple principal. By good intentions I mean serving God, helping others etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good that you can seek to do is endless, offer your service as a volunteer in someway, donate some money to charity, give your money to a friend in need, phone a friend you haven’t spoken to in some time. Point being is that when you can’t do good in your own home for some reason, seek to do good elsewhere in the world because it will be the world a much better place for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">In this short post I will talk a little about how when you can’t do good because of some reason like a disagreement with yourself or a flaw you have that you should do good elsewhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Self-Importance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Self-Importance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-Importance" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Self-Importance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Self-Importance/">&lt;p&gt;I realize that I can be incredibly foolish, silly and ignorant sometimes My own sense of self-importance has let me down considerably and to think that I know better than others and God is foolish to think that way because God is in complete control of absolutely everything. People shouldn’t think they are better than others because of their perceived spiritual blessings they have received as a result of their faifth in God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve let myself and the world down considerably due to thinking that I’m more important than others which is wrong because everyone and everything is equal even God himself in the eyes of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I foolishly chose self-importance over others and I was too arrogant and blinded by ignorance and prideful to see what it was I was doing to myself. All those times I hurt and deceived people and lied to their faces when they said “are you ok”? And not being as honest as I should be to them and saying “yeam i’m fine” when I just wasn’t. But also not being true to myself and my own beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my own self-importance got in the way significantly in terms of making real tangeable progress towards God and I have been a complete and utter fool towards myself and let others down which isn’t what I stand for. But I have let others down and more importantly I’ve let myself down and the life of progress towards God which I would like to lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will continue to pray and meditate as best as I can each day to God in the hopes that I can change for the benefit of the human species and more importantly for the benefit of myself. Its wrong what I’ve done to myself and zeaoulsly evil to have done all the things that I’ve done to myself and to think I can get away with it is stupid and foolish and to think that others can’t see my own actions is fooling myself. Praying that I reduce my pride (which I have done now) and reduce my own sense of importance. But I feel the pace of spirtuality is far too fast and should slow down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own sense of self-importance isn’t who I want to be anymore in terms of how I identify with being very important. I should respect myself and others more to recognize that I have been given life and so should put efforts into doing God’s work and not the work of the devil/evil. I’m sorry towards myself for having done the things that I have done to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess its also about how I was in darkness for so long and now I’m begginging to see the light considerably more I wandered why I was in darkness for so so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The work of God should be in creating beautfy, lifting people’s spirits especially people who are down, expressing christ like emotions to others and more importantly yourself, striving to be happy, striving to be joyful, giving to others especially because the power of giving is true in the sense that what you give to others you get in return in the sense that you reap what you sow, but you should give with the belief that God will return to you what you give to others, but you shouldn’t to so for yourself – you should do so with the intent of serving God. Practing self-love more and being more positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I gave way to so much self-importance is due to me not recognizeing the oneness of all life and realizing that I’m not the only person in the world and its also incredibly selfish to not believe in the word of God.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I realize that I can be incredibly foolish, silly and ignorant sometimes My own sense of self-importance has let me down considerably and to think that I know better than others and God is foolish to think that way because God is in complete control of absolutely everything. People shouldn’t think they are better than others because of their perceived spiritual blessings they have received as a result of their faifth in God.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sexual Frustration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Sexual-Frustration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sexual Frustration" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Sexual-Frustration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Sexual-Frustration/">&lt;p&gt;This one is a touchy subject for me because I have experienced considerable sexual frustration and has mainfested itself in very peculiar ways, and much of which i’m not very proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the reason that I haven’t spoken to many woman in my life is due to my relationship with myself mainly, but also due to lack of courage and self-confidence and also that like I feel it will bring me more suffering because I for some reason feel its better that you are ‘stronger’ if you are alone and have no partner in your life because then you won’t suffer the loss of them. Which I now see is quite foolish of me because love between two people should be a wonderful thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like with the pandemic some people are feeling incredibly sexually frustrated because of how lockdowns are making it harder and harder to meet and greet new people and things like bars and restaurants are becoming more descriminated against because you need to show vaccine certrficates and tack and trace depending on where you are in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I feel like if you meet a certain partner who you can relate to and enjoy then you should bond and have a realtionship, rather than being seperated because you will feel a lot happier together and won’t feel as llost as most people who are single feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also feel a deep sense of lacking within yourself as you feel your heart mourne for someone else and company with another. Sometimes you can express your sexual frustation through dream sleep, but its important to not beat yourself up too much about having sex with people through dreams sleep because its a natural and healthy thing for people to do, but just seek to not break one of the ten commandments thu shall not commit adultery because its wrong to have sex with family members even if it is through dream sleep because its unfair and unhealthy because it is harmful to family life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technique to meet your new partner which I read from The Great White Brotherhood’s book the stairway to freedom (and a link to their website and free books are in my about page) is to sit quietely and tell God that you are ready to receive your perfect partner and thank him for sneidng you your perfect partner. It may take a number of weeks/months/years even to mee this person, but God’s angels will ensure that you two meet each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to add that you need to be willing to change with regard to meeting your perfet partner because a lot of people have flaws which will undermine the wonderful and beautfiul relationship that they wish to have together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also not beat yourself too much in the ways that you express your sexual frustation, there is no shame in how you express it. But seek to channel your sexual frustation into desire to change that sexual frustation and find a woman/man in your life, seek to goto places like parks, to bars, to nightclubs, to restaruatns, to socieities, weddings etc and just seek to put yourself out there is my general advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly I just wanted to add that I really lack affection a lot and have suffered tremendously from a lack of affection and that is mainly due to feeling the need to be ‘strong’ and is due to toxic masculinity which I feel our society doesn’t address enough because I still suffer from a lack of affection towards others and struggle to receive a lack of affection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">This one is a touchy subject for me because I have experienced considerable sexual frustration and has mainfested itself in very peculiar ways, and much of which i’m not very proud of.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Suffering and the Four Noble Truths</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/buddhism/Suffering-and-the-four-noble-truths/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Suffering and the Four Noble Truths" /><published>2022-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/buddhism/Suffering-and-the-four-noble-truths</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/buddhism/Suffering-and-the-four-noble-truths/">&lt;p&gt;In this artcile I will talk about suffering. Which for me is a subject mattar that I have struggled with a lot, in terms of how to deal with suffering and how to resolve suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will first say that I have suffered tremendously as a result of demonic possession, I have experienced considerable mental suffering as a result of being possessed when I was 17 because the demonic personality is still there, but it has somewhat lessened a lot due to not being tempted to use its personality which is still there. I will also just add that I was exercised with help from The Great White Brotherhood, which you can find a link in the about page of my blog to their website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also foolishly believed that the means out of suffering was to give way to evil, but it defintelety wasn’t because I just suffered a great deal more and it has cost me more than anyone could ever know. I don’t think that anyone should resolve their problems by giving way to evil or give way to evil for that mattar – feel free to check out my article on evil that I wrote which may help you with your own evil &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovehumanity.gitlab.io/spiritual/Evil/&quot;&gt;https://lovehumanity.gitlab.io/spiritual/Evil/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furhtermore I also realized that I make myself suffer in the present moment through like mental suffering, emotional suffering, making others suffer in the hopes of preventing further suffering, which is just not the means out of suffering. I guess it was mainly due to a total lack of courage in terms of worrying too much for the future and thinking that other people have more power over me. But you should know that you have complete autotomy over yourself whether you belive it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Buddhism the means out of suffering is to follow the four noble truths and to meditate on them as it is wisdom from a very wise master the Buddha. Practicing the eightfold path is indeed the path out of suffering, but for me I struggle with understanding why that is and should really meditate and spend more time contemplating why it is the noble eightfold path is the means out of suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first noble truth is that life is inheriently suffering, in life we suffer through things like physical suffering, mental suffering, emotional suffering and it is an inevitability that everyone will suffer in some way in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second noble truth is that change is a constant thing in life, and there is no stopping change suffering has a cause and we try to manipulate sitations, people and try to get our way. But the important thing to remember about the second noble truth is that disastification arises within us. Its you that are disasstified with the current position of the fact that you are going to suffer and that no mattar what you do life is inherientely suffering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third noble truth which is perhaps the hardest one to grasp is that the cause of suffering is desire and attachment to things or disasstification as the Buddha describes it, because for me I realize that I have a lot of wants and also somewhat realize that not everyone can have what they want in life which is a universal truth and I guess I just need to be more accepting of this fact. Then I realize that I take it out on myself somewhat when I can’t have what I want because of my own arrognace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth noble truth is the promise that you can end your suffering and the suffering of others by teaching the noble four truths through ahering to the noble eightfold path. Which is right understanding, right intentions, right speech, right action, right livelihood, right effort, right concentration, right mindfulness. I won’t go into too much detail but this is the means out of suffering. Which I am still putting efforts to recognize.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html">In this artcile I will talk about suffering. Which for me is a subject mattar that I have struggled with a lot, in terms of how to deal with suffering and how to resolve suffering.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Compassion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Compassion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Compassion" /><published>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Compassion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Compassion/">&lt;p&gt;I thought I would write this article on compassion. This will be similar to my article I wrote on self-compassion but it applies to giving others compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that you need to accept is that you need to have good intent when attempting to provide someone with compassion. If there isn’t good intent, then comapssion will not be as effective. As with any other chirst like emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also just wanted to add what is meant by suffering and really it’s just disasstisffaction in how your experience is right now and can take the form as it has with mine in terms of mental suffering, emotional suffering, you can suffer also from your false beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You first need to connect with the person and put efforts to understand and appreciate the suffering that they are going through. But see them on a deeper levela nd also respect them. I have struggled with giving compassion to others and still struggle because I feel I can be very ignorant and selfish sometimes because of my own self-importance, which I’ve struggled with a lot in my life and plan on posting my article on self-importance that I wrote very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that the key thing with compassion is emptahy also with the person and putting efforts to see the suffering they are going through. But seeing the person behind the suffering and accepting them as they are and having a deep level of compassion for what they’ve been throguh and what they are going through right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for me I’ve also realized that I just suffer for the sake of suffering and this is due to my delusion of how to end suffering I should suffer in the present to avoid further suffering in the future and I realized that following the noble four truths of Buddhism has helped me out of suffering and the eightfold path is the path out of suffering, which I recommend all who read this to take more seriously because it will end your suffering that you go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that I somewhat identified with my suffering and allowed it to control me, and was foolishly somewhat proud of my suffering as I felt that suffering gives you strength, but not to ghte degree I have suffered and made others suffer as a result of my own suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you shouldn’t just give compassion out blindly all the time because they may expect that compassion all the time and then they won’t learn from their mistakes of not understanding the nature of suffering and how the noble eightfold path is indeed the way out of suffering. Which is why I feel it’s important to teach to others why they suffer and it’s due to desire and attacthment to things, because when you attach and desire and no longer have those things then you suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desire can be anything, you desire for the future to be a certain way, you desire for others to behave a certain way, you desire for the world to be a certain way, but the solution is to have no desire, because all suffering is caused by desire. It’s also about attachment because people attach themselves to items, luxury clothing, the past, the future, people, situations – I.e they want a situation to go a certain way etc and so when these things are no longer with you – you suffer. The solution is to have no desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of trying to change the world, seek to change yourself before you change others because you are not yet perfect and have a long journey ahead of you as do we all. But just take the journey in strides and don’t try to rush it because of others, enjoy every moment of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">I thought I would write this article on compassion. This will be similar to my article I wrote on self-compassion but it applies to giving others compassion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Patronizing Others</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Patronizing-Others/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Patronizing Others" /><published>2022-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Patronizing-Others</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Patronizing-Others/">&lt;p&gt;Patronizing Others&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that one thing that has caused me suffering and many others suffering is patronization which is whereby you think that you are better than others and so in very subtle ways have behaviors which condescend them in someway. But its also about thinking that you can get the better of others in someway and you think that you are more intelligent than others which is quite arrogant because we are all equal and to patronize another isn’t in line with reality because you are not better or lesser than anyone or anything else. Everyone and everything is equal in the eyes of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To patronize is also to kill another’s confidence in themselves which goes against one of the ten commandments thou shall not kill. But I realized that I also patronize myself in a way which isn’t good for me to do that because we and everything is equal, but I just struggle to accept that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also find its important to call out patronization if and when someone does it to you because it affects your self-esteem when someone patronizes you in someway and you just accept it and think that the other person is better than you in someway because when you patronize another its puts them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should learn to have the courage to stand up to people whom patronize you in someway and learn to not judge those who patronize you in someway because we are all on our separate journeys. Just as a short note you shouldn’t think that you are more spiritually advanced than someone else because they still patronize. We are all far from perfect. You should be accepting of all life as all is one and to harm another is to harm yourself. Which took me a lot longer than it should have to realize that harming yourself isn’t good because its yourself that you are doing it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to understand people a lot more and be forgiving to those who patronize you and forgiving to those who judge you. But learn to be your own person and not allow yourself to patronize another and not allow yourself to be patronized by others, but stand up for yourself and what you believe. Not what others want you to believe. Become more mindful of your intentions and recognize more when you patronize others. Its in very subtle ways that people patronize you and you patronize others. But learn to be more understanding and forgiving of when people do this kind of thing because they don’t recognize the oneness of all of life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Patronizing Others</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rushing Spirituality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Rushing-Spirituality/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rushing Spirituality" /><published>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Rushing-Spirituality</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spiritual/Rushing-Spirituality/">&lt;p&gt;Rushing Spirituality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that one thing that is holding me back a lot now that I am starting to see some results with my spiritual advances I feel the need to rush spirituality for more gains because I have been in the dark for so long now and given way to a lot of negative thoughts and been quite depressed and just felt so lost. But now that I am starting to see some results with spirituality I am willing to learn lot about myself a lot more because I can see that there are indeed significant gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one thing that I learned during my rush for spirituality is that it can damage yourself significantly if you are not careful, and so my advice would be to practice spirituality in your own time and at your own pace. Some people progress faster than others, while others progress slowly. But you shouldn’t judge how fast/slow someone progresses in their spirituality because its not a contest or a race, I guess one of the reasons I feel the need to rush in spirituality is because of fear of suffering and I realize that this is in part due to me not realizing the nature of suffering and that following the Buddha’s noble eightfold path is indeed the way out of suffering, because the Buddha is one of the great masters of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also the fact that I suffer from mental health difficulties is in part one of the reasons why I rush, because I worry too much about how others judge me, in part because I don’t accept that I have mental health difficulties because I’m too egotistical, arrogant, prideful to accept that I do have mental health difficulties. I feel like ego does get in the way sometimes, but I don’t often recognize it. Ego also affects my ability to trust other people, because I can be antisocial when I choose to be which does make me quite lonely and I feel a lot of people suffer from this similar thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I realize also is it should be about the journey that is of importance. I know its a little cliche, but that is true. But I don’t quite see that, or accept it as truth hence why I’ve been rushing spirituality out of fear of losing out on something (suffering).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, go at your own pace in spirituality and only practice spirituality if you do want to develop. You don’t have to practice spirituality if you don’t choose to and also its important to take breaks with spirituality when you feel the need to. But the gains that can be made are big.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html">Rushing Spirituality</summary></entry></feed>