<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-19T07:42:02+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Saint Christopher’s Blog</title><subtitle>Place where I talk about my journey of spirtuality. Here you will find articles on Buddhism, Wellbeing, Health and various other things. Here I also talk about Buddhism and a little bit about Psychology.</subtitle><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><entry><title type="html">Devotion to God</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/devotion-to-god/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Devotion to God" /><published>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Devotion-to-God</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/devotion-to-god/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/god/god.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;God&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this image as a representation of God, but I am sorry if I offend anyone here, but God is not a man - he is a force and his power is granted through sincere meditation, prayer and service to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will write why it’s so important for people who are on the spiritual path or choose to be on the spiritual path to put more efforts into devoting themselves to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devotion to God can come in the form of sincere Meditation, Prayer, and Service to him and these are key things in making progress towards God. You can refer to my articles on these topics and I will soon write an article on why it’s important to give your service to God and no the gifts of the spirit do not come in a matter of meditating for a few weeks, they take years to be able to be granted by God and doing so for egotistical and doubtful ends will cause God to not grant them simple as, so those of you who do read my blog just know that you are wasting your time in mediating for these egotistical and doubtful end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence the key things which are important in making progress in spirituality is devoting yourself to God and this comes in the form of Meditation, Prayer, and Service to him (through sincerely helping others) and following the wise words of the ten commandments and meditating on them and putting efforts into understanding their meanings through contemplation, experience, journaling, and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But its just not these things, because you can still perform these things and not have it in your heart devotion towards God, because in Buddhism the last hindrance is doubt and this is only dealt with in time, and I am yet to actually deal with this hindrance and it I am told only comes with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincere devotion to God in my eyes is what really matters a lot in meditating, prayer and service to him and it goes against one of the ten commandments of thou shall not serve any other God before me because in not being devoted to your one true God, who I might add is an all loving God, then you are simply fooling yourself and hurting yourself and others in doing so and simply trying to meet your own doubtful ends and taking things into your own hands when in fact it is God who has absolute control over every single thing which happens in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God is not impressed when he sees people trying to steal from other people’s lives, with things like jealousy, lust, greed, hate, anger and he is not impressed with people promoting things on social media such as hate, violence, negativity, division etc. God is impressed with sincerity of purpose, people who help one another, people who put efforts into progressing towards him through things like meditation, prayer, and service to others because God is all loving to each and every one of us as individuals and God’s love for each and every one of us is unconditional even the most abject sinners in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God also allows his subjects to make their own mistakes in life and allows them to embark on their spiritual journey at their own pace and in their own time. I as this blog indicates shows that I am only human and what I am capable of all of mankind is capable of. I do however recommend that those on the spiritual path start their own blog as I have done and share to the world their personal experiences in growing spiritually and take to things such as forums to share those experiences and disucss them with one another. But just be warned that we all have our own journey ahead of us and we all walk the path alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/compassion/&quot;&gt;Compassion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Misconceptions on Buddhism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/misconceptions-on-buddhism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Misconceptions on Buddhism" /><published>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Misconceptions-on-Buddhism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/misconceptions-on-buddhism/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/monk/monk.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;monk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will talk a little bit about perceptions in Buddhism and how this has deterred people from actually following Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general opinion or first thing that comes to mind when people hear of Buddhism is monks, bald heads, sexual abstinence, life of monastery etc. This then in my eyes deters people from actually looking more into Buddhism and following Buddhism. Which I think is a real shame because it is very wise teachings from a master of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I think it’s ironic because the Buddha himself recognized the truth that you shouldn’t put labels on information, because it deters from the information itself. So, you should look at the information held on a topic, rather than giving way to your preconceived notions of what the information is. When applied to Buddhism or the perceptions of it, they actually deter people from looking more into the teachings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I think that we in society need to change our perceptions of Buddhism because Buddhism isn’t just about being a monk, shaving your hair off, sexual abstinence etc. Its so much more than that and it’s a real shame that so many people dismiss it out of hand due to their misconceptions of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buddhism is believe it or not a promise that you can end your own suffering right here on earth and for me this has proven true because the four noble truths if understood correctly will indeed end your own suffering and you will reach nirvana if you follow the noble four truths correctly which is a state of bliss, enlightenment, unborn – its difficult for me to put into words what it actually really is, but I recommend that you read more on what nirvana really is to understand it better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Buddhism" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When You See Wrong do Two Goods Elsewhere</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/when-you-see-wrong-do-two-goods-elsewhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When You See Wrong do Two Goods Elsewhere" /><published>2022-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/When-You-See-Wrong-Do-Two-Goods-Elsewhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/when-you-see-wrong-do-two-goods-elsewhere/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/charity/charity.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Charity&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write about why it’s so important for people to do two goods in the world or elsewhere for that matter when they see bad or wrongdoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world would be a much brighter place and we the public would be much happier the people in charge did follow this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It really about bringing God’s kingdom upon earth because earth should be a place which is God’s kingdom and not the kingdom of chaos, destruction, corruption, liars, manipulators, thieves, hateful, hurtful people because that’s not what God’s kingdom should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God’s kingdom should be a place of love, compassion, kindness, peace, order, beauty, joy, forgiveness, generosity, righteousness, holiness, gratitude and people who are faithful servants to him. This I think is a really good principal to follow in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of seeing wrongdoing may be when someone lies to you, when someone deceives you, when someone hurts you, when someone makes you think you are confused when you are not. You shouldn’t take revenge on these people because they do not know where they go, you should follow Jesus’s teachings of turning the other cheek when it comes to people that do wrong onto you and seek to follow this basic principle that I have laid out here in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples of good that you can do in the world is donating to charities, giving to others (and you can refer to my article on this topic), serving God through your job, helping others in some way through things like Forums etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this principal shouldn’t be taken to an extreme, but just taken in balance and go by what you feel is right while being true to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/when-someone-does-wrong-by-you/&quot;&gt;When Someone Does Wrong By You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-forgiveness/&quot;&gt;Self Forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/virtue-signalling/&quot;&gt;Virtue Signaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Pray for your Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="God" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop Watching Porn</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stop-watching-porn/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop Watching Porn" /><published>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Stop-Watching-Porn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stop-watching-porn/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/porn/porn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Porn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little about Porn. Now Porn is a topic which many people in our society don’t like to discuss, but hide, like its something that should be hidden to the general public, when generally a lot of people watch it and consume it on daily basis and I think it should be brought to the forefront because its extremely wrong the kinds of porn that the industry promotes and the effect that this has on young people to this day and the effect that it has had on people’s lives, especially young people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The porn industry needs a major shift because the kinds of things that it promotes just isn’t righteous, things such as adultery which destroy families and ruin family life just isn’t right and the fact that mainstream porn industries promote this is very sinful in my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the effect it had on young people including myself will last people a lifetime and has had a major impact on society in terms of people’s mental health, wellbeing and spiritual development and development as people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It promotes these sinful scenarios and incest porn such as “step moms”, “step sisters”, “daughter swaps”, “step dads”, “step brothers” who have sex with each other and it effects people psychologically, mentally and emotionally and effects society as a whole. Of course, most of them are not actually real “step moms”, “step sisters”, “step dads” and “step brothers”, but it promotes to young people this kind of thing, which I think is a grievous sin towards God and his kingdom and something needs to change in the porn industry as a whole and in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It promotes sin in terms of making young people lustful towards “porn actresses”, making them believe that things like adultery are normal in our society and of course they almost certainly are not. I guess because young people grow up in this environment where they watch these sinful acts which are promoted by the porn industry, and it encourages them to believe that this is completely acceptable and normal things like adultery and these really unusual and weird scenarios which just don’t happen in the real world with actual loving and caring couples who have lived together for decades who servants of God are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the solution is to make people recognize, especially young people and the porn industry itself the wrongdoings that they do and the effect that it has in our society, especially to young people and young adults such as myself who has watched such sinful acts and videos for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I think that the solution to any issue in society is to first raise awareness to the general public and the people actually effected by it especially on why its so wrong and evil. The porn industry as a whole needs major reform and laws and regulations need to be put in place which stop the promotion of such sinful acts such as adultery and the young people that consume this kinds of content need to stop watching this content, but of course this is very difficult to do when its so heavily pushed this kind of content onto young people, therefore only until Governments start to act in accordance with God and start to actually take action to help young people across the globe stop watching these kinds of sinful content online is when we can start to see a shift in the mental health and wellbeing of young people in our society and instead promote normal and happy loving and caring families in our society, because what the porn industry as a whole promotes is extremely wrong and sinful and goes against the ten commandments, thou shall not lie (lying about them being “step moms”), thou shall not kill (“killing family life, killing happily married couples, killing what could have been happily married, loving caring couples), thou shall not steal (“stealing what could have been loving and caring couples), thou shall not serve any other God before me (“Serving dubious masters who don’t have societies best interests), thou shall honor your father and mother (promoting discontent with mother and father, through incest porn) thou shall not commit adultery (incest porn), Thou shall not make idols (promoting through masturbation worship to these sinful people in the industry as a whole), thou shall not covet (promoting lust to people). So, in total 8 of the 10 commandments are broken and it’s a grievous sin to break that many of the ten commandment and goes very much against God and his wishes for humanity. Hence why it’s important that young people are brought awareness to this issue and why it’s important that adults who should know better than young people do more about this, because in my eyes its an wrong the - whole industry in porn and the fact that Governments around the world are actually complacent in this, and only until we as individuals start to take to thing such as meditation, prayer and service to God can things begin to change in society as a whole and the porn industry can begin to change as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1: 17/03/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly I just wanted to add I’m not telling you to stop watching porn regardless of the title and the tone of the article, its just I wanted to encourage people to listen to my advice and spend more time considering exactly what they are watching and how it is very sinful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-forgiveness/&quot;&gt;Self Forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Pray for your Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forgiveness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/forgiveness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forgiveness" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Forgiveness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/forgiveness/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/2020-12-17-Self-Forgiveness/yellow-flower.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;think&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will be talking about forgiveness and forgiving someone that does wrong by you. First and foremost, forgiveness is a process and forgiveness brings a lot of atonement to your soul and helps to raise you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let me just say that you shouldn’t keep forgiving someone when they keep constantly sinning against you and these kinds of people do not deserve forgiveness because they still believe in their hearts it’s the right thing to do and don’t show any level of respect for you and if you forgive them when they keep sinning against you then it shows that you don’t respect yourself. Therefore, forgiveness can sometimes begin by choosing not to forgive those who still believe in their hearts that sinning against you and God is the correct thing to do. There is a lot of power that forgiveness can bring to people and your enemies for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why you should forgive your enemies or strive to is because they don’t know which way they go, they are being lead astray, forgiveness also comes from recognizing that your enemies and sometimes your friends even don’t really know the deeper realities and the difficulties that you have faced in your life. Only God knows the absolute realities into all and so its important to show forgiveness to people whom you know better than when they sin because we are all equal and when you forgive another for their sin, you are able to be a true servant of God because the world should be filled with people who are more forgiving, loving, kind and generous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, forgiveness should be a show of strength because it takes some courage when someone has sinned a great deal in their life to be able to show that person forgiveness in what they do because you should recognize that we are all equal and even the most abject sinner in the world and the people who are truly evil in the world you are also capable of. Equally the great masters of the world such as Buddha, Jesus, Muhammad you believe it or not are capable of the same acts of those great masters. Hence why its important to be forgiving to those who sin when you realize that they sin because as Jesus once said, “Father forgive them for they do not know what they do”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to forgive your greatest enemy and seek to understand why it is that they commit the sins that they commit and just recognize that they make up part of life as do you and seek to realize that the most evil people and evil groups in the world do and the great sins that they commit you also are capable of committing because we are all equal. Equally what Jesus was capable of with the various miracles that he did perform and is performing to this very day you are also capable of doing, because don’t believe for one second that Jesus doesn’t care for earth and is in heaven and is helping mankind on earth and sending his love to us each day. Its within you and only you are able to change yourself and become the best version of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop Using Social Media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stop-using-social-media/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop Using Social Media" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Stop-Using-Social-Media</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stop-using-social-media/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/social/social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Social media&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will be talking about why you should limit the time that you spend on social media platforms. Now in general most people need to admit to themselves that social media doesn’t really bring much benefit to them in their lives. Social media companies have designed algorithms which have been optimized to make the general public stay on social media for as long as possible to maximize their revenue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media in general also promotes a lot of negativity to the world and you have a lot of people doing terrible things on social media such as scamming, extortion, grooming, trolling, promoting hate, promoting racism, promoting gambling and all sorts of really negative things which contribute nothing but harm to our society and to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media also has a major impact on people’s mental health and makes people suffer because on Instagram and Snapchat when you always see your friends doing activities with others you feel lacking inside because you yourself are at home watching them enjoying life, so it promotes things like jealousy, hatred and negativity and doesn’t really promote any Christ like things such as peace, love and happiness, which is a shame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the general public should limit the time they spend on social media platforms and ideally seek to remove it all together because it doesn’t help humanity and people’s own mental health which I think should be taken a lot more seriously in our society because social media in general actually promote mental illness by way of their algorithms which doesn’t benefit anyone long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, social media companies don’t have humanities best interests at heart because they censor certain opinions and ideas which hinder democracy and Governments around the world are complacent in that and its only until we as individuals start to stop using social media or at the very least limit the time in which we spend on these platforms because like I said it promotes things such as jealously and hurts our mental health. We should take to things such as meditation, prayer and service to God because it will lessen the power that evil has in the world and the evil that these social media companies bring to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, social media companies affect societies mental health, hurt our democracy, and do a lot of harm to the world and its only until we as individuals stop giving way to the temptation to constantly look at our phones every 5 minutes to look at Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, YouTube etc that we can begin to lessen the impact of the harm that these social media companies bring to the world. We as individuals should and need to take to things like meditation, prayer, and genuine service to God because it will bring a lot of benefit to the world and will further the power of God on earth. But if you feel that this is too much for you, then at the very least limit the time that you spend on social media, which will help your own mental health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 1: 17/03/22&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to just add that, I am not telling you or forcing you to stop using social media regardless of the title. Its just I believe that our society needs to consider what they consume on a daily basis because its wrong in my eyes to spend all day on social media mindlessly consuming content. So really its moreso about the content in which you consume which is of importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/prayer/&quot;&gt;Prayer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/giving-to-others/&quot;&gt;Giving To Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/being-authentic-and-true-to-yourself/&quot;&gt;Being Authentic and True to Yourself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/finding-your-ideal-partner/&quot;&gt;Finding your Ideal Partner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/self-forgiveness/&quot;&gt;Self Forgiveness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/virtue-signalling/&quot;&gt;Virtue Signaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/pray-for-your-enemies/&quot;&gt;Pray for your Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/practice-spirtuality-in-secret/&quot;&gt;Practice Spirituality in Secret&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop Watching the News</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/stop-watching-the-news/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop Watching the News" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Stop-Watching-the-News</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/stop-watching-the-news/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/news/news.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;News&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news is something which I think only brainwashes the general public and is propaganda. Try finding an old news article and you will be hard find to find an article from three months ago on their own website and this really is how the news thrives by constantly filling the general public with absolute nonsense in what’s really happening in the world right now, because how reliable really are a bunch of overpaid journalists who don’t really care for the general public and who brainwash the public with false doctrines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my view we the people should take a stand in the content that we consume and consume only content which is beneficial for us which certainly isn’t the news which promotes these corrupt and backstabbing leaders we have in power who certainly do not know better than the general public and who don’t really care for each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content which I deem credible and worthy of consumption are independent sources from people with little financial interest who follow God and Christ. The news stations that we have in the world are certainly not following God and certainly not following Christ. Content that is reliable and credible books and articles/research papers on your field or independent blogs from genuine down to earth kinds of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news are corrupt organizations who lead the public astray and brainwash the general public into fear and fear then controls them. Of course, the news follows a formula of control as do the world leaders the formula is Problem, reaction, solution. They create a problem to sell us things which hinder out development as individuals for their own selfish reasons, which is an abomination to the concept of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We the people have put up for long enough with this brainwashing, and only until we as individuals begin to stop watching the news and start taking to things like prayer (praying for our leaders especially) and meditation and service to God will we be able to put a stop to this absolute madness that the news television promotes, and our leaders promote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, we the people need to understand that watching the news only bring our own downfall and the downfall of the world because the news doesn’t have our best interests at heart and they don’t portray the world as clearly as they should and we get filtered news and filtered by people who don’t care for us or our wellbeing, but only care about serving their masters who have their own doubtful ends. Therefore, avoiding the news is in my view everyone’s best interests because bad news sells, and it just promotes negativity which reduces the power of God in the world which is the power of love. It also affects your own mental health and we the people should be doing more to stop the news organizations and politicians from getting away with their crimes against the general public.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Right Concentration</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/right-concentration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Right Concentration" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Right-Concentration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/right-concentration/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/Buddhism/eightfold-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eightfoldpath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this short article I will be talking about Right Concentration. Which is one element of the eightfold path and one which I think if mastered will be very beneficial to all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part in understanding right concentration or any element of the eightfold path is to understand why this makes us suffer. You first need to understand why not having Right Concentration at the right times and at the appropriate settings leads to suffering. To me Right means the correct level of concentration at the right times and when appropriate. But the key thing with all the elements of the eightfold path is to realize and appreciate why not having them leads to suffering, which I think is key in understanding and following Buddhism and the philosophy behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right concentration is heavily linked to right mindfulness because with right mindfulness you are able to appreciate as and when you are not concentrating on the task at hand and when you drift off so to speak. But like I said you need to understand why not having any one of the elements of the eightfold path actually leads to suffering, before you are able to fully appreciate why it is that not having that element actually leads to suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, seek to meditate on why not having an element of the eightfold path leads you to suffering and spend some time in contemplation why it is that not having right concentration actually leads one to suffering, because it will help you and others immensely when you are able to focus on the task at hand and help you to reduce the suffering that you have. Seek to journal (a means of contemplation) why it is that not having right concentration leads to suffering, I also have an article on this blog why its important that people take up jouranling as a means of spiritual devotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related Articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/meditation/&quot;&gt;Meditation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-mindfulness/&quot;&gt;Right Mindfulness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-intention/&quot;&gt;Right Intention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/right-speech/&quot;&gt;Right Speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/sloth-and-torpor/&quot;&gt;Sloth and Torpor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-first-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The First Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-second-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The Second Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/the-third-noble-truth/&quot;&gt;The Third Noble Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/journaling/&quot;&gt;Journaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Buddhism" /><category term="Right Concentration" /><category term="Noble EightFoldPath" /><category term="Noble Four Truths" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Veganism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/veganism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Veganism" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Veganism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/veganism/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/vegan/vegan.webp&quot; alt=&quot;vegan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I encourage all those on the spiritual path to become vegetarian/vegan and see it as an act of obedience towards God. The reason why you should consider diet as important is because what you put inside your body has an effect on your wellbeing. When you eat only junk food and takeaways then it causes upset in your stomach and you become unhealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also just say that I have been vegetarian since mid 2018 and have been a vegan since 2020 March so I have good experience with being both and generally I would recommend being a vegetarian before going into veganism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But vegetarianism and veganism is showing respect for life because you show respect for the animals that are being slaughtered before their time to die and against their own wishes. It also goes against thou shall not kill which is one of the ten commandments because you kill the animals by eating them and you are the reason that they died before their time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I agree that plants are also living, but plants have less sentience than an animal, so in a sense it’s the lesser of two evils that you eat plants than eat animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the DNA of an animal is very similar to that of humans and so it can be considered a form of cannibalism to eat animals because they are so similar to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also goes against thou shall not steal because animals should be free to live their lives as they chose in peace and harmony, instead we have a situation in the world where animals are bred in captivity, with no amount of love or affection and then they are slaughtered for the general public to enjoy as a meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you shouldn’t if you yourself vegetarian/vegan look down upon those who eat meat, but accept that they still believe in their hearts that it’s the right thing to do and so accept these people as you should all life and not condemn them or judge them but show respect for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the digestive tract of carnivores is short and so the food can be digested quickly, whilst the digestive tract for humans is long and so humans were never meant to be carnivorous, and meat contains toxins which actually harm the body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, humanity will do well to become vegetarian/vegan because it will reduce the suffering that these poor vulnerable, defenceless creatures of God have had to put up with for so long. But you should only become vegetarian/vegan if you yourself believe in your heart that it is the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="Vegan" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Others Think of You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/what-others-think-of-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Others Think of You" /><published>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/What-Others-Think-of-You</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/what-others-think-of-you/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/blogs/think/think.png&quot; alt=&quot;think&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article I will talk a little about what other people think of you. This is something which I have struggled with a lot in my life and something I am sure that other people have struggled with a lot of their life. What other people think of you is always something subject to change and not everyone will have the same opinion on you, especially on places like social media where I have advertised this blog and where toxic people and behaviors thrive (generally I tend to ignore these people but try to see where they are coming from and leave them to their toxic behaviors because their behaviors don’t achieve anything and only cause upset to themsevles and the rest of the world through their negativity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now not following the crowd so to speak is something which so many people don’t do and it’s a real shame because people should be true to themselves and not just do things because of others, in the sense that their actions shouldn’t be defined by the opinions, judgements and beliefs of others or their perceived opinions, judgements and beliefs. Granted everyone should live by some sort of consensus, but in a sense, this takes away from people’s ability to truly be themselves, because you are just following the crowd and the crowd could and has been in the past very wrong in their own ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, you should respect people’s own opinions and negative feedback, or opinions should be seen as feedback because in society you should present in a way appropriate for the situation and for the time and place. Which is important because you should respect others and this in of itself is a form of respect. So conformity to society is important, but its choosing when to be yourself and when not to be yourself that is important. But its also about respect for yourself and respect for others, because respect for yourself and respect for others should be equal and so you shouldn’t try to make others conform to your perceptions, beliefs or opinions in one single day because it takes for others to accept your different opinions, ideas, perceptions and beliefs, because in short when you are so different from the crowd it just doesn’t achieve anything and can make things worse for yourself in expressing your so different ideas, beliefs and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what I’m really trying to say here is that you should choose wisely as and when to fight your battles and when to be true to yourself and when to express opinions, ideas and beliefs which are far out there so to speak because you shouldn’t undermine what other people think, but respect what others think and currently believe even if you know what they currently think and believe to be wrong and not based on reality. This is something which I have struggled with because to see so many people give way to deluded ways of thinking and deluded beliefs in things just hurts me a little inside because they are under illusion and it’s a real shame to see much of our society under an illusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence why it’s so important for humanity to be true to themselves at the right time and in the right circumstance because consideration should be taken into how the general public may react/respond/what they may think of you personally when you express beliefs, opinions, ideas, perceptions which are not in the general consensus because as I have found out to my own detriment you can’t show spirituality to the world when they are not ready for it especially the general public, but during times when people give me stick for my ads I run I just try to understand that they are still in an illusion so to speak and just are not ready for the light and so I seek to understand that it threatens their confirmed reality which they are subject to and then I seek to forgive them for they no not what harm it does to themselves (in terms of hindering their own growth and spiritual development) and forgive them for the fact that they have harmed others development in encouraging people to think like them and then forgive them for the offense that they may have caused me or intended to cause me had I not been what others may describe as an enlightened being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess what this article is really about is that you can’t please everyone and you should pick and choose as and when it is appropriate to be yourself because you may or may not harm people in being the true you in the sense that it threatens others conformed beliefs and perceptions on things that they have so long held and so only brings harm to them and harm to yourself for the backlash that they give way to by denying the validity of you and that is certainly not what I stand for. I stand for love, peace, order and harmony between mankind and life in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the key think for most people because generally I tend to find that most will conform their behaviors, perceptions, beliefs and ideas on what others do is the courage to be yourself and the courage to be disliked, while choosing your battles so to speak on when the right time and when the wrong time to be yourself is, because being yourself at the wrong time can and does have a detrimental impact on the world and being yourself at the right times should have a long lasting and positive impact on you and the rest of the world. Granted how are you supposed to know when the right and wrong times are to be yourself, but I guess you should go off on others feedback is really the key thing and you can only base this on your own judgements in things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I do believe that being true to yourself is very important and being true should mean having your own beliefs, ideas, perceptions, and thoughts on topics and not just having these because of the crowd so to speak. Equally you should be mindful of the feedback that you receive when being true to yourself and when not being true to yourself but seek to work for the benefit of mankind and the benefit of yourself – but have these two things be of equal importance to you in your life. You should respect people’s opinions and beliefs even if you know them to be wrong because nobody on earth is perfect, but really pick your battles as and when to be true to yourself but work for the betterment of others in your choice of when to be true to yourself and when not to be true to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: This article was inspired by a user on Reddit by the name of /u/VentusTrash who spoke ill of my ad on Reddit, but please show him kindness and love for what he said because he inspired me to write this short article which I know will help others along their journey through life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Saint Christopher's Blog</name></author><category term="Spiritual" /><category term="true to yourself" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>